[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen everybody
I'm shame today we're looking at part
one of our story called the man who
would be king and the vocabulary words
are associate associate Craig we'll have
dinner with some business associates on
Friday Warren Warren Cindy's mother
warned her not to get too close to the
hot stove assistance assistance I could
really use your assistance on this
project you got it thank you recognized
recognized it's been so long since we've
seen each other that I didn't recognize
you at first really good girl that long
suffer suffer fans of the sports team
suffered yet another painful loss so
we're talking about a really interesting
story called the man who would be king
okay so we've got some characters we
need to know about okay who are the
carrots okay so we have a reporter
that's right a newspaper reporter I
don't know his name and we've got
somebody named a peachy can I hang on a
ham curry cheek Carnahan okay and Daniel
Dravot dravite that's right
okay so peachy we'll calm peachy peachy
sees a reporter on a train and he needs
to get a message to his buddy
right Dravid yeah and then next we see
them with the reporter telling them this
story what are they going to do what's
their plan they have an upcoming plan
they want to go to puff feresten
Afghanistan do what to be kings they
want to rule over the locals and that
just sounds absurd that's crazy and I
think that the reporter thinks these
guys are just going to get themselves
killed
that's right they're gonna get very very
big trouble right yeah that's not a very
good plan exactly but he helps them he
like gives them a map in the books and
information right so two years past two
years pass and peachy right mm-hmm
comes he ends up on the doorstep of the
reporter Larry
getting a bag and the reporter didn't
even recognize because he looks so awful
she was in an awful State right and I
guess he said they had a really hard
time when there were in Afghanistan and
they had to eat their own camel whole
and their new rules that's right well I
guess they really went through a lot
okay let's find out about these crazy
fellows in today's article I enjoy
actually the man who would be king on a
train in India a newspaper reporter
meets another passenger by the name of
peachy Carnahan peachy asks the reporter
to relay a message to his associate
Daniel Dhruv Oh today's lesson is called
the man who would be king part 1 hello
everyone my name is Jeff and I'm Mike so
the man who would be king isn't this
what we would call a prince a young man
is the son of a king his father is a
king or a queen
a person who one day will mom or will
become okay she was is a prince okay
alright so there we go that's the story
thanks for joining us everyone in and
see ya no no no it's not that simple you
actually have two days so let's start
reading right now the man who would be
king on a train in India a newspaper
reporter meets another passenger by the
name of peachy Carnahan which by the way
is an awesome name peachy Carnahan
peachy Carnahan is a pretty pretty cool
name the peachy keen a it's a peachy
named peach she's kind of an old slang
old way a slang way of saying
something's great or good I'm feeling
peachy or peachy keen peachy keen so
peachy Carnahan is this character's name
an unusual but very cool interesting
name let's find out what's going on on
this train journey in India it says
peachy asks the reporter to relay a
message
to his associate Daniel Trevo pass pass
along this message for me that's right
to relay something is just to pass it
from one person to another to get it to
its ultimate destination in this case
the ultimate destination the end of this
message will be with this associate
Daniel Dhruv Oh what is an associate it
could be a lot of different things it's
someone you know someone you're familiar
with someone you might work with someone
you might spend your time with we might
use a words like colleague or co-worker
to talk about an associate maybe someone
who's in a club or so the member of some
society along with you could be an
associate - you wouldn't really use it
for a good friend or something like that
but you know someone you know and you
interact with in more of a sort of
professional kind of way official or an
informal way exactly not on the sort of
a friend level for example Craig will
have dinner with some business
associates on Friday yeah we could just
say some colleagues that would be the
same that they'll be doing some business
they're not going out to dinner to have
fun with one another like friends would
anyways folks with that it is time for
us to take a break but don't go away
when we come back we'll have more of
this story hopefully we'll have more
peachy carnahan - hello Jamie
Santiago the culture should encourage
people in the salty Josua the man who
would be king Yahoo and Aaron man
kushikatsu the into the Idaho Churchill
um impartial teacher
doodlee mention coach also peachy corn
hand
not to mention coaching teacher
Bandaranaike educate had a hope and
Daniel drew volt Kalamazoo do da Shaw
Petri con gente means how cool how your
trio Tom and Rosita
peachy you know she said how's the PE
ACH hamantaschen why young Petri was a
peachy keen
Seco a junkie why she knew whom how the
her Banda Hunnam taken content associate
associate Abajo Pantone Shakur Horan
Napo John dance
relay relay Tasha tone CPR should run
that Rhonda my gosh you cannot show the
nega-chin she'd say John moody shall try
now
Daniel drivel Nepean now Adrian the
ultimate to get solution on three hold
three Chandra Tasha Pinto ult I am a te
ultimate debacle and Jo the man who
would be king
despite his feeling that peachy is a bit
of a shady character
the reporter does as he is asked a few
days later both peachy and Revo turn up
at the reporters office with details of
their upcoming plan they were going to
kaffir Stan Afghanistan to become kings
and rule over the locals the reporter
warns them about the dangers but their
minds were made up they asked for his
assistance and he believing they will be
killed on this adventure gives them a
map and books about the area
okay let's continue reading from our
story will have more peachy kar nan
right now get this despite his feeling
that peachy is a bit of a shady
character
the reporter does as he is asked oh yeah
I'll take your message and I'll pass it
on for you but here we hear we learned
that peachy is a bit of a shady
character or seemed that way yeah hello
if someone is Shady let's say you're
saying that you don't quite trust them
they seem suspicious to you yeah they
might have some kind of secret plan or
they might be lying to you a little bit
if they come across as being shady but
even though peachy seems Shady this
reporter decides to relay the message as
he was asked so then we read a few days
later both peachy and Dravo turn up at
the reporters office with details of
their upcoming plan interesting so the
reporter thought as long as he passed on
the message that would be the end of it
for him but no because later these two
associates peachy and drove oh they turn
up they show up they come to the
reporters office in a surprising way in
an unexpected way with details of their
upcoming plan they have a plan it's
coming up and here the details here are
all the facts and information about the
plan so what's the plan they were going
to kathira Stan Afghanistan to become
kings and rule over the locals they were
there living there to become king
they're gonna go to this place in
Afghanistan okay wild place off the map
at this point in time and they're gonna
show up and become the kings there
they're going to Lord and rule over the
people who live there the locals this is
kind of a shady plan yeah sounds weird
anyways the reporter warns them about
the dangers of their trip but their
minds were made up yeah we're going and
we're going to become kings this is
awesome by the way here it says that the
reporter
warns them ie the reporter says hey be
careful ok watch your step
something scary maybe or dangerous or
risky awaits you so be careful yes when
you say things like this to someone else
you are warning them for example Cindy's
mother warned her not to get too close
to the hot stove ok so be careful the
stove is hot don't touch the stove or be
careful if you go to that foreign
country and be try to become a king
the local people won't like it that's a
good thing to be warned about who are
you to be our King you just showed up on
a truck you're right arrived on a train
and I hear the king that's not gonna
work but it seems pretty weird but
anyways peachy and drove oh they seem to
know that their plan won't work without
a bit of help so we read they ask for
his assistance and he this is the
reporter and he believing they will be
killed on this adventure gives them a
map and books about the area ok so they
came to him this reporter for assistance
assistance is a noun and as I mentioned
earlier they came to the reporter for
help help and assistance are basically
the same thing if you're asking someone
for assistance you're asking someone for
help you need them to sort of add their
efforts to yours in order to succeed in
doing something if you ask someone for
assistance on the street you might be
lost and you need someone to give you
help to show you the right way in this
case they needed help they needed
information and that came from the
reporter in a map and a book we're
interesting let's look at our example
sentence for assistance I could really
use your assistance on this project and
yes if you put in the word help in that
sentence it would be just fine as well
we'll take a quick break and then with
your assistance we'll be back to finish
off our article Gong Gong cha cha cha
cha nega-chin KO peachy corn Han Xin
Jie's upon our invasion she say no it is
a tree it's a greenhouse young you're
then cool yeah cuz she has showed salt
had a yellow light so Hama when Joanna
she owns
shady shady Jesse on Khalid Abu Kokoda a
bit of a shady character jpoa yo it
incursion Nigella should allow a young
girl suspicious tickets it happens o su
SP IC IOUs suspicious KJ machine could
either she either Hawaii de how cool she
says it heat up she can hold on a young
girl and you should Petri corn hands
high Oh Daniel gyro page I haven't see
what routine that teases a bank-owned
shouldn't met hamantash Anya tree are
for Hanukkah Joshua couple races have
teacher Chinna Belcher Moana TomTom
biron man she should teacher to Gotham
and ticket evaluation she coaches around
are indeed shot in traditional commander
your teachers here to receive George
okay Hammond petrified who held
even Shangguan the shoe amazing iconic
bands Warren Warren shootin Zootopia
should seek out he/she warn somebody
about something be assured she got even
more emotional assistance assistance
Takashi Japan Mancha Picasso means
assistant studies teacher girl help
tada Tara kampuchan turns up coming up
coming
Taj agencies online lenders young
fashion de I all know enjoy on our
period turned up there's been hashed
association Geoghan show up is shank on
silicone gel the man who would be king
two years pass and a crippled man shows
up at the reporters doorstep with a bag
it is none other than peachy Carnahan
whom the reporter almost didn't
recognize at first for he was in an
awful State
seemingly driven mad peachy tells the
reporter that he and Revo suffered great
hardships on their journey took a fierce
tan and were even forced to eat their
own camels and mules along the way when
they finally arrived they used their
guns to help a group of locals win a
civil war
okay let's get back into the story so
two people are gonna go to Afghanistan
and become kings of the locals there
that's the plas sounds like a really
strange plan and risky - anyways two
years passed and our story and the
crippled man shows up at the reporters
doorstep with a bag so there's a man
he's crippled probably can't walk
properly anymore or looks like he's hurt
in some way so he can't function like a
normal person this person shows up and
they've got a bag well who is this
person
peachie karna the exactly let's read on
it says it is none other than peachy
carnahan whom the reporter almost didn't
recognize at first for he was in an
awful state so it's a big surprise
peachy karna hands back two years later
but the reporter almost couldn't tell
that it was him because peachy was in an
awful state he looked terrible his hair
was dirty and matted as clothes were
ripped he's crippled he's crippled it
looks like he was twenty years older
than he was even though it was just two
years ago so the reporter could barely
recognize him amazing what has happened
- peachy karna must have a story to tell
anyways here yes to recognize something
is to identify that thing when you look
at something and you can tell what it is
you have recognized it so let's say you
see a friend a familiar face you can
recognize that face immediately you know
who they are for example it's been so
long since we've seen each other that I
didn't recognize you at first yeah now
that I've got a good view of you okay I
can know I know who you are but before
you look different I couldn't recognize
you all right so let's hear peachy's
story and hopefully that will explain
where he's been for two years and why he
looks so terrible right now we read
seemingly driven mad peach he tells the
reporter that he and Dravo suffered
great hardships on their journey to
ephyra Stan and were even forced to eat
their own camels and mules along the way
wow this sounds like a really difficult
long and dangerous journey something
like they've suffered they definitely
suffered seemingly driven mad this kind
of basically means it seems like if you
ask the reporter he might guess that
peachy has gone mad he's been raised E
maybe that's not the case maybe he's
just really tired and needs to relax or
maybe he really has had some mental
illness but he seems kind of crazy right
now and he told him about the great
hardships the terrible difficulties and
terrible things that happened as they
suffered through this long journey to
suffer this verb means to undergo some
kind of terrible experience alright so
maybe you've suffered from a lot of pain
in your teeth well you should go and see
a dentist if you suffer from poverty in
your life well you've grown up or you
live in a situation where you don't have
enough money having pain all the time
not having money having troubles in your
life with your relationships these kinds
of things if they go on for a long time
we can really use this word suffer it's
sort of a terrible experience that goes
on and on and on for example fans of the
sports team suffered yet another painful
loss the team was the champions five
years ago these days they can't even get
one win against the the weakest team so
the fans suffer
anyways peachy karna hand and mr. drove
oh there they got where they were going
and it wasn't easy but they got there
but get this when they finally arrived
when they got there they used their guns
to help a group of locals win a civil
war they they're already suffering and
now they've got to participate in a war
a civil war wow what a story alright
folks with that today's story is now in
the books but don't worry another part
of our story is coming up soon how I'm a
tingling down into the hole you're
aiming by
ten hundred thousand the pentateuch in
the treatment in a tidy migrant England
Petrie corn hand it has a teaser had
children butcher like you had a drunk on
Canyon so how dental recognize recognize
Tasha don't repair into Liberia new life
hang on a doorstep doorstep Zachary
online Shulman Janet idea haha a window
my own doll quote refunds crippled
crippled traditional pours out the
Shanghai major Karen picado how costly
dirty Donna peachy super baby formula
takeuchi social tagging services she
wants a couple resident teacher to do to
Shanga without wrong from the continent
in Asuncion type a voyage pseudonyms
either north or hundreds natal majority
- Oh Jim Changjo punctuation Hungarian
in the nature Civil War cheaper nature
hire young the hardship says it's a
quick routine and now Jehovah can tend
to suffer suffer Tapia should solutions
odontology qiong's oppa how the shooting
Hanuman my closet issue to the tone to
the show hi young to undergo u nder geo
undercoat higher your chin deeds also
diesel Hana me transit John Jacob is
okay Michelle
[Music]
now how is a handy wine show come the
one fat diet
see now she shot a wimp at John Deere yo
lianca bigger should
despite de rigueur should ask so when
she came into the young van how much
Elijah despite despite their shooting
when sara has to teach its homie OG
means the hodo means Veeru despite
feeling sick she went to work jinghuan
SHINee pooja for Tahajjud Shashank bang
ha Natasha Natasha Gordo although she
did okay on my period Australian
jinghuan cut Hamilton Jets the homie
avenged it's true
Natasha Ruben Israel despite that it's
true peace ratio means homework sanction
the fact you later how they did that
true champion despite the fact that
George Adams young John fan said it's
true
nowadays you can tell although it was
raining they still went hiking
jinghuan - I'll hammer hydrogen she
nakaka new yo-yo homeopathy Joo young
despite like I said nah gorillaz return
to the not happy trip despite it was
raining they still went hiking
deirdre despite the fact that it was
Sam Halima realization damages just told
her even despite her Satish it's the
home importance idiots the trio saying
Yasha
tear each other despite the fact that it
was raining they still went hiking
how do I measure a stanchion when she
came into the young fat drunk when she
died means to a wager top position
ninjutsu Casio Shangguan Jie that means
the young ginger the time into the Conan
you my pet ETA Miasha homies Oh shoo
shoo the ting-kwong with shoo shoo nah
my ass tanto language a that means to
the Shahadah the east you should root on
the myung-hoon roots and yeah
hey on my page jungle tree altitude
century the a puffin on my own nature I
can we continue Daniel will be taking
three months off as was mentioned in the
meeting general when I wrote he tada
Daniel Johnson thank you the HSL
trans Amanda
yachiru Tom Janu samyama happenchance
Eden Jetson
Tom Sawyer young life education teacher
Daniel John Chatterton searching as was
mentioned in the meeting Joe Pass Road
surgeons general Hans equation so today
yeah
Hahnemann sounds Sen Johnny Antonio
Machado jello okay welcome to I'm Holly
uh everybody I'm sure okay so what's
today's topic shame me who young that's
how I know okay so I'm Jung summer and
guess ptew moon pop you do that
nobody sent me another poem shape on
your notice I did did you rehearse y'all
like to play want attention
[Music]
why is our food taking some compound you
don't have to make such a scene yeah so
in this you were just making like a
scene right I was making a theme a
little bit I mean you should be more
patient but why don't we say make a
scene somebody says I'm a scene Oh scene
was it just a thing we meant in Bouie
more the down there's a valiant
[Applause]
Academy's idea which I didn't do Leah
yeah I make a scene don't make us okay
so what doesn't make a scene I will just
come
or you can say we don't have to throw a
tantrum
oh okay so tantrum look at stitch he's
just a sapphire peachy's go again she is
indeed a mill the would see the Knights
on five piece trial just a song it's a
tantrum just see how good throw that
they are cuckoo titi does so throw a
tantrum you could say don't be such a
drama queen
that sooner is it just me honey honey
dissipate room without any hydrants it
sound like a drama my fans I say yeah
just see one that's it away chew it down
so it's just a schwa twins I've gotten
its own drama queen to see what okay
okay so in the future if you're not sure
how to say something in English
calleman Diana you don't have to make a
scene you don't have to make a scene you
don't have to throw a tantrum you don't
have to throw a tantrum don't be such a
drama queen
don't be such a drama queen
[Music]