[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hello
everybody i am shane
today we're looking at part one of tom
holland
from ballet to spiderman
and beyond and the vocabulary words are
studio studio larissa signed up for
dance classes at a studio close to her
house
suggest suggest my friend terry
suggested a great restaurant for us to
try
nice guidance guidance i got into my
dream school
thanks to my parents guidance
achievement
achievement finding a cure for the
disease
is perhaps the scientist's greatest
achievement
lifetime lifetime my dad doesn't believe
climate change will be solved in his
lifetime
so we're talking about tom holland the
famous actor
right have you ever seen billy elliot
yes i
have and i didn't know that was tom
holland
i didn't know that either i didn't make
the connection
between billy elliot because he was
pretty young
that's right when he played billy
elliott i didn't know that there was a
connection between that and spider-man
i love the movie billy elliott me too
so good it was a good performance by tom
holland and
you can tell that he is a great dancer
right so he always did have a natural
talent right and dancing and he liked
dancing and performing
and his mother always knew that he was
going to do something big one day right
that's right so she did actually support
him in this dream and then he did
try out for uh start to learn ballet
so that he could do billy elliot i think
he trained for a little while and then
he landed this
role and that's pretty impressive and it
led
to a huge thing which is
becoming spy spiderman spiderman
and he signed a six picture deal so that
means
six spiderman movies that's a lot of
money
okay i think he has he would have enough
money for the rest of his life
that's so cool he's a really talented
actor
definitely his big break okay let's
learn more about
tom holland all right let's go
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond tom holland's mother always
knew he had star power
even when he was just a baby he just
wouldn't quit dancing
so when he was old enough she signed her
son up for hip-hop dance classes
at a local studio in london she never
imagined this would set him on a path to
hollywood
today's lesson is called tom holland
from
ballet to spider-man and
beyond part one hello everyone
my name is jeff and i'm mike and if
anyone has been out to the movies in the
last few years you might have
heard of these you know these marvel
superheroes movies these avengers
movies you definitely know tom holland
he's
spider-man or at least he's been
spider-man for
it must be close to 10 years now he's
been spider-man for quite a long time
for five different movies and of course
he's still a very young guy
a young actor but he's had quite an
interesting career so far
and he's got some cool things coming up
for us to enjoy so let's find out more
about tom holland and how he went from
ballet
to spider-man and what he's going to
continue to do
he went from ballet yeah to spider-man
who knew
interesting anyways tom holland's mother
always knew he had a star
power or had star power i should say
even when he was just a baby
he just wouldn't quit dancing
so he was a young dancer but no he
wasn't actually ballet dancing from the
beginning
it was a different form of dance he
loved to dance but
not necessarily in classical ballet so
next we read so when he was old enough
she
that's his mother she signed her son up
for hip-hop dance classes
at a local studio in london ah okay
so like a lot of young kids it wasn't
ballet that was so interesting to him it
was hip-hop dancing
dancing to hip-hop music break dancing
things like that that's what he really
wanted to learn and sure
if you're going to learn a type of art
or perform or even practice or do
a type of art a studio is the kind of
place you might do it
we often think of a studio as a space
where artists work
in some kind of way a painter's studio
might be a big
open place with lots of windows to let
in light
a dance studio would have very little
furniture just a big
open floor some mirrors on the wall and
that's where dancers
would practice and perform mostly
practicing
mostly working on their art and then
they might take the art out of the
studio
put it in a gallery if it's a painter a
painter
or perform it on a stage if it's a
dancer but whether where they do the
work where they do their practice
that would be in a studio for example
larissa
signed up for dance classes at a studio
close to her house all right so it was
hip-hop dance now
his mother was probably thinking this
would be you know good exercise good to
get his energy out he likes to dance you
know
maybe he'll get to perform with a pop
star or be in a music video but
to go from hip hop to superhero movies
that probably wasn't what she expected
that probably did not occur to her
no at that point she thought all right
we'll start him off there at the hip-hop
dancing all right and then
maybe we'll advance to ballet because
no one ballet dances out of the womb but
yeah she never
imagined this this start
in hip-hop dancing class would
set him on a path to hollywood anyways
folks with that let's go ahead and
take a break but when we come back we'll
hear more about
tom holland hello
[Music]
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond when holland was 10 years old
a talent scout suggested he try out for
billy elliot the musical
a play about a young boy who follows his
dream of becoming a ballet dancer
holland didn't know ballet but with his
dance teacher's guidance
he trained for two years and landed a
part
he did so well that he was given the
title role
after only two months of performing this
was holland's big break
okay when holland was 10 years old
a talent scout suggested he try out
for billy elliot the musical
a play about a young boy
who follows his dream of becoming
a ballet dancer so there you go
he was in hip-hop class there and he
wasn't necessarily going to move on to
ballet but hey
a talent scout saw him and said you've
got to try out
for this musical you're perfect for it
you're gonna
knock it out of the park it'll be a home
run
for you anyways this talent scout
suggested he try this out if you suggest
something to someone you recommend this
thing
to them you say you should probably
do this for example my friend
terry suggested a great restaurant for
us to try
okay moving on so billy
elliott the musical that's right not the
movie
no the musical that's right very popular
musical in london
and one of those musicals where there's
a kid in the main role as
billy elliot and as the kids grow up
right they need to find
new people to continue on the role so
this is a good chance for a young actor
with some dancing skills to get a pretty
big job a pretty big role
but of course tom holland was a hip-hop
dancer
billy elliot is not a hip-hop musical
it's about a young guy who does ballet
so holland didn't know ballet
but with his dance teacher's guidance
he trained for two years
and landed apart he basically had to
learn how to ballet dance from scratch
from
zero it took him two years he had some
dancing ability
but hip-hop and ballet not a lot of
similarity there so he needed guidance
from a teacher and that's what teachers
give people they give people
guidance they give them advice they give
them wisdom
they give them training and knowledge
they show them skills they answer their
questions
they basically set you on they suggest
they suggest stuff they set you on a
path to success
and if you follow their guidance if you
follow their instruction
listen to what they want to teach you
then you will be successful for example
i got into my dream school thanks to my
parents
guidance i asked them hey i want to go
to this great school
what should i do and they suggested all
these things so i listened to their
advice
i took their guidance so two years of
hard work
now he was a ballet dancer two years of
his life that's right
now he was a ballet dancer but at all
two years his life but he did
land this role yeah he did so well
that he was given the title role
after only two months of performing so
he was an
understudy perhaps for a couple of
months
and then they said hey this person is
doing better
than the lead let's give him the lead
and this
was holland's big break he was billy
elliot not
boy dancer number three he was no he was
no longer
wow boy dancer named
unknown number three he was billy
elliot's the star
this was tall this this was holland's
big
break all right folks with that it's
time for us to take a break but don't go
away
we'll be right back after this
understudy u-n-d-e-r-s-t-u-d-y
under-study k-1
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond by the time holland was 16
he was getting major parts in films as
well as excellent reviews
despite his achievements he didn't feel
successful
his mom even sent him to carpentry
school as a backup plan
in case acting didn't work out however
at the age of 19 he got the offer of a
lifetime
a six-picture deal to play spider-man in
the marvel
cinematic universe
okay holland he has hit
the big time he landed the lead role
there in
billy elliott the musical well done
and by the time holland was 16
he was getting major parts and films
as well as excellent reviews now that's
important
okay he was getting those good parts but
the critics
also liked him not only
was he getting these parts but he was
doing a good job and people were
noticing
that he had talent yeah and people were
definitely paying attention all right so
let's see what it says next
yes despite his achievements he didn't
feel
successful he thought i'm not that great
i've done a couple of good things i
guess but
am i really all that successful nah
anyways here we have the noun
achievement to talk about
and achievement is something noteworthy
cool
great awesome that you do successfully
if you reach a goal that you've really
been working
hard to achieve and you get there
that's an achievement graduating from
college
is an achievement climbing a mountain is
an achievement
completing a project at school can be an
achievement
putting your socks on in the morning
not an achievement that wasn't that
wasn't hard to do the same thing goes
for
drinking a cup of coffee in the morning
so on so
forth for example finding a cure for the
disease is perhaps the scientists
greatest achievement there you go
finding a cure for a disease
now that's an achievement okay so
tom holland didn't think he was all that
successful
and i guess his mom shared these
feelings
because his mom even sent him
to carpentry school as a backup plan
in case acting didn't work out
wow very interesting so his mom thought
well
you might have skills as a dancer and
success as an actor but
you need to have something in case this
whole show business thing just
doesn't happen carpentry carpentry
making things with your hands out of
wood tables and chairs and carving
cabinets and stuff like that well
you know we might laugh but you can make
a lot of money as a skilled carpenter
jesus was a carpenter that too
but you can make a lot of money as a
carpenter it's one of those skills you
can always have like being a chef or
something like that so there you go
so we had this other backup plan a
backup plan is like a plan b
in case plan a in case your case your
first day
plan doesn't work out at least you won't
be completely lost
you'll have this backup plan in case
things don't work
out so let's read on and find out if
things worked out
for tom holland well it says however at
the age of 19 he made a table
no no no however at the age of 19 he got
the
offer of a lifetime a six-picture
deal to play spider-man in the marvel
cinematic
universe the mcu you can make a lot of
money as a carpenter but you make more
money being
spider-man in hollywood movies a little
bit more
all right so yes this is definitely the
offer
of a lifetime all right your lifetime is
that period when you're alive
from the day you're born to the day you
die that
is your lifetime now of course here we
don't know
he's still a young man he could live a
lot longer maybe someone will
offer to make him king of spain we don't
know that would be the offer of a life
not likely
but it would be a good offer the offer
of a lifetime is basically the most
wonderful thing anyone has ever said
here
do you want this it's amazing it's a
wonderful
adver wonderful opportunity for him the
offer of a lifetime the best offer
his whole life for example my dad
doesn't believe
climate change will be solved in his
lifetime
in the period he's alive he thinks the
climate will always
be in trouble your dad sounds like a
smart guy yeah
all right folks with that today's lesson
is now in the books and it's time for us
to say
noteworthy
lifetime lifetime
the means of a lifetime change
foreign
by the time we got there the show had
already
you'd better take an umbrella with you
in case it rains
[Music]
abraham lincoln was the 16th president
of the united states
at that time america was divided by the
civil war
what was that war about it was fought
between america's southern
and northern states the southern states
didn't want to be part of america
anymore
they wanted to form their own country
they also wanted to make their own laws
back then it was still legal in the
south to own slaves
but in the northern states owning slaves
was already illegal
lincoln was against slavery during the
war
he put forth an order that freed 3.5
million slaves in 1865
the war ended and the southern states
lost
today there is a huge statue of lincoln
at the lincoln memorial
in washington d.c you can also see words
from his famous speeches
carved in stone come visit and learn
more about
american history here is more
information abolish
many people want to abolish this law
beard the man has a long gray beard
civil the country is in the middle
of a civil war coffin
the king's coffin is made of gold
document you have to fill out these
documents
before you can see the doctor
establish the school was established
in the 1800s
important being happy is more
important than being rich
leader hank is the leader of the soccer
team
portrait the artist painted a portrait
of his sister
slavery the usa had slavery
for more than 200 years
wasn't that a super interesting lesson
i know i thought so we'll see you again
next time
see you next time