[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hello
everybody i'm shane
today we have our lesson on closed test
and it's called
cyberspace in space and the vocabulary
words are
mankind mankind the history of mankind
is full of war and violence agency
agency after she got her degree colleen
started working for a government agency
lunar luna the moon takes 27.3 days to
go once around the earth
and complete a full lunar cycle
partnership
partnership experts agree that the
partnership between the two companies
has been quite successful so we're
talking about something really
interesting cyber space in space
yes because if you go to the moon
right and you get off of your rocket
what is the first thing you want to do
selfie right and then
post it to instagram right so
what would happen if people can't do
that that's pretty horrible so that's
where nokia is going to help
right so nasa is going to put another
they hope by
2024 that's right to have the next man
and the first woman on the surface of
the moon
that is so cool so of course they're
going to want to be checking their ig
you know so we have to set up some kind
of
cellular network so they're really going
to do it
so that means in the future if let's say
if we go to the moon
then we'll be able to take selfies and
post it on
you know our whatever social social
media yeah that we want to yeah
like instantly but it's also going to be
important for communication between the
people
it's not just for selfies on instagram
that's true it could check the health
status of the astronauts and things like
that so
of course there are some real practical
and important reasons
it's not just for social media you are
right okay i'm so sorry
but it's a wonderful progress let's
learn more about cyberspace
in space let's go
cyberspace in space in 1969
nasa helped mankind make history by
putting a man on the moon
now nasa is once again looking to break
new ground
by bringing the moon online the space
agency has teamed up with the finnish
phone company nokia on this project
and together they aim to have the lunar
surface wired by 2022
hi i'm jeff hi i'm hani
welcome to this month's close
test today we're going to read about
space and nasa
and the moon you see
we haven't been to the moon for a while
as a species okay right right right
and it's high time that we go back
well first of all though we are going to
need to
make some tech breakthroughs
think about this
is there internet on the moon
can you go online while
on the moon no
and no but this won't be
true for long right anyway the title of
this month's
lesson is cyberspace
okay i say we get started let's start
reading
okay let's get online yeah
let's get going the first line of
today's
lesson says in 1969
nasa helped mankind
make history by putting a man on the
moon
yes folks we've people as a species
have been to the moon just not
recently anyway mankind
is a word that you can use to refer to
all people or all
of humanity or all of the human race
at once basically the term
mankind refers to the human species
as a whole for example the history of
mankind
is full of war
and violence well all of that
happened in 1969 in the past
now nasa is once again
break new ground by bringing the moon
online
your options are a looking two
b making up c engaging
in or d depending
on
how
so the sentence should read now
nasa is once again looking
to break new ground by bringing the moon
online there you have it nasa is
taking us back to the moon but first
they are going to bring the moon online
it's official
to bring the moon online well
but they will have some help
right the space agency
has teamed up with the finnish
phone company nokia on this project
and together they aim to have the lunar
surface by 2022
your options are a wire be
wired c wiring
[Music]
so the sentence should read
the space agency has teamed up with the
finnish phone company nokia
on this project and together they
aim to have the lunar surface wired
by 2022 okay we have
two vocabulary words to discuss
the first of these is the word agency
an agency is like a company or an
organization
that focuses on or specializes
in one thing travel agencies help people
travel while a space agency might help
people
to go to space and beyond
for example after she got her degree
colleen started working for a government
agency
also we have the adjective lunar
to talk about the word lunar means of
or having to do with the moon
okay now if you wanted to talk about the
sun there's a related adjective
solar solar means of or having to do
with
the sun okay i know this sounds
weird these adjectives come from
latin so don't worry about it too much
for example
the moon takes 27
days to go once around the earth
and complete a full lunar
cycle okay everyone with that it is now
time for a break but don't go away
we'll be back after a short break
cyberspace in space the partnership is
part of nasa's artemis program
which plans to put the first woman and
the next man on the moon by the year
nokia was given 14.1 million dollars to
design
a 4g lte network that will be upgraded
to 5g in the future
[Music]
welcome back to this month's close
test lesson the title of today's lesson
is
cyberspace in space
well before the break we learned that we
are
going back to the moon well not jeff and
i but nasa is going to go back to the
moon
and it's about time i agree
nasa is going back to the moon but
they're also going to do some really
cool stuff while they're there nasa
is going to go back to the moon
and they're also going to bring the moon
online does this mean that there will be
internet on the moon well i guess
that's possible it is possible
yes nasa is going to bring the moon
online so
internet on the moon it's a possibility
but
they're not doing all of this alone nasa
is working with a
finnish company named nokia to bring the
moon
online and the partnership is part of
nasa's artemis program which plans to
put the first woman
and the next man on the moon by the year
and here we have our fourth vocabulary
word of the day
partnership a partnership simply means
a relationship between partners it can
refer to a relationship between
two people companies organizations
etc for example experts agreed that the
partnership
between the two companies has been quite
successful
wow all of this surely
sounds ambitious but i also want to hear
a little bit
more about this whole moon going
online thing i mean
will there actually be internet on the
moon
really really close
enough it sounds like there will be a
cellular network there on the moon
and that nokia is going to build it
with nasa i should have known the next
sentence
of our article says nokia
was given 14.1 million
dollars to design a 4g
lte network that will be
upgraded to 5g in the future
there you go
is
okay everyone with that it is now time
to take
another break don't go away though we'll
be back with the final part of this
month's
closed test soon
cyberspace in space the lunar network
will provide
new visitors to the moon with every
mobile convenience they already have on
earth
astronauts will be able to communicate
and share data with one another
and also use it for navigation what's
more
it will be used to track each
astronaut's health and fitness
if everything goes according to plan
instagram stories straight from the moon
can't be far behind
welcome back everyone this month's
closed test
is about taking the moon online
no joke she's serious
everyone nasa and nokia
are working together to build a
cellular network on
the moon it will be a
4g network that can be upgraded to a
5g network in the future
wow ok let's read on the lunar network
will provide new visitors to the moon
every mobile convenience they already
have
on earth your options are a
2 b by c
so the sentence should read the lunar
network
will provide new visitors to the moon
with
every mobile convenience they already
have
on earth so yes
if you are lucky enough to be one of the
visitors
to the moon and rich enough yeah one of
those rich people
if you're one of these people lucky
enough to get to the moon in the near
future
you'll be able to log on to the internet
while on the moon
you will be able to use your smartphone
while on the moon yep and there's
more astronauts will be able to
communicate
and share data with one another and also
use it for navigation
beats
so yes it will be great for smartphone
usage
but it will also be useful for people
like astronauts who will have a
real need for it while on the moon
blank it will be used
to track each astronaut's health
and fitness your options are a
personally be fortunately
c strange to say
or d
so the sentence should read what's more
it will be used to track each
astronaut's health and fitness
anyway i know that that might
sound boring but astronauts will be
the people who first go back
to the moon and it will most
likely be astronauts who are there
most often so we should probably take
good
care of them right but if
everything goes according to plan
instagram stories
straight from the moon can't be far
behind
it's true
it's so true yeah anyway everyone we are
now
finished yes our lesson is now
in the books right and it's time to say
bye bye see you next time
[Music]
hello i'm james miller an actor
i haven't been in many movies yet but
i'm sure that i will be famous
one day who knows i might even win an
academy award
what's an academy award that's another
name for
an oscar for a hollywood actor
the greatest honor is to win an oscar
if an actor wins this award he or she
will have the chance to star in many
hollywood movies maybe i should mention
where hollywood is
it's an area in los angeles california
many movies are made in hollywood even
when a studio film
is made somewhere else it can still be
called
a hollywood movie in fact
hollywood is often used to describe the
film business
it can also describe people who work in
this business
for example both hollywood actor and
hollywood film are common phrases
well wish me luck i'm going to try out
for a role in a
new hollywood movie here is more
information
icon the famous singer is a
pop icon originally
paul originally wanted to be a teacher
but now
he is a policeman
suppose the weather was supposed to be
sunny today
but it rained
release the book will be released
in september
film the movie was filmed in spain
set i helped build the movie set
lifeboat the lifeboat saved the people
in the ocean
leading kate is the leading actress
in the movie role
david got a role in the play
budget my food budget every month
is 500
so what did you think of today's lesson
pretty interesting right
we hope to see you again next time
you