[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody i'm shane
today we're looking at part two of
soybeans the miracle crop
and the vocabulary words are loaded
loaded
these snacks are loaded with sugar
moreover
moreover randy's grades have been down
this semester
moreover he often shows up late to class
healthful healthful some fats are
actually healthful
so there's no need to be afraid of them
popularity
popularity the popularity of the tv show
turned its sleet actress into a big star
ingredient ingredient the cooks at this
restaurant prefer to use
local ingredients so we're still talking
about the amazing
miracle crop soybeans right yeah it's
just
very very healthful it's like loaded
with protein
and minerals and vitamins and it's
even connected or linked to
lower heart disease that's right and
less
less people getting cancer i think
that's probably because
meat is usually connected to heart
disease and cancer
and type 2 diabetes so if you're eating
a more healthful diet with soybeans
you're going to
be healthier what a great you know crop
because it has so many benefits right i
think it also strengthens your bones as
well oh yeah right
right but and it can also come in
different forms like for example miso
is a soy paste right like the miso soup
yeah it's used for a lot of things that
you wouldn't think of i didn't root
soy sauce soy sauce and how important is
soy sauce i know
chinese cooking can you imagine if there
was no soy sauce
exactly ah so it can be used for so many
things
it's good for the planet right and it's
good for you i think you were saying
that you know thanksgiving
you used to eat tofurkey tofurky
yeah so it can even be made into
something that like i said before the
texture of meat so during thanksgiving
in the u.s they will make something
called
tofurkey and it kind of looks like a
turkey but it's made from soybeans
that's right
that's so cool i never had it before so
great alright soybeans number one
let's learn more about this amazing crop
soybeans the miracle crop
today more and more people are
recognizing the benefits of eating soy
making it a popular health food product
soybeans are loaded with protein
fiber vitamins and minerals moreover
consuming soy can improve bone health
and may even be linked to lower risks of
heart disease
certain forms of cancer and type 2
diabetes
welcome everyone today's lesson is
called
soybeans the
miracle crop part two
hello everyone my name is jeff and i'm
mike yes we're talking about the amazing
things that the humble little soybean
can do for us from making soy sauce to
making a fake type of coffee that i
don't think people drink much anymore
but they did
in the past and then scientists
discovered that it had a lot of protein
you could use it to make oil you could
turn it into plastic to make
cars with apparently and of course it
also became a very
cheap but healthy animal feed or animal
food
that they gave to lots of farm animals
so people have been using soy in
lots of amazing ways for a very long
time tofu is made
from soy it's another one delicious it's
wonderful it's great i love eating
that stuff why are we feeding our
soy and soy products to animals
let's consume it ourselves and
apparently yes today more and more
people
are recognizing the benefits of eating
soy and soy products making it a
popular health food product it says
soybeans are loaded with
protein fiber vitamins
and minerals wow basically everything
you need
to be healthy and that's right pretty
much everything you might need protein
that we might get from meat
fiber that we might get from you know
wheat or grains or
certain fruit vitamins of course from
fruit and vegetables
and minerals from lots of different
things but all of those things
are in soy and also we see in this
sentence not in small amounts
in large amounts right soybeans are
loaded
with these things yes there are large
amounts of these things
packed in soybeans that's what the word
loaded means found in large quantities
packed with so on and so forth so what
we're saying here
is that soybeans are really good for you
if you
eat them you will get large amounts of
these good
things like protein fiber vitamins
minerals etc for example
these snacks are loaded with sugar you
shouldn't
eat those they've got way too much
sugar in them anyways moreover
consuming soy can improve
bone health and may even be linked
to lower risks of heart disease
certain forms of cancer and
type 2 diabetes
wow so start eating
soy everyone absolutely it does sound
like one of those
super foods we often hear about so when
we use this adverb moreover
it's something you might use especially
in your writing to show that the
sentence before
and this sentence that i'm using
moreover
to begin they're connected it's all kind
of the same idea
basically we use moreover this adverb in
the same way that we would use
other words like also in addition
furthermore and you know things like
that we're basically
connecting things it's all one big group
of information
it all is very closely related but we're
just separating it into two sentences
but the second one moreover shows that
there's a connection
between the first and this one for
example randy's grades have been down
this semester
so he's not doing well at school right
moreover
he often shows up late to class another
thing that shows
he's having trouble at school anyways
folks with that it's time for us to
take a break and to eat some soy
we'll be back right after this yum yum
hello daddy
diabetes
soybeans the miracle crop since soy
comes in many forms
it's easy to fit this food into your
diet
among the most popular products are tofu
and soy milk
which are great substitutes for meat and
dairy respectively
miso a soy paste is wonderful for making
a wealth of delicious foods like soups
and sauces
in addition tempeh an indonesian food
made from fermented soybeans
has been getting a lot of attention as a
tasty healthful food
with the popularity of plant-based diets
soy has also become a key ingredient in
fake meat products
from chickenless nuggets to tofurkey and
soy bacon
[Music]
okay i've already mentioned this tofu
tofu is everywhere it comes
from soy remember soy is
very versatile soy beans i should say
are very versatile so
since soy comes in many forms
it's easy to fit this food
into your diet and among the most
popular products are tofu
and also you can't forget
soy milk which are great
substitutes for meat and
dairy respectively so there you go
if you want to become a vegetarian and
you want to become a vegan let's say
and you want to find a way to replace
meat
and dairy in your diet go for tofu i
should say
and soy milk okay there you go they
replace yeah the meat and the milk that
you might
drink otherwise miso we also read
miso a soy paste is wonderful for making
a wealth of delicious foods
like soups and sauces that's right
another thing that comes from
japanese cooking me soiling is a soy and
some salt
and you can use it for that wonderful
umami taste that you get with lots of
delicious foods i i once took just a
normal chicken breast and instead of
putting some spices or
oil to give it flavor just put a little
bit of miso on it
and roast it up in the oven or grill it
it's very very good
made it taste really nice but that's not
the only thing you can do with soy
we're just getting started and it says
in addition
tempeh an indonesian food made from
fermented soy beans
has been getting a lot of attention as a
tasty
healthful food this sounds very similar
to miso
from japanese cooking but with a
different wonderful flavor
now here we have the word healthful
people
rarely use this word these days
usually people just use the word
healthy i am a healthy person
and i eat healthy food well
you don't really eat healthy food let's
say you have an apple
and the apple is growing on the tree and
it's
thriving you can say that that apple
is healthy and let's say you
are not sick you're growing in you're
robust
and happy you are healthy now
you pick that apple and you
eat it and it makes you healthy
that apple has been healthful
for you so here the word healthful means
healthy but it does mean
it's healthy as in it's conducive to
health for you it helps you to be
healthy for example some fats are
actually healthful so there's no need to
be
afraid of them okay let's go ahead and
move on with the popularity of
plant-based diets soy
has also become a key ingredient
in fake meat products
from chickenless nuggets to
tofurkey and
soy bacon hmm yeah absolutely
tofurkey tofu turkey tofurky
tofurkey that caught me by surprise
that's a new word by me
tofurkey i think it's they shaped the
tofu
the tofu to actually look like a turkey
i don't know about that but they
probably
put some things in it spices and other
things to make it taste
kind of like turkey or something like
that but yes these are all things you
might have
if you're on a plant-based diet
basically if you're a vegetarian
or a vegan and you're not eating meat or
other
animal things you might be on a
plant-based
diet mostly fruit and vegetable and
stuff like that and there is a growing
popularity
with this kind of healthful diet
this kind of diet that where people
don't eat things from
animals popularity this is a noun that
just basically talks about
how much people like something large
groups
of people the public how much the public
likes something is talking about its
popularity the
number one movie in the cinema the
number one song
on the charts famous people who we all
go oh that guy's so great or
she's so famous and everyone loves her
they have high levels of popularity
they are very popular to use the
adjective
for example the popularity of the tv
show
turned its lead actress into a big star
people loved the show and of course all
the stars on the show
were also popular they had a lot of
popularity
also we have the word ingredient to talk
about
when we're talking about ingredients
we're talking about all those
things that you combine to make
something usually when you when we're
cooking and you want to make a dish
you have ingredients you put those
together to make
that dish like if you want to make
spaghetti you need to
boil water add salt to the water you
need to have
pasta and sauce and stuff like that
and then put them together in the right
way those would all be
the ingredients of the pasta that you're
trying to make
for example the cooks at this restaurant
prefer to use local ingredients or
locally sourced ingredients
all right folks with that it is time for
us to take a break but don't go away
we'll be right back
after this
t-h-r-i-v-e thrive
robust r-o-b-u-s-t
robust on
among the most popular products are tofu
and soy milk which tien did
have among the most popular
products
foreign
standing over there is the cute guy i
met
yesterday
in addition
the price is reasonable in addition
the quality is good
get a lot of attention or should gain a
lot of
attention
the new app is gaining a lot of
the miracle crop the environment is also
a factor
and choosing legumes such as soy over
meat for our meals
could reduce greenhouse gases and
conserve water and land use
soybeans are healthful simple to grow
and less harmful to the environment
it's fair to say that soybeans truly are
a miracle crop
[Music]
mike yes we've left something out while
while talking about this miracle
crop what's that we've left out the
environment
oh okay well of course yeah more people
are looking at having a
plant-based diet there is a growing
popularity for that but also a growing
popularity
for picking foods that are good for the
environment that don't hurt the earth
by us growing them and eating them it
says the environment
is also a factor and choosing
legumes such as soy over meat
for our meals could reduce greenhouse
gases
and conserve water and land use
basically this sentence is saying soy is
better for the earth
than eating meat if everyone switched
from meat to soy
the earth would be very happy we would
reduce greenhouse gases
co2 levels would go down because cows
make a lot of
greenhouse gas and also we would save a
lot of water and land
water that we use to feed you know to
give to animals and
land that they have to grow that the
animals need to grow on
we talk about legumes here that's just a
category
of kind of vegetables we put beans in
there we put
peas in there these are legumes so
they're a little bit different from
you know cabbage and other fruits and
things like that it's basically
beans this is that family of legumes
anyway soybeans everyone is healthful
simple to grow and less harmful to the
environment
it's fair to say that soybeans
truly are uh
miracle crop where's the choir oh there
we go
lovely now it's time for the one
question
mike yes what's your favorite way
to eat soy that's a good question
well i'd say at least in my personal
kitchen at home
no i've never had tofurkey i love to eat
soy sauce i mean i have that at home and
i
put that on certain dishes but i'd have
to say
stinky tofu i love to eat cho dofu
especially the fried kind
and i do enjoy that but i don't eat it
at home very often
because it does tend to kind of smell up
the place
but if i go to a night market i will
enjoy a nice plate
of chodofu me too
all right folks that's it for our lesson
and it's time for us to say
bye bye
[Music]
you may think the name silicon valley
sounds
very strange actually the name of
silicon valley
refers to the large number of silicon
computer chip makers
in this area of course silicon valley
is no longer just a center for computer
chip companies
it is also the home of important
software in
internet companies for example both
google and facebook are based here
these companies also started out here as
much
smaller companies as they grew
silicon valley also became richer
these days silicon valley is one of the
wealthiest
regions in the world silicon valley is
also lucky to have
stanford university in the area
many engineers and business people from
stanford
have contributed to silicon valley it's
an area that
continues to grow here is more
information birthplace
tom's birthplace is a small town in the
uk
headquarters the company's headquarters
is in new york city
high tech this phone is very high tech
paris is the french hub of fashion
innovation farming innovations
make it easier to grow food
millionaire the millionaire has an
expensive car
notify the school notifies parents
when their children don't go to class
rent my rent each month is
12 000
security there are lots of security
cameras
in the department store sensor
the light has a sensor so it turns on
when someone walks by
wasn't that a super interesting lesson
i know i thought so we'll see you again
next time