[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen one must be
us I'm Shane
today we're looking at part two of
marvelous my Orica and the vocabulary
words are appreciate appreciate because
of its many parks the city is great for
those who appreciate nature abandoned
abandoned I reported the abandoned car
that was parked in front of my house to
the police composure composure
Olivia studied late 18th century
composers in school capital capital
Sacramento is the capital of California
my home state really gallery gallery
Sophia likes to visit our galleries in
her free time so we're still talking
about the marvelous meiotic time that's
right last time we talked about how
beautiful it is yeah and the beaches
ruin you can't ride your bicycle around
the island but today if we're gonna talk
about some other things now then do I
think it's quite famous for going to the
beach right that's right but there you
can go to the countryside there so
there's some coming things too it's
becoming more and more popular like
there's some abandoned farms turned into
some like you know retreats where you
can go and just relax and enjoy the
countryside and there's lots of
festivals going on summer long if you
like music they got Street markets you
can enjoy the wine and the great food
well your guys definitely the play with
the place to go yeah and if you like
music speaking of music if you like
classical music you like Chopin there's
a yeah there's a monastery there where
you actually stayed and now it's a
museum so you can see stuff about Chopin
or music classical music so that's kind
of cool and in the capital of Majorca
home ah that's right you can also see a
lot of historic buildings you can see a
lot of museums and if you'll enjoy
paintings by the Casa oh yeah because
some of Picasso's paintings
that's right you can definitely enjoy
the art in the culture and the music
yeah Salvador Dali there and Miro like
oh wow yeah there's a lot of great
Spanish artists that's right it just
sounds like a wonderful place that has a
combination of everything right a lot of
culture and a lot of fun a lot of
natural beauty awesome alright so let's
go to Majorca too bad yes marvellous
Majorca although my orcas beaches have
been its main draw for many years more
recently visitors have begun to
appreciate the islands cultural
attractions too many of my orcas grand
old houses and abandoned farms are being
turned into pleasant rural retreats
where visitors can enjoy the relaxed
lifestyle of the my York and countryside
in the nearby villages summers go by
like one long festival the days are
filled with music dancing and street
markets that sell my or canned wine and
other delicious local produce today's
lesson is called marvelous my Orca part
2 hi everyone my name is Jeff and I'm
Mike okay let's get started once again
on our lesson on my Orca home to Rafael
Nadal one of the great tennis players of
all time in his generation there's Roger
Federer
there's Novak Djokovic and then there's
good old Rafael Nadal he calls my Orca
home now although my orcas beaches and
we started talking about the beaches
last time although my orcas beaches have
been its main draw for many years more
recently visitors have begun to
appreciate the islands cultural
attractions too so before people thought
hey you got the mountains there and then
the eye candy the beautiful coasts
around Majorca but there's much more to
be had there in Majorca than just
beautiful landscapes and coasts like
that yes more recently our article says
visitors have started to or begun to
appreciate the islands culture as well
and the cultural
interesting so here we have this word
appreciate talking about visitors
tourists appreciating the culture of my
orc well when we talk about appreciate
in this sense we're kind of saying they
respect it they think it's good they
like it and they know that it's you know
important or interesting or unusual it's
something that we should give respect to
as well as enjoy now in another way we
can use appreciate just as kind of a way
of saying I'm thankful for something I
appreciate my friends hey I appreciate
you driving me to the airport today that
was a very kind thing to do and in
another way we can also use this to talk
about if we understand something we
understand its value all right I
appreciate how important my health is to
me I was sick last year it was terrible
so now I have a better understanding of
how important or how good or you know
how much I need something so appreciates
always a little bit different but it
generally means we're thankful and we
respect or understand something's
importance for example because of its
many parks the city is great for those
who appreciate nature who enjoy and
respect and like to spend time in nature
anyways yes many of my orcas grand old
houses and abandoned forms are being
turned into Pleasant rural retreats
where visitors can enjoy the relaxed
lifestyle of the my Yorkin countryside
how about that now here we've got grand
old houses and then abandoned farms it
doesn't sound like these farms are going
to be abandoned for long they're being
turned into things that people can enjoy
but yes abandoned farms other forms that
the farmers have left they've left and
they don't look like they're coming back
any time soon yes if something has been
abandoned someone has left something
somewhere and they have no intention of
returning and picking up or you've had
you have a house or a farm or something
and you leave those places and you think
you know what I'm never coming I'm never
coming back I'm abandoning this place
yes abandoned would be the verb
abandoned here would be an ad
for example I reported the abandoned car
that was parked in front of my house to
the police and if you want to do your
shopping well head to the local village
in the nearby villages summers go by
like one long festival this is that
culture we're talking about the days are
filled with music dancing and street
markets that sell my or canned wine and
other delicious local produce
Wow so you'll have lots of options for
eating drinking dining and entertainment
yeah maybe learn a little bit of Spanish
to help yourself with the shopping but
I'm sure there's an app for that and it
sounds like you'll have a really good
time enjoying my Eric and people food
culture what a great holiday and we
haven't even finished there's still more
alright so let's listen to some music
and then let's dance
Wow bailamos Wow dance Spanish classes
are paying off alright everyone let's go
ahead and take a break there it's time
for us to yet take that break and also
bailamos muy bien
hello Mario Tech want you want Opie's
any gadget Onodera say hello say way
like this ship I had a show on show
situations and Mark how tall nonfat eat
in the currency Shalimar to coddle the
serum jinghuan see shall I can hang -
and we'll watch Indian calendar sure
Malik hot - angle should go home with a
long high of 82 Nong Jaa June Cedric
Benson
sure sure pigeon a chance or round
yokomen Koh solution shall Senna be haha
so murrica sounds in the ocean Soho not
there foods in the trend Rona
Saturn's yahowha manchanda THC me denote
Ramallah in your hooter honey I could
require control Seattle should see a
tree my mother called mother cut out a
garage or outside he non-champions later
how not really the dance it appreciate
appreciate
Tasha don't see - in shock shanshu Taha
lingua oh can see the ISA nama
abandoned abandoned hashish ounces you
know she Judah should sheep were younger
Jericho and Rome
marvelous Majorca
in one of these villages Valdai mosa
you'll find a monastery where the famous
composer frederic chopin and his lover
George Sand spent the winter of 1838 as
well as now being a museum devoted to
the great musician the monastery also
holds a classical music festival in his
honor every August
[Music]
word on the street Mike now is that you
like music I do I like you're a fan of
music I like music play the bass play
the music you like to play the music
listen to the music how do you feel
about this piano player fellow named
Frederic Chopin Oh chop in' you mean
Chopin
I'm a big fan of Chopin no I know that
big red Rick Chopin Chopin that would be
the crannis
that would be the correct genius yeah of
course not named Chopin I'm not a big
Chopin fan I'm not so much into the
romantics more the Baroque style music
but of course he is a very well-known
composer and it seems there's a
connection to my Orca he spends some
time on my Orca we find out all about
this in our first sentence
you mentioned Rafael Nadal the famous
tennis player he lives there now
Chopin used to live there don't look for
him there he's gone but let's find out
about this famous resident of my Orca in
one of these villages valide Musa you'll
find a monastery where the famous
composer Frederic Chopin and his lover
George Sand spent the winter of 1838
that's a mat that's absolutely amazing
so they stayed in this monastery back in
1838 in the winter of hiss of course as
we mentioned Chopin is a famous
classical music composer probably also a
piano player a pianist but a composer is
what he's most well known for what is a
composer this noun simply means someone
who writes music that's it you're the
person who sits down and either works it
out on the piano or something writes it
down on the music paper on the notation
and stuff like that when we think of
composers we have think Mozart Beethoven
Chaka
skee Chopin Bach people like that sure
you could be a composer of modern pop
music we might call you a songwriter or
something like that because composers
are mainly focused on the music not the
word so much so that's why we might
separate the terms we use Olivia
for example Olivia studied late 18th
century composers in school so that
would have been like Mozart or someone
like that is that what she made your
didn't it interesting I don't know if
you can do that but hey you can take a
look they're very interesting the lives
of these composers now as well as now
being a museum devoted to the great
musician the monastery also holds a
classical music festival in his honor
every August so there you go you like
music there in Majorca you can also
listen to the Spanish music and the
classical music if you go there in
August head to this festival alright
folks with that it's time for us to take
a break but don't go away we'll be back
soon hey John when I got sanjana's well
father Moore's at Truman nosotras a
shell behind hello children children
songs and window shows our Google APIs
and Bonnie don't hear her name social
Darian shinza to determine watching and
shopping say wait wait that I knew each
other for one Namir wait I mean in the
pirate ship including English and
hydrogen when John yonder monastery
monastery Chewbacca showed our unique
ages yet the matanza composure composure
Tapio so treats yeah Michael Sata she
dances she hung down notation tickets n
ot a tion notation beautiful how only
your musical notation to keep you out
that in fool hawlucha healthy - ah
noryeok ah should know Shing near the
trunk so Jill my passion for young
songwriters like that our church uncle's
a robust young composer IPO Tata
johnrandall
Hanna Jericho and John marvelous Majorca
Palma my orcas lively capital is also
home to many museums historic buildings
and galleries here you'll be able to see
works by great Spanish pain
deters such as Picasso Dali and Miro
whose former house in the city's western
district is open to visitors as the day
winds down spend an evening enjoying a
freshly caught supper in one of Palma's
oceanfront restaurants while taking in a
beautiful my Orkin sunset what better
way to wrap up your Spanish adventure
let's get back to my Orca next we're
going to move on and talk about a really
important city there in my Orca in fact
we're gonna talk about the capital of my
York ok yeah of course it's good to
visit the biggest city on the island no
matter where you go you'll probably find
a little bit more going on there so
let's find out about Palma Majorca is
lively capital is also home to many
museums historic buildings and galleries
yeah you'd expect to find things like
that in a big city in a capital city
more of the cultural stuff will be
located there in the capital of my Orca
so does this mean it's a country and
that's the where the president is no
remember my orc is a part of Spain and
the capital of Spain is Madrid which is
not on this Islands which is not on the
island here when we're talking about
capital and we're talking about an
important city in a place that houses
the government of that place ok so let's
say there's a mayor in Majorca chances
are they live there in the capital Bal
the government people live there in the
capital or at least work in the capital
now one note the capital of a place is
not always the biggest city in that
place let's say like New York City is
not the capital of New York State for
instance ok it might be the cultural
capital the financial capital the
capital in every other way but the
government Center in New York they're
the capital is actually a city called
Albany anyways for example Sacramento is
the capital of California not San
Francisco not Los Angeles not San Diego
Sacramento other things you might see in
Palma a gallery or probably
Merl gallery's this noun is basically a
word we use for a space that is used for
viewing art alright usually it's a large
open space now it might not be a museum
a museum would have galleries those big
rooms where they hang the paintings but
museums are more places for people to
come and look at old famous works of art
and you can't really buy things that you
see there but in a gallery it's kind of
like a shop for art so you'd go to the
gallery they might have a special
showing and in many cases if you like
the painting and have a lot of money you
can buy the paintings on the wall in a
gallery you would also go to a gallery
to see sculptures and 3d art and all
kinds of things like that but if it's
art you appreciate with your eyes you'll
probably go to a gallery to see it if
not a museum for example Sophia likes to
visit art galleries in her free time
that's a fun thing to do okay moving on
here in these galleries here you'll be
able to see works by great Spanish
painters such as Picasso Dali and Miro
whose former house in the city's western
district is open to visitors here's a
big fan of Miro now moving on as the day
winds down spend an evening enjoying a
freshly cut supper in one of Palma's
oceanfront restaurants while taking in a
beautiful my Yorkin sunset by the way I
hear if you do go to Majorca the fishing
is great you can go fishing yourself or
a fisherman can bring you one of these
freshly caught dinners a fish they just
pulled out of the Mediterranean there
they might even clean it for you and
cook it up for you in one of these
oceanfront restaurants sounds magic and
this beautiful orange purple yellow red
my Orkin mediterranean sunset coming
down you're sitting there with your
fresh fish and a nice cool drink what
better way to wrap up your Spanish
adventure what better way to end your
beautiful wonderful enjoyable holiday in
Majorca alright let's go I'm ready let's
go
oh you're going let's
we're going to be there for lunch he
means let's go ahead and ask the lucky
thing question okay the plane leaves in
a few hours
come on so in Europe in your opinion
what is the main draw of Majorca and you
can't say shovelling I'd say the main
draw of Majorca is that you get to enjoy
all the wonder of Spain but in a much
smaller package because you know
traveling around a whole country can
take a long time but I'd rather go and
spend five or six days really getting to
know this little island I think that
would be enough good concentrated
concentrated dose of space and I might
see rafael nadal amazing
all right everyone with that it's time
for us to take a break but don't go away
we'll be back next time with more
I might even beat him at tennis no you
all tonight America the show for Parma
Tavano UK Canada Bhagwan Alicia Chandra
how far along not enemy Helen Doron
waita she by AHA chatters open channel
Picasso Dali human talking donkey show
in Sochi she's Oh penguin hikita
pyramidion hi chanting even seen Sammy
DiPietro Haru go even shall make way -
in-law - one time in Tujunga who shall
carry things we POA
hanim do all I can the dance capital
capital Taipei should show don't wanna
show fool now you can watch an emotion
hold on what it's on yet see Jonah -
meow - oh channel that I will hunt
you taught him to do english' to turn on
Joker you nauseate logic aunty - aw
shofu theme wedding should say tada Cho
Chang no weirdo the show for portion
ownership sure Albany Georgia a pony
the matanza de da de da chuan Santa
Lucia Lucia Shyam into her bosom Chong
technology transition San Francisco Joe
teens and Los Angeles Los Angeles San
Diego should be occurred later
homicide and gallery gallery Takahashi
issues of in the Chen Liang Guan hua
lung Bhutan dance oceanfront oceanfront
version hi Pete I sunset
set to show you look she young Jaime
Johnson James John talkin bids ok
my uncle John house in handy high-end
show come the one fat Danielle she got
your shot will fight song did yoga
digger should as well as their ago
should devote something to cha-cha means
the hodo means it be Sangha should and
somebody's honor
this should what better way to G
ing don't sit yoga should wrap up when
we sell a shirt as well as as well as K
vanish it's like that relationship
mature wide the maja mean Katie means
the hodo means sound as well as
being a chef is also an actor controller
seeming choo-choo has a mean yeah you
know how did Elijah devote something to
jam in Soho domine sit sit don't sit
devote happy hour Chang Shama Shama Tran
young who Joseph own Shin hos Rotolo
shon-kar da Fung gentilozzi energy
meeting the woman challenge I will
devote something to - I mean so who
don't mean saliva Alta Mira she devotes
most of her free time to volunteer work
habitable furnaces oxygen to function
Gillian pookins oh just watch a hotel
you'll come to retreat an eco how
limited Elisha see in somebody's honor
in somebody's honor
Tasha Tasha Willis and Lauren judging
will Athenian Madrid the Acacia - in
honor of somebody vitro the monument was
erected in honor of the poet Sega Cheney
invasion light genie in a way she how
much is eyelashes she take a shushing
what better way to Taliesin don't see
what better way to diverge in don'ts
assuming leadership
hi ocean Mishima Kong - ah - ah - ah -
ah Shama Shama Joe should see how the
favela
drill a shop what better way to start
your day off than with a hearty
breakfast
yeah interchange in agent hi um uh Pete
cheetah functions out shankel how the
fans Anna creature pushes everyone here
or selfish or chilly don't function
without hand Joe should indeed sensing
you can see how the phone back whatever
lecture she wrapped up please wrap up
Tasha to show young some about what you
like if you like the other one showing
what it usually is challenge it let's
wrap this meeting up just a short woman
she showed a time way about how no meet
you sounds Angela Antonio Machado jello
[Music]
there's going to be an amazing topic do
you believe it yeah yeah yeah something
Wilma yes okay good so do you know what
the topic is today
yes that's very good you always have to
something more that's amazing you to
Castle we are going to now go to the
dialogue I promise Chung Hsing wall it's
gonna be good
[Music]
I'm so sorry I will never hurt you again
Frank tricked me into kissing him okay I
trust you but don't trust Frank hmm what
honey Bhutan how do you get tricked how
did he trick you into kissing him no I
don't remember
no remember okay very interesting okay
so I trust you I trust you okay so I
trust you I trust
hmm hung long tongue though trust faith
on the serum dry one Chen Jose I need
some yes
pour I believe you well I'm changing me
was something neat yeah the truth is I
don't really believe you how do you get
tricked into kissing somebody okay going
back I'll take your word for it
uh okay so I'll take your word for it
just it was Santa Shang Shang nice sure
them they destroyed our kilometers each
other
Ian mmm BAE Tong sang scene because when
they showed up now what you're something
I do it indium ooh trading cuz the
English and upon your shoulder
don't worry really there's there's
nothing over there and like there's
nothing going on I'll take your word for
it
I'll take your word yes okay well if
you're having problems with English and
you think we could help you yes I trust
you I trust you I believe you I believe
you
I'll take your word for it I'll take
your word for it
[Music]