[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hey everybody
i'm shane today we're looking at part
one of soybeans
the miracle crop and the vocabulary
words are
consume consume the average person
consumes over
three grams of salt per day reputation
reputation reports that employees were
treated poorly
have ruined the company's reputation
demand demand rory complained that his
new girlfriend demands constant
attention production production
global steel production fell in the
first three months of 2020
content content nuts have a high
fat content so they provide a lot of
energy
so we're talking about soybeans soybeans
if you're a vegetarian
soybeans are your best friend really
because i'm a vegetarian and soy beans
can be made into
so many things and it's high in protein
too
and oil so you can get your protein oil
from soybeans
yeah you can replace meat with soybean
or soybean products like
soy milk tofu
and tempeh and they can use soy
texturized soy to kind of like make
imitation meats
so you can still have the same texture
of eating meat
but without hurting animals that is
amazing but
let me ask you this before you became a
vegetarian did you eat a lot of soybeans
or was it
after you became a vegetarian it was
really more
after i stopped eating meat i realized
the benefits and how wonderful
soy beans were mm-hmm and there's so
many things that you can do
with soy beans too right they can be
used like because the oil
in there that can be used i think even
henry ford
used soybean to kind of make like
plastics or stuff for his cars
i know that's pretty amazing so it's not
only for eating
yeah it's very very versatile and you
can feed it to
cows and things like that to make them
grow bigger so you can also
make more meat so everybody likes
soybeans
i love soybeans too and i love soy milk
okay let's learn more about the miracle
crop all right
soybeans the miracle crop
nature has gifted us with a variety of
crops but only one
the humble soybean has earned the title
of miracle crop
what makes this plant so special to
begin with
soybeans are highly versatile which
means they can be grown
in a number of climate conditions and
consumed in different ways
when soybean seeds first arrived in
america from china
in the mid 18th century they were
planted for the purpose of making soy
sauce
during the civil war when coffee beans
were scarce
soldiers used soybeans to make a coffee
substitute
today's lesson is called soybeans
the
[Music]
miracle crop part one
hello everyone my name is jeff and
i'm mike yes soybeans they are a
miracle they're a gift from the heavens
or some god from god
all right so if we say something is a
miracle it's almost
magical it's amazing it's incredible
why are we talking about a bean as being
a miracle
crop well probably because soybeans
unlike some of those other lazier beans
that don't really
do very much is really great soybeans
can be used in
lots of different ways you know
white beans fava beans kidney beans
they're just
beans the soybean though it does more
than your average bean
okay it's pretty amazing we're gonna
read about it for two days
you couldn't read about green beans for
two days
if you're going to put it that way all
right yeah those other beans
are lazy i gotta try harder
anyways yes the soybean is very
versatile anyways let's go ahead and
start reading nature has gifted us
with a variety of crops
but only one the humble soybean has
earned the title of
[Music]
miracle crop crop
from god now
what makes this plant so
special i guess that's the question
of the day well we're going to find out
so yeah
what makes soybeans so special so much
of a miracle
it says well to begin with soybeans
are highly versatile or versatile as
some people
say what does that mean which means they
can be grown
in a number of climate conditions and
consumed in different ways so there you
go
two reasons why the soybean is so
great it can be grown in the number of
climate conditions basically you don't
need
perfect weather in only one part of the
world to grow
soybeans they can be grown all over the
place in rainy places
and dry places cool places warm places
and they can be consumed in different
ways we can use
soybeans of course when we talk about
consume
we talk about eating things you will
consume food
to give your body energy but we can also
use consume
when we talk about other things that we
use up cars
consume gasoline to give them energy if
you make a fire
you will be consuming wood to create the
flames in the heat
that make the fire so we're using the
using these
things up often in a way to make energy
or something like that so we're eating
soybeans but we're also
using them in other ways we'll find out
all about that
very soon but look at this word consume
in our example sentence which says
the average person consumes
over three grams of salt per day
so yeah we eat it and we use it in our
bodies
okay moving on yes when soybeans
seeds first arrived in america
from china in the mid 18th
century they were planted for the
purpose of making
soy sauce by the way i've heard
that the bean the soy bean actually got
its name
from the sauce and not the other way
around
oh interesting yes people made soy sauce
with this
plant and later on they said hey the
bean that we need
to make this sauce let's call it
the soybean because we make soy sauce
with it
very very interesting so there you go
people were putting that
wonderful salty black soy sauce on their
food a long time ago and then
about a hundred years later during the
civil war
when coffee beans were scarce soldiers
used soybeans to make a coffee
substitute so here's use number two a
time of war
often things become scarce they're hard
to find you can't get them so easily
soldiers still wanted some kind of
delicious drink
delicious hot drink they couldn't find
coffee beans so
they roasted up some soy beans and used
those to make
a coffee substitute something like
coffee
that they could drink with their
breakfast i don't think so
no it would be different there you go
use number two though of soybeans
already let's take a break and then
we'll be back
with more of the miracle crop hello
and beauty soybeans the
the film made him an international
superstar
and international superstar means
for the purpose of jasha means
elijah the event was held for the
purpose
of raising money for children with
cancer
without
soybeans the miracle crop the reputation
of soybeans as a miracle crop
took root in the early 1900s when their
many uses became known
the scientist george washington carver
discovered that soybeans
were a valuable source of protein and
oil
in the 1930s automobile producer henry
ford
even built cars with plastic made from
soybeans
okay these days soybeans have a
fantastic
reputation people think of them
as being a
a miracle crop a crop
from god now the reputation of soybeans
as a miracle crop took
root or this is where things got started
in the early 1900s when their
many uses became known
by the way your reputation is what
people commonly think of you okay
when someone mentions your name the
first
things that come into someone else's
mind about you
that's your reputation do they think
good things about you or bad things
about you
that is your reputation for example
reports that employees were treated
poorly
have ruined the company's reputation
before people
thought that they were really nice
people working there at that company but
it turns out that they were
really nasty to their employees so
people thought
you know what forget them they're in the
past
we don't like those people anymore their
reputation
is ruined forever okay
so the public doesn't think good things
about
that company but they do think good
things about soybeans now we saw early
on
soybeans were used to make soy sauce and
then kind of this
fake coffee but it was only about a
hundred years ago
that people really began to discover how
useful
soybeans were and there's one person in
particular
who was very interested in exploring the
uses of soybeans it says
the scientist george washington carver
discovered that soybeans were a valuable
source of protein
and oil ah things you might not think
about a bean you might
you know make something out of it eat it
put it in hot water
drink it but using it to make protein
you know as
as a way to give your body a lot of
healthy nutrients
it's just a bean it's not a big piece of
meat that's where you normally might get
protein from an
oil now that's totally different oil for
cooking or
oil for doing other things with and mike
it doesn't stop there
in the 1930s automobile producer
henry ford even built
cars with plastic
made from soybeans wow you could recycle
those cars
plastic or you could eat them or you
could eat them or make them into a
delicious coffee
that too possible all right folks with
that it's time for us to take a short
break but don't go away
we'll be right back
[Music]
foreign
soybeans the miracle crop after world
war ii
the united states became wealthier and
more people demanded meat on their
plates
to support this increased meat
production farmers used soybean meal to
feed their livestock
because of its cheap cost and high
protein content
all the while soy remained a steady part
of americans diets
though mostly in refined forms
okay let's move forward a little bit
after world war
ii the united states became wealthier
and more people demanded meat on their
plates
no more of these vegetables and potatoes
and such
i want meat we're wealthy now
give me meat yeah that's what they were
that's what they're demanding when you
demand something you
ask for something and you won't take no
for an
answer you're basically saying give this
to me
and if you don't well i won't be happy
about it right so people will demand
their rights
they will demand to speak to the manager
if they're really angry in a store and
they want to make a big complaint
or something like that they're not
saying please would you mind if you
ask the manager no i'm going to talk to
the manager you're going to
get them and i'm not going to leave till
it happens
that's what they're demanding so people
you know back then they had a bit more
money
and they said you know growing up i only
ate chicken once a year
but now i want steak every day and if
you don't give me steak i'm going to
ask for it again basically shop that
pork shop's okay too
so anyway people wanted more meat there
was a huge
demand for it or a very a large
group of people were saying this is what
we want please bring it to us
for example rory complained that his new
girlfriend demands
constant attention anyways back to
the soybean now to support this
increased meat production remember
everybody in america wanted me
to support this increased meat
production
farmers used soybean
meal to feed their livestock
because of its cheap cost and
high protein content how about
that by the way production that's the
noun
that comes from the verb produce when
you
produce something you make something
usually
in large numbers okay production is the
act of making or producing stuff that's
all there is to it for example
global steel production fell
in the first three months of 2020
people weren't making that much steel oh
okay
but they were making a lot of meat back
during the time
after the war so of course they needed a
lot of livestock
pigs and cows and you know animals to
make the meat and when we talk about
soybean
meal here we're not using meal like
breakfast
lunch dinner these are the meals you
might eat here we're talking about
prepared food
that we feed to farm animals that's the
kind of
meal we're talking about here so
basically they were using soybean
to feed to pigs and cows and things like
that it was
cheap and it had a high protein content
all right protein is something good that
we get in our food in
in meat we might have vitamin content
in vegetables and fruits and things like
that so what is content
it's an amount of something inside
of something else basically if you talk
about this thing
what is inside it what is it all made up
of
that is the content so we can talk about
the content of food
in terms of protein and vitamins and
minerals
we could talk about the content of a
book about oh it's a it's an adventure
book for children with lots of magic and
and exciting scenes that's the content
that's what's
inside this thing for example when we
get back to the uh
the idea of food content nuts have a
high
fat content so they provide a lot of
energy
that's why nuts can be quite healthy but
also fatty
anyways all the while soy remained
a steady part of americans
diets though mostly
in refined form so they're not just
eating bowls of soybeans eating boy
they were not eating bowls of soybeans
they were
eating soy but in refined
forms how interesting all right folks
that's it for today's lesson
and it's time for us to say bye
bye go get some soy sauce
pam spent 20 minutes looking for her
sunglasses
and then realized that she had been
wearing them on top of her head
all the while
remains done
[Music]
put on your seat belt we are going on a
road trip
across america on route 66
we'll start driving in chicago illinois
and
end up in santa monica california
that's almost 4 000 kilometers of road
besides illinois and california route
66 goes through six other states
they are missouri kansas oklahoma
texas new mexico and arizona
there are lots of stops along the way to
visit attractions
of course we'll need to see the grand
canyon in arizona
i would like to visit some old caves in
new mexico too
i think we could cover around 300
kilometers a day
that way we will finish our journey in
less than two weeks
we're lucky to have this fine spring
weather
in the winter it can snow in illinois
in the summer the dry heat of arizona
and new mexico can be terrible
so if you're ready let's go
here is more information
entrepreneur this successful
entrepreneur is very rich
historic july 4th 1776
was a historic day for the usa
marker the marker shows how many miles
we've walked
monumental her monumental work
has changed science forever
numerical the scientist used
lots of numerical information
order please put these books in
the correct order
pleasant this music is
very pleasant
pronounce do you know how to
pronounce this word
remain tom's mother remained by his side
while he was sick
souvenir rita brought home many
souvenirs from europe
did you learn something new today i hope
you did
thanks for watching and we'll see you
again later
do next time