[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hello
everybody i'm shane
today we're looking at part two of i can
do it i'm batman
and the vocabulary words are capable
capable patrick thinks that his son is
a very capable young man phenomenon
phenomenon last night i saw an unusual
phenomenon
bright lights in the sky above my house
wow
ufo nervous nervous
joy is feeling nervous about her big
speech tomorrow
confidence confidence chris lacks
confidence
so he doesn't often speak up in class
advantage advantage kyle took advantage
of the
great weather and did some gardening
so we're still talking about this batman
effect you know
thinking that you are a superhero or
something
yeah i think now a lot of people do this
for example beyonce yeah
beyonce did this uh she pretended
to be a person she invented that's right
called sasha fierce
because i think she was a little bit
nervous about performing in front of a
large crowd right yeah because you'll
have stage fright
right but she imagined to be that person
instead of focusing on herself
that's right because she has
insecurities or she might think she has
some weaknesses or
she might fail she takes herself out of
her
body and puts it into this very
character
yeah do you ever do that
in fact i really do do this i do this
i'll think of like
mentors that i have like my father or
somebody like that
and i will imagine to myself what would
he do
in this situation and because you know
mentors to you are kind of like
superheroes like role models superheroes
right so
you think well if they could do it then
i could do it right and it makes you
just feel like okay
it's possible that just proves that your
mind can be
really really powerful it's definitely
true that's the point
exactly and believe in yourself that's
right okay
enjoy today's lesson enjoy it whoever
you are
i can do it i'm batman the batman effect
works by allowing people to distance
themselves from their negative
emotions by pretending they are someone
highly capable
people in high stress situations are
able to better persevere through
challenges
[Music]
today's lesson is called i can do it
i'm batman part two hello everyone my
name is jeff
and i'm mike and it might sound crazy
but yes you can do it
you are batman or you can do it if you
think you are batman as we learned
yesterday a psychological study with a
group of kids
found that when they're asked to do
something difficult
the kids who believed that they could
because they're
batman they did much better and they
worked much harder
than the kids who just thought of
themselves in good ways
but not as a superhero or someone
amazing
like batman so believe you're batman
you'll do better
the batman effect it's a thing backed
by science amazing amazing the batman
effect by the way
works by allowing people to
distance themselves from their negative
emotions they're not thinking oh
i'm just i'm i did badly
i did badly i make mistakes all the time
they're thinking
i'm batman i'm not i'm not gonna take a
break a break does batman
take breaks no way we're gonna get to
the bottom of this
now cause i'm batman i'm batman
exactly and of course batman works hard
he doesn't take breaks and he's really
good
right he always wins he always finds a
way to fight through
so by pretending they are someone highly
capable people in high stress situations
are able to better
persevere through challenges they won't
give up they'll
fight on they'll continue working
they'll persevere
even through difficult things even
through a challenge you believe
that you can do it you have the skills
the talent
everything you need you are highly
capable you can do it
even if you might not be you believe in
yourself
batman believes in himself hey
i believe in myself i'm batman you're
batman anyways
if you're a capable person that means
that you can
do stuff you are able to do things okay
my daughter she now plays the piano she
is now
capable of playing the piano can do it
there you go she has that
ability okay she can do it for example
patr patrick thinks that his son is a
very
capable young man that this person this
young man can do
a lot of stuff has very many has a lot
of
capabilities i should say all right
folks with that it's time for us to take
a break but don't go away
we'll be back after this
i can do it i'm batman one famous
example of someone making use of this
phenomenon
is the pop star beyonce in the early
days of her
career beyonce would feel nervous about
performing in front of people
to deal with this she'd often imagine
herself as a super confident singer
named
sasha fierce as sasha fierce
she could perform with all the
confidence she didn't believe herself to
have
and now she's one of the most celebrated
live performers in the world
[Music]
okay one famous example of someone
making use of this phenomenon
is the pop star beyonce
batman well we'll learn
more about we'll learn more about that
later on
but yes you might think no one actually
uses this no there are pop stars who use
this
technique they don't say i'm batman
let's say
but they might use this technique they
might use
a technique like this to distance
themselves
from their negative emotions ah
interesting and when we talk about a
phenomenon we're talking about something
that is
kind of a strange occurrence but it
might be
real it probably is real but it's kind
of unusual the kind of thing that you
would first read about or hear about and
go that can't be true
that can't be real but it is real for
example you know
the northern lights is one of those
amazing natural
phenomenon it doesn't happen all the
time it's kind of mysterious and strange
how it happens
but it does actually happen it actually
has
you know a reason in science for this to
go on but still
it seems very unusual like the batman
effect if you just read about this you'd
go come on
but if you read the studies and the
research you find out
no it's real it's just very unusual
for example last night i saw an unusual
phenomenon
bright lights in the sky above my house
okay in the early days of her career
right beyonce would feel nervous
about performing in front of people
stage fright yeah
even the queen bee there she felt
nervous in front of a large group of
people
if you are nervous you are on edge
you're
anxious you're worried you're really
jittery i know that here in taiwan
people are really nervous about
giving presentations where they have to
talk in front of many
people it makes them very nervous very
uncomfortable for example joy is feeling
nervous about her big speech tomorrow
she doesn't want to
embarrass herself or something like that
she just doesn't want to make a fool of
herself in front of a lot
of people so beyonce
yeah even queen bee herself
she used the batman effect to her
advantage yeah as you said people are
nervous in taiwan all around the world
about
speaking in front of people or even
artists
well-known artists get stage fright they
get nervous about performing
dancing singing playing their instrument
in front of an audience so to deal with
this
she that's beyonce to deal with this
she'd often
imagine herself as a super confident
singer named sasha fierce
interesting so she kind of turned
herself into a superhero
but not a superhero just a different
person with a lot of confidence
and a different name same effect
as sasha fierce she could perform with
all the confidence she didn't believe
herself
to have beyonce doesn't have this this
confidence
beyonce is nervous sasha fierce she
could walk through a brick wall she's so
confident and powerful
getting rid of she got rid of those
negative emotions
and all that was left was that
confidence
yeah that's right she got rid of that
negative emotions by pretending to be
a different more capable person and use
as you said it gave her confidence
confidence is when you believe in
yourself
you believe that you can do it you
believe in your skills and your talents
you believe in your training and your
knowledge as well but you're not like i
can't
no you're like i can it might be
difficult but
i can do it i believe in myself i have
confidence
for example chris lacks confidence
so he doesn't often speak up in class he
gets
nervous he doesn't have what if i say
the wrong
thing or ask a stupid question or you
know he doesn't believe
himself he lacks confidence so did it
work for beyonce
i i think i think i think so yeah are
you kidding
and famous and now she's one of the most
celebrated live performers in the
world i think i've seen her full stop
yeah
all right everyone everyone let's go
ahead and take a short break but
don't go away we'll be back after this
thank you
[Music]
a super confident singer named
shimoshima shijonjigan named shiyo who
is named jinhua
means
i'm kind of
dana is looking at a portrait that was
painted by a local artist dina jones
that was painted by a local artist
that was painted
dana is looking at a portrait painted by
a local artist
i can do it i'm batman if we take
advantage of the batman effect
then we should all be able to improve
our performance
what's more there's no reason to limit
yourself to just
one other identity if you're facing a
personal difficulty temporarily take on
the identity of a wise family member
if you're running a race perhaps imagine
yourself as usain bolt
the legendary sprinter choose whatever
identity is best for the task at hand
with just a little creative thinking
every one of us can become
a little more like the person we wish to
be
[Music]
okay if we take advantage of the batman
effect
then we should all be able to
improve our performance so there you go
if you think you are
lagging behind in school or at work
take advantage of the batman effect or
the sasha fierce effect
say i'm batman or say i'm sasha fierce
okay take advantage of this and
improve your performance anyways here we
have this word
advantage okay if you take advantage of
a situation
okay you exploit it you get the most
out of it that you can okay you take as
much benefit from it
as you can now you can exploit
or take advantage of situations but you
shouldn't take advantage of
people a small note there for example
kyle took advantage of the great weather
and did some gardening there you go
i've got a great day so i'm going to do
me some
gardening i'm going to get as much
benefit from this day
as is humanly possible gardening wise
all right then so yeah an advantage can
be something that
makes you better able to compete gives
you an edge
but also when we use it this way take
advantage
of we're using something to give us that
edge
all right very cool so yeah take
advantage of the batman effect let's
move on and see what it says next what's
more
there's more to it there's no reason to
limit yourself
to just one other identity ah so if it's
a
tough challenge you're batman if it's a
problem of feeling nervous in front of
people
you're sasha fierce you can change it
depending
on the situation be whoever you want
whoever helps you
fight that battle that you're facing if
you're facing a personal difficulty
temporarily take on the identity of a
wise
family member oh it's a difficult choice
what should i do
what would my grandmother do what would
my grandfather do
use their wisdom or let's say
you're running a race perhaps imagine
yourself as usain bolt
the legendary sprinter probably as fast
as him
probably one of the greatest runners of
all time
i'm using bolt and there you go you
run run run yourself to the front of
the pack but you have to eat chicken
nuggets first because he always used to
do that
anyways let's go ahead and move on
choose whatever identity is best
for the task at hand with just a little
creative thinking
every one of us can become a little more
like the person
we wish to be again though we're not
trying to
become batman we're just trying to
distance ourselves
from negative emotions
that's the true point here anyways
mike do you think you'd be interested
in making use of the batman effect in
your daily life
or if you already use it
how do you feel about it that's very
interesting well i've never really used
the batman effect before but you know if
i'm physically tired i might think of
people in
in history who are physically tired but
kept on going
you know so if it's at the end of a long
day and i didn't sleep well
i might think of an explorer shackleton
wandering through the desert or across
the ice with heavy loads on their back
and think well that guy walked for
five days with no rest i can make it to
this evening
so you know that kind of thing it's kind
of a way of saying you know
i might be bad now but it could be a lot
worse
it's a different way of thinking about
it but still it gives you that
motivation
to keep on going i like it all right
folks
that's it for us and it's time for us to
say
bye-bye take care of
the leads
she can whip up a meal with whatever
ingredients
are left in the fridge taken
[Music]
welcome to niagara falls
i hope you like water because we have a
lot of it here
this place is called niagara falls
because it is
actually made up of three waterfalls
there is also an island between two of
the falls it's called
goat island no there are no goats there
the island got its name after a man
named john steadman
brought his goats to the island stedman
brought his goats there
to protect them from wolves but the cold
winter
killed most of steadman's goats when
british soldiers heard this story
they called the island goat island
here's another interesting fact about
niagara falls
in 2012 a man named nick
wallenda walked on a rope across
the falls since niagara falls is located
on the border
between the united states and canada
wallenda
had to present his passport when he
arrived on the canadian side
isn't that funny here is more
information
waterfall that river comes down in a
waterfall
off the cliff border
this train will cross the border between
china
and india glacier
these glaciers are made of layers of
solid ice
hydropower hydropower is produced by the
energy of falling water
or fast running water
drain the men used a big pipe to
drain the water from the pool and then
cleaned it
separate the two countries are separated
by a tall mountain
erosion soil erosion
by rain in this city is very serious
veil the bride's face was
covered by a white veil
missed the small village
disappeared in the mist
preservation the students are working
for
environmental preservation
today's lesson was quite fascinating
right
i know i thought so well we hope to see
you here again
next time