[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen hello
Wonder Woman Wonder Man Shane today
we're looking at part two of gal gadot a
wonder of a woman and the vocabulary
words are household household the
designer is quickly becoming a household
name globally globally Saturdays concert
will be broadcast globally promote
promote the organization put up posters
around town to promote awareness of
climate change access access various
politicians have promised the country's
citizens better access to medical care
fund fund Rodger lacked the funds needed
to buy the apartment so we're still
talking about this beautiful talented
actress gal gadot that's not an easy
name to pronounce it only took me a few
practice get her name right gal deduct
yeah but we know her as Wonder Woman
that's right she really is a wonder of a
woman so she's made a lot of money she
was one of the highest-paid female
actors for playing in Wonder Woman right
but she is using her fame and her money
actually to help underprivileged
children right with equal access to
education right mm-hmm she's also a
mother of two I didn't know that when
you see her you wouldn't think that well
she's already a mother she's in such
great shape yeah and she's so young
still isn't she she looks really young
yeah definitely she looks really
children already
so there's a new movie that she's going
to be in right mm-hmm
Wonder Woman 1984 I'm so excited I'm
definitely going to see it so it's gonna
be a little bit retro back in the 1980s
I love movies that are set in the 1980s
because I grew up in the 1980s
ah that's right so I'm really looking
forward to this one me too okay well
let's learn more about Wonder Woman and
then go see her on the big screen next
month definitely enjoy enjoy gal gadot a
wonder of a woman Wonder Woman broke box
office records and turned gadot into a
household name she became one of the
highest-paid actresses globally and
landed a spot on Times list of the
world's 100 most influential people
garage used her fame to work with
pencils of promise an organization
promoting equal access to education for
children as a mother of two it should
come as no surprise that she is using
her fame to raise funds to build schools
in underprivileged areas around the
world
[Music]
today's lesson is called gal gadot a
wonder of a woman part 2 hello everyone
my name is Jeff and I'm Mike in yes
we're learning about the well-known
actress gal gadot mostly known to around
the world as Wonder Woman these days but
she's been acting for quite a while did
you know she was in the original Fast &
Furious movie back in 2009 so it might
seem like she just appeared on the scene
but she's actually been in been in big
Hollywood movies for a while but she
started her life in Israel joined the
military became a instructor and then
when she left she became a model and
then an actress so today we're gonna be
learning more about her now and into the
future especially her relationship to
this great Wonder Woman film franchise
there you go Wonder Woman Wonder Woman
the movie broke box office records and
turned gadot into a household name so
before Hey
she was relatively famous a little bit
filming a little bit a little bit famous
I should say she had been in some big
movies but Wonder Woman took her to that
next level of Fame mmm that's right it
turned her into a household name we used
this phrase yesterday basically when we
call someone a household name we mean
that they are so well known that
everyone has heard of this person
everyone in your household now the idea
here being is that there are probably a
few generations in your household things
that your parents know famous names that
your parents know might not be known to
the kids or the grandparents and vice
versa but if someone is a household name
that means everyone is her has heard of
this thing even if they're not that the
right age or if they're not a big fan or
something like that
it's just so well known for example the
designer is quickly becoming a household
name something like Coco Chanel would be
a household name as opposed to some of
the more unknown or younger designers
pretty much everybody everybody no
matter who
everywhere around the globe that's right
you know about her she's a household
name now yes she has reached that level
of fame and there's more she became one
of the highest-paid actresses globally
all around the world and landed a spot
on Times list of the world's 100 most
influential people how about that now
here we have the adverb globally let's
say you are globally famous you are
known the world over yes you're a
household name everybody knows your name
no matter where in the world you are no
matter where on the globe you are for
example Saturday's concert will be
broadcast globally all around the world
there you go and so what has she used
this Fame for how has she used her
influence it sells gadot used her fame
to work with pencils of promise an
organization promoting equal access to
education for children this sounds like
a great organization this is probably a
charity it's probably safe to bet that
pencils for promise this organization is
a charity and they work to promote
access to education for kids getting
more kids in school is always a good
thing and I would promote that any day
to promote something it's kind of like
to advertise you're bringing attention
to something companies will promote new
products in the same way that they
advertise new products if you're
supporting something you're promoting it
maybe your friend is opening a business
and you're helping them give out flyers
or put up signs or something like that
or maybe it's just something that you
believe in maybe you've decided to
become vegan and stop eating meat and
you work with other groups or other
friends to promote the idea of eating
meat-free talking about how good it is
and getting other people to try it out
or at least learn about it
for example the organization put up
posters around town to promote awareness
of climate change they think it's
important and they want more attention
to be paid on paid to it there
now we also have the word access to talk
about here it's being used as a noun if
you have access to something you can use
that thing it is available to you okay
it's easy to get to that's all there is
to it now if you access something you
can use this word as a verb too when you
access something you do something so as
to be able to use that thing so access
is when you can use that thing but when
you are using that thing you can be said
to be accessing that thing for example
various politicians have promised the
country's citizens better access to
medical care so so before maybe it
wasn't easy to get that metal medical
care now it's going to be easy to get
that okay and we use that medical care
mm-hmm pencils of promise of course
bringing education to kids is a really
good thing and I think almost anyone
would agree to that but if you're like
gal gadot maybe there's a slightly more
personal reason you want to promote
education and children we read as a
mother of two it should come as no
surprise that she is using her fame to
raise funds to build schools in
underprivileged areas around the world
yeah everyone can agree that kids need
education poor kids more than most but
if you're a mother if you have your own
kids and you're thinking about their
education and then you look at similar
kids who just don't have the money and
think it's unfair that they can't have
an education then that you know might
push you to use your influence to
promote this and to raise funds to help
out to because what to charities need
charities need money and what our funds
funds are money that's basically all it
is this is a noun form we generally use
an S because having a fund is doesn't
really make a lot of sense in this kind
of way and if you want to do something
you need lots of money so you're gonna
raise lots of funds or just funds in
general you're gonna raise money in
order to do something funds or the money
you use in order to do something for
example Roger lacked the funds needed to
buy the apartment
didn't have enough money to buy the
apart couldn't afford it that's it
anyways folks with that it's time for us
to take a break but don't go away right
back after this tahini jp1008 carretera
shootout show me the culture and how
English a mini-challenge a search on
yahoo Chaudron potential essential sure
you check all the news injury yet on
shankazute at a church in Jupiter you're
in shock video oh how knowledge and I
can the pansy household household
packing machine chatting the ji-yong de
was actually mentioned to Jerry who
shall de household name to such a short
time you who shouts also change the
trimming the who horseshoe in sound
camera it could telling me a comma or
the Sunita junior summer pop one night
pay no tsuita da-da-da-da-da means the
super sad face on Yamuna hanim ago buoy
globally bigger food citizen chhoti
hamburger each other - Bianca hides the
man nutrition which I attribute on earth
on the show children : Tay da Shaw Tammy
on Z dimension going to your church in
her thumbprint and showed her the truth
hurts or sachiko deep in quantity like
more plantation shop how when John
yonder under privileged position on pink
Wanda Raja Rasheeda non-terminal Stanga
bands
promote promote pashutin search in
p-chan
access access resident down means day on
zhongshan
or associated gene rule take a take a
dong dong say / - Jung ho chi what is
the change in gene rule not that I can
fund fund happy I should teaching OSHA -
gene - Adam means tobacco and John gal
gadot a wonder of a woman recently gadot
reprised the role that made her famous
in the latest Wonder Woman movie
Wonder Woman 1984 however in addition to
her superhero duties she has started
working as a producer with her own
production company among other projects
the company is adapting the life stories
of several strong women throughout
history such as Irena Sendler a Polish
social worker who saved dozens of
Jewish children from the Holocaust gadot
will perform in these projects to
continue as an example for women and
girls around the world ok let's start to
learn about Wonder Woman - the sequel to
the first Wonder Woman movie yeah
recently gadot reprised the role the
role of Wonder Woman she reprised or
played again the role that made her
famous in the latest Wonder Woman movie
Wonder Woman
1984 so it's not going by the title
Wonder Woman - it's going by this title
Wonder Woman
1984 which leads me to believe that this
movie takes place in 1984
yeah or we've missed a whole lot of
seagulls yeah I don't think this is the
1984 this it's most definitely not so
it's set in the year 1984 cool lots of
great 80s music and fashions however in
addition to her superhero duties she gal
gadot she has started working as a
producer with her own production company
yeah a lot of Hollywood actors are doing
this these days when they get some power
and money they often use it to do really
good things like making good films I
think Margot Robbie is a good example of
that I'm gonna do good things with my
pal with my power and money yeah well
they'll make you know interesting movies
and not all just superhero epics and I
think Margot Robbie is a good example
young talented actor has now become a
successful producer and what kind of
project is gal gadot interested in doing
with her production company it says
among other projects the company is
adapting the life stories of several
strong women throughout history such as
Irena Sendler a Polish social worker who
saved dozens of Jewish children from the
Holocaust wow that is really really cool
so hopefully we're gonna get a
collection or a series of movies about
these interesting strong but kind of
unknown
women throughout history like this great
hero Irena Sendler she was a Polish
person but she saved Jewish kids from
the the Nazis of course during World War
two
never heard of her but I'm sure it would
make an amazing story
now why is gal gadot doing this
specifically well it says here that
gadot will perform in these projects to
continue as an example for women and
girls around the world so there you go
gadot she's gonna make quite the idol
for women and girls the world over war
globally
all right folks with that it's time for
us to take a break but don't go away
we'll be back soon
Sarah Bush in the mini challenge as an
EHR and Ito passes the mock ariados ha
tadashii in Sri Lanka Chum in the
chaozhong Java truth is even a higher K
she said to see the Chilean consulate
annainsea Joran yes reetahan situations
if you can see her chocha machine you're
eating a burrito that penetrates out in
english supership how commando hadashah
tanning internship in concert on a
condition see where change hands in the
show mean
she's a machine John Chancellor so much
on the charts in Soma shank al Haddad
she's only way no shootin Todd who shot
Ando
shangela shoe shaming you're tired on
the pole and Schillinger parents are
gonna wait Asia try and Angela yen-chu
situation chickadee the phone in hand
inhaler show liebe yeah hey Tod Capuchin
turns Jewish Jewish sushi no no tyrant
Holocaust Holocaust Papa Parkway motor
home it down hard social H - E - oh the
Holocaust
Toby gon today its associated incision
not say - yo tyranny petrucha Hunnam
Gallaher showdown tsukushi-chan Minister
ethics with epi see epic a countdown
means like a - a hidden sensation ship
and the hoja heard back way more the
Seahawk oh and Joe gal gadot a wonder of
a woman gal gadot didn't start out
trying to become a star
but it's a good thing that she did with
her strength and kind heart this wonder
of a woman is just the kind of role
model we need today okay everyone let's
start to wrap up our article on gal
gadot gal gadot didn't start out trying
to become a star but it's a good thing
that she did okay so not only is she a
great star a great actress but her fame
she's used it in a really good way yeah
exactly with her strength and kind heart
this wonder of a woman is just the kind
of role model we need today so she's not
just selling luxury products and hanging
out with celebrities on expensive yachts
she's using her power and her money to
do really good things because not
everyone uses their power and money to
do good things sometimes they just kind
of waste it so there you go well done
gal gadot we look forward to those
movies both Wonder Woman and actually
I'm more interested in the movies she'll
make with her own company those sound
really cool here's our what do you think
question sir what is the question for
today Mike yes what qualities make gal
gadot a great role model and you can't
say Wow oh then I can't oh no I know
several qualities make her a great role
model first she's not your typical
Hollywood person who's only concerned
with right and she wants to give back to
the community she's working with a
charity that I'd say is a great charity
because they actually you know you can
see the work they do it's not just sort
of giving money to some big charity and
it kind of gets lost already that too
but I think pencils for kids and buying
books for kids and building schools and
poor areas that will actually you'll see
some good effects of that so I think
that's another good quality she's
working with good charities that are
doing real work these days sounds off
with her power and motor power and money
anyways folks with that our
is now in the books and it's time for us
to say bye bye take care the main canal
carriage a dirty notes retreat our
hostel apartment I am Merida ypr book an
Italian hina khawaja hey Shan Shan Shan
Shan Shan Shan Shan Shan yeah
Liang to deliver on channel machine my
way to the city enriched with a fan
brush will do have the means huge song
reaches over sure to the pin pyre
cogitation me and reached an IOT
translator how Michael chika young does
bigger celebrity tickets Cele BR ity
celebrity p.m. million tonne challenger
media the Mineral Show charming mil
hyoyoung Tao yacht why a CHT yet Tapia
she wrote in quietly how everyone went
wrong on the role model Tasha Jamal
fantasy Park Jung Nam a transgender
communities okay Michelle
[Music]
so John how is your handi fine Joe
Campbell one fat diamond see now just
how far John been yo Sangha bigger
should come as no surprise the Ergo
should in addition to this anger should
start out the East Java house Li should
come as no surprise come ass
Juho Chong Chong Wei Jia surprise jr.
relief Quan way have blowed that eating
the lemon soo Jung Hwan me I'll show
more grand 30 mo shooting the fun ain't
shall come as a surprise trip reassured
in Virginia Jaron Thea poignancy
naturally come as no surprise to be a
ruling renting ya say you know Jojo
little dana sings as well as a
professional singer it comes as no
surprise that she won the singing
competition Dana chunga Changa country
ago so yaha tying the bill chumpies I
think bullying run you like to say evil
Jojo how did Elijah in addition to pages
it's in addition to happy I should show
me show me UI hides and ya Joe Gunn
besides is the Shang home not ji ho Xiao
Jia means the hodo means little
I'd like a cheeseburger in addition to
french fries Chillicothe Ohio cheese
Tampa cognitive halation start out the
East hanyong fact danger about cash cash
it's home
namaho Mina hi Katie salmon's la da da
Shi Jiu Jitsu mia
social mission mikazuchi how start out
homie acadia tones ing la da da it has
Joshua mojo Jung tae ho zoom
oh nan let's all go legit they
started out as coworkers but later
became close friends communication
shuttle shoot-down holy Chandler
changing the poyo so Shah Jahan so today
et je t'ai chi hazy huh no matter the
young fashion wipe out that sheet um
who's your trophy home in case you on
something right dog legit if we start
out at 6 a.m. we should get there by
noon Rugel Menzel million trova in get
Jones's change ok done a lilo how he
sounds Johnny and gentlemen I'm a sassy
jela
[Music]
[Laughter]
[Applause]
that's the video that's hilarious
can you send that to me all right
hilarious
and how young so manly man eating 10
chappathis wall tile shower that's
what's a penthouse yeah hey cuz a new
bird oh oh very funny very funny very
funny
because it will be like go ahead god
yeah Bishop Carroll County certain
attention young young hilarious
hilarious aunt what's up no you're not
hilarious your pronunciation is great
okay jeong-ho tell her she's a woman
kpop funny to Hunter and hilarious yeah
[Applause]
okay you could say that's what the
funniest thing ever okay funny yes just
a fun yet that Psychology Today holiday
they say how shall not means ho means
that I can ever doesn't have a shower
though she got a quad John Cazale quad
time face any better that's the funniest
thing since yesterday that's the
funniest thing today
don't milk few turds a good house shop
laughing my head off eating the Apple
haha we're going to tell Jenna ship yeah
actually it's kind of funny pretty
hilarious
no yes okay okay
awkward said anyway anyway through a
pony by England your wouldn't either hot
woman dreaded boy shown you know for
sure that's not hilarious this is very
serious will take your learning very
seriously okay so if you need help with
your English okay that's hilarious
that's hilarious that's the funniest
thing ever that's the funniest thing
ever
I'm laughing my head off I'm laughing my
head off
[Music]