[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody i'm shane
today we're looking at part two of the
duck-billed platypus
the impossible animal and the vocabulary
words are
dive dive great white sharks can
dive to depths of one thousand and two
hundred meters
electrical electrical one way to produce
electrical energy is to burn coal
signal signal in 1977
a scientist received a powerful signal
from space
that has not been detected since
scoop scoop tom scooped up some rocks
with his hand
and threw them into the river hmm crush
crush to make wine the traditional way
you need to first crush the grapes with
your feet
chris i guess you don't like wine
but i like the duck-billed platypus do
you
because they are really really unique
they're super
cute right yes they are and but you
wouldn't think that they're
meat eaters would you i guess i wouldn't
you're right but they eat they are meat
eaters yeah so they're
carnivores right they eat meat and they
actually hunt at night under water
under water wow so they're nocturnal
animals they go
underwater but the interesting thing is
they keep their eyes
and their noses shut right so if they go
underwater
and their eyes are closed how do they
see what they're trying to catch
i think they can send uh they can sense
the electrical
what is it what is it the electrical
signals from that's right
from like you know maybe like a worm
underwater tasty worm or something
like a shellfish and then they would
just scoop it up with their bill
and they get all the mud and the rocks
and everything
then they bring that back to the shore
and then they'll use those rocks
to crush things like to shellfish that's
right so that they can eat the meat out
of it
because they don't have teeth they don't
have meat seeds so they just
swallow it down that's pretty cool such
an interesting animal i have never heard
of any animals like that
it's pretty cool let's learn more about
the duck-billed platypus
all right
the duck-billed platypus the impossible
animal
you might be surprised to learn that
platypuses are meat eaters that hunt for
their food underwater
they like to snack on worms insects and
shellfish
and spend up to 12 hours a day on the
hunt mostly in rivers and wetlands
today's lesson is called the duck-billed
platypus
the impossible animal
part two hello everyone i
am jeff and i'm mike and we actually
know that this title
isn't really telling us the truth it is
a possible animal
the duckbilled platypus the really weird
animal that exists would be a little
more accurate but it does almost
seem impossible especially when we learn
not i mean not only does it look
strange you can see a picture of it
there in your magazine i'm sure not only
does it look strange but
we learned yesterday that it actually
has genes from
all different types of animals mixed in
and this all happened 166 million years
ago
it almost does seem like nature just
decided to play a joke one day
and said i'm going to make this animal
that totally breaks all the rules but
it's real well it's a unique answer it's
a very weird
special that followed its very own
unique genetic path to where it is
right in one little corner of the world
one little corner of the world now you
might be surprised to learn
that platypuses are meat eaters
really that hunt for their food
under water ducks use that kind of mouth
to eat
weeds and grass and stuff they don't
hunt with them not the duck build
platypus
they like to snack on worms insects and
shellfish and spend up to
12 hours a day on the hunt
mostly in rivers and wetlands
so they hunt most of the time they do
they're busy little animals and of
course they have to probably eat a lot
of those
little worms insects shellfish animals
they might find in
rivers lakes ponds wetlands places like
that so
they spend most of their time in water
they aren't in the ocean
right they're in fresh water rivers and
wetlands not in
seas and oceans giving us an idea of you
know what they eat
where they live their habitat and their
environment let's take a break and then
we'll be back with more about the
duckbill
platypus hello
the duck-billed platypus the impossible
animal
platypuses do their hunting at night
they dive under the water for a minute
or two at a time
paddling with their front feet and
steering with their back feet
and tail while searching for food
strangely during the entire time they
are underwater
their eyes ears and noses are shut tight
so how do they find their food
okay before the break we learned that
platypuses
hunt they hunt a lot they hunt like
12 hours a day but get this
platypuses do their hunting
at night they are nocturnal
interesting so they're hunting 12 hours
a day
but most of that is actually in the dark
as you say at night so how do they do
this
how do they hunt for those worms and
insects and shellfish in
rivers and wetlands they dive under the
water for a
minute or two at a time paddling with
their front feet
and steering with their back feet and
tail
while searching for food okay well that
sounds kind of
like it would make sense if you look at
their bodies they have those
those feet for paddling and then the
back legs and the tail like an otter
do some of the steering or like a beaver
do some of the steering and of course if
they're eating shellfish and
things like that they will definitely
have to dive what is it to dive
to dive in in the case of a platypus is
basically to go
down in the water so you're swimming in
the water
you see something interesting at the
bottom of the lake or the river
and then you dive down to get it you
could do that if you're swimming or
with people or certain types of birds or
ducks
they might also be outside of the water
and go
head first down into the waters but if
you're in the water
and you're just moving downwards you're
diving as well like a shark
great white sharks can dive to depths
of 1200 meters below the surface of the
water wow
they can swim really deep under the
water there but amazing platypuses don't
worry about that
anyways strangely during the entire time
they are
under water their eyes ears
and noses are shut tight
apparently the platypuses don't use
any of their senses in order to hunt
yes they shut their eyes they shut their
ears
and they shut their noses they don't
smell
they don't hear they don't see so how do
they find their food
so how do they find their food that is
the question and we'll
answer that question
right after a break radar we'll see you
after that
mites
shot
h-e-a-d
some people listen to music while they
study keiji huacha
some people listen to music while
studying
on the hunt
scientists are searching for a cure for
the disease
the duck-billed platypus the impossible
animal
the answer lies in the platypus's bill
which can sense tiny electrical signals
set off by the movements of other living
creatures
once the platypus senses a tasty worm or
insect
it scoops it up in its bill along with
the surrounding mud
and small stones and heads back to the
surface
there it uses the stones to crush the
food in its mouth
before swallowing it because platypuses
don't have teeth
one might say this strange little animal
is living proof
that truth is stranger than fiction
all right let's say i'm hunting in the
water
i would generally keep my eyes open so
that i can see
sure uh and let's say i could somehow
smell
in the water sharks do shark smell i
would keep my nose open
sure same thing goes with the ears i
would want to hear
the platypus does none of these things
the platypus
closes its eyes nose and ears when
hunting well so how does it find prey
the answer lies in the platypus's
bill oh that big duck-shaped mouth
type thing that it has the thing that
goes quack on a duck
right well i guess it makes sense it's
hunting at night so the eyes wouldn't
work
very well especially in a river and of
course it's an
air-breathing animal so it has to close
its nose and not breathe in water so
yeah
the bill that big mouth part that's how
it hunts
how exactly the answer lies in the
platypus's bill
which can sense tiny electrical
signals set off by the movements of
other living creatures that is
absolutely incredible i think sharks
have something
similar they have sensors down their
whole body which can pick up the
movement
of animals far away so it doesn't have
to see them or smell them but
still electrical signals that it can
sense
humans we don't have any kind of ability
like this
we can't really sense electrical signals
now here electrical means
ever having to do with electricity
but yes we use electricity on a daily
basis
when you plug your phone into the wall
to charge your battery you're using
electricity you've got a device it's an
electrical device
and it charges your phone with
electricity and yes
animals do get let off electrical
signals
and apparently the duckbill platypus is
able to
pick up on them how cool is that for
example
one way to produce electrical energy
is to burn coal it's not a clean way of
making electricity but
you can make electrical energy in that
way
anyway let's move on the next vocabulary
word
is the word signal that's right what is
a signal basically a
signal is some kind of energy that
carries
data or information when we think of
signals the easiest thing to think of is
how your cell phone works or how a radio
works
there are those radio waves coming
around there are the cell phone towers
sending signals or wi-fi or internet
things like that and you have some
machine that can turn that
energy in the air into some kind of
information into the noise coming from a
radio
into the call or the email that comes to
your phone
or something like that so it's that
energy out there that's carrying data or
information of some kind for example in
a scientist received a powerful signal
from
space that has not been detected
since wow what was that could have been
aliens or it could have just been a star
letting off
energy in some kind of unusual way
or a space traveling duck build platypus
no it wasn't not likely no it wasn't it
could
that would actually be impossible okay
once the platypus senses a tasty wormer
insect not in space it scoops it up and
it's
built along with the surrounding mud and
small stones
and heads back to the surface by the way
to scoop is to pick something
up with a circular kind of a circular
spoon like
entity so here that bill it might have a
bit of a
circular surface on it and it can scoop
up this stuff
pick it up almost like a shovel then
take it back
to the surface for example tom
scooped up some rocks with his hand and
threw them into the river he turned his
hand
into something that kind of looks like a
bowl or a spoon
picked those up and then threw them in
to
the river now what does it do
once it gets to the shore there well
remember it's picked up the
insect or the the shellfish or whatever
along with some stones from the bottom
of that river and there
up at the surface up at the top of the
water where of course it can breathe
again
there it uses the stones to crush
the food in its mouth before swallowing
it
because platypuses don't have teeth
when you crush something basically you
put a lot of pressure on it you
smash it you pound it from some larger
shape into smaller and smaller and
smaller shapes
we use our teeth to crush especially
hard foods if you put nuts
into your mouth you don't bite them and
cut them in half with the front part of
your
your teeth you put them into the back
with those big teeth and you
smash them in between into small pieces
that is what it is to
crush something here's another thing we
might crush but
with our feet to make wine the
traditional way
you need to first crush the grapes with
your feet
or with a great press a machine that
pushes down on them
and crushes them into a small tiny
pieces
there you have it getting the juice out
anyways let's go ahead and wrap
up our article one might say this
strange little animal is living proof
that truth is stranger than fiction
i couldn't have possibly said it better
myself all right folks it's time to ask
the one
question mike which fact or facts about
platypuses
did you find the most surprising well i
still think that it's surprising that
the platypus can also be
poisonous we didn't really get into that
but yeah
the males have these little spurs these
little pointy things on their back legs
i believe
that apparently very poisonous to human
beings i mean
i don't know why that would be what do
they use them for well
we'll have to leave that for another day
but for an animal full
of surprises it's pretty easy to find a
surprising fact
because a platypus is basically just one
surprising fact after another in a 50
centimeter package
i agree all right folks it's time for us
to say bye bye
we'll see you next time
on
scoop
[Music]
my
there are over 700 different species of
eucalyptus trees
these trees make up nearly
three-quarters
of the forests in australia koalas live
in eucalyptus trees
and only eat eucalyptus leaves
eucalyptus trees are both good and bad
for forest fires in australia they can
grow back
in a few months after the fires go out
the oil inside of them makes it easier
for them to catch on fire though
some countries have banned eucalyptus
from growing to prevent fires
eucalyptus wood is often called gumnut
the oil is used in many beauty products
and
some natural medicines some of the
things that eucalyptus
helps with are coughs and joint pain
it's also used in perfumes because it
has a particular smell
since the various types of eucalyptus
trees grow
all over the world the oil has been used
by people for
thousands of years let's go climb a
eucalyptus tree
and see the view from up there when
traveling to australia
here is more information
special anna got a special gift on her
birthday
evergreen pines are evergreen
trees treatment
the best treatments for a cold are to
rest
and drink more water haze
the mountains were surrounded by the
haze
petal this flower has many petals
poisonous the poisonous snake
is very dangerous insect
ants butterflies and flies
are all insects surface
the leaves floated on the surface of the
water
toxin toxins in the water
made people sick soil
the soil is wet after the rain
thank you for watching today we hope to
see you again next time
[Music]