[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody surprise surprise it's shane
today we're looking at part two of
surprising geography facts
and the vocabulary words are exposed
exposed
the fire was caused by an exposed wire
vanish vanish the plane flew high into
the sky
and then vanished above the clouds
damn damn a dam was built to help
control flooding in
areas near the river process process
i only eat food that has not been
processed
in any way roughly roughly
roughly half of my neighborhood lost
power
after the storm so we are talking about
surprising geography
facts right right they start with the
dead
sea yeah that's right what a scary name
i know but it's going to vanish it's
going to disappear before our
eyes because of the rising sea level
right
and it has like the the lowest exposed
point of
earth because it's actually below sea
level
that's right that's interesting right
very low
and then another surprising geography
fact is that
did you know the world's tallest
mountain is not
mount everest that's right it's actually
in hawaii right that's crazy yeah it's
because
that the base of the mountain yes
because hawaii is an island
right so actually the base of the
mountain is below sea level
so if you are to measure from the base
of the mountain to the top it's
higher higher than mount everest i
didn't know that i've always thought
mount everest is the tallest mountain
in the world i think the most
interesting one is that
australia is wider than the moon
i know i didn't know that because from
my
east side to the west side it's about 4
000 kilometers wide
but the moon is only about i think 3 and
kilometers wide wow that is so amazing
yeah yeah that's what's fun about
learning these kind of facts because
they're just so
fascinating and interesting i know and
you can tell people about them and
they'll be
wow you're so smart impress
people by your english and your
knowledge of geography
you are definitely right and you're
welcome
surprising geography facts the dead sea
is below sea level and sinking
the dead sea has the lowest exposed
point on land
at 430.5 meters below sea level
however it is vanishing right before our
eyes
once covering an area of almost 1 000
square kilometers
it now only reaches around 650.
humans are to blame for this dams were
built which prevent the flow of water
into the lake
and factories pump water out to process
minerals
lowering the water level
today's lesson is called surprising
geography facts part two
hello everyone my name is jeff and i'm
mike and we're learning some amazing
and interesting facts about the world
antarctica
is the world's biggest desert and did
you know that russia
is like really big i knew that but i
didn't know that
11 times i didn't well i didn't know it
covered 11
time zones and it also controls an
island that is on one side
of the international date line
separating the
world into 24 hours and just four
kilometers away
on the other side of that line is an
american island so it's one day
in russia it's the day before in america
amazing
incredible okay let's move on and talk
about
the dead sea a fascinating body of water
the dead sea
is below sea level
and sinking and sinking
it's actually getting lower the body of
water itself is
getting lower and lower does that mean
that it's
drying out or does it mean that the body
of water itself is
actually like sinking into the earth
probably a little bit of both but it's
definitely drying out yeah the dead sea
which is there
in the eastern part of israel near i
think between israel and jordan
it has the lowest exposed point on land
at 430.5 meters
below sea level so if you're gonna walk
over to the mediterranean sea
which is the closest big sea you'd
actually be going
uphill you'd be going up to get there so
the dead sea like death valley in
america is also
below sea level that's not that unusual
however
it is vanishing the dead sea is also
vanishing
right before our eyes like the aerial
sea
like a lot of glaciers i think global
warming and human activity might be to
blame here
we're the worst aren't we anyways here
we have this word exposed
to talk about if something is exposed
it's kind of out in the open okay that's
all there is to it in this particular
situation
in other situations if someone is
exposed
they're open and unprotected and
vulnerable but here
we're saying that this is out in the
open okay this point
it's there it's out in the open if you
wanted to
you could go there and touch it or
something
it's there it's exposed for example the
fire was caused by
an exposed wire someone probably
should have done something about it
maybe closed
that up that wire shouldn't have been
exposed or
it shouldn't have been unprotected
someone should have
someone should have protected that wire
i should say
yeah we cover wires with plastic or
rubber right because if it's exposed and
you touch it
or another wire touches it it can cause
a spark or a fire or something bad all
right we also have this word
vanish when something vanishes it does
that it disappears it was there
and then a second later maybe it's not
there anymore i mean we often think of a
magician
with some kind of egg or something and
then they do this and oh
it's gone it's vanished it's disappeared
that's magic alright now sometimes
things vanish or disappear
it's not magic if you leave your cell
phone on a table
in a public place and walk away for two
minutes you might come back and go
it's vanished that wasn't magic someone
probably
took it away and stole it or something
like that and
things can vanish or disappear slowly
too
it doesn't always happen like that for
example
a rain puddle right rain will fall and
then the sun comes out and the heat will
make that
little puddle that little bit of water
vanish
or disappear it wasn't magic it didn't
happen quickly
but it was there and then later on it
wasn't there
as if it was never there in the first
place for example
the plane flew high into the sky and
then
vanished above the clouds it's still
there
you just can't see it there you go
that's the idea so how
is the dead sea vanishing well we'll
learn more about that i think
okay we read on the next sentence says
once covering an
area of almost 1 000 square kilometers
it now only reaches around
650 so that's quite the reduction now
humans are to blame for this
we are the worst dams were built
which prevent the flow of water into the
lake
and factories pump water
out to process minerals lowering the
water level
also look up the arrow see
the same thing happened to the aerial
sea
anyways here let's talk about the word
damn
a dam is kind of like a wall
for water it's a wall that directs
water keeps it in one place keep float
or keeps it flowing in one direction
uh it might produce hydro electric power
etc that's what dams do for example
a dam was built to help control flooding
in areas near the river some famous
dams in the world uh who the hoover dam
in the united states and the three
gorges dam in china yeah and they have
some smaller dams here i think in taiwan
i believe so yeah
up in the mountains they help to control
water and also sometimes
make power so they've damned the river
basically stopping the rivers
that used to flow into the water into
the lake
or into the dead sea of course that will
make the water levels go down and
they're also
taking the water that's in there out
they're
pumping the water out and using it in
factories and other places like that to
process
different things to process things is to
change
things through some kind of mechanical
industrial
engineering thing all right so a factory
will take the water in
and then use that water to polish steel
make cat food produce clothing who knows
well i think you must need water to
produce cat food i don't know
but they use it in order to do something
it's basically
one of the ingredients that goes into
this factory method
in order to produce something in the end
maybe nothing to do with water like
cat food or clothes i think clothing
production they have to use a lot of
water in the production or the
processing
of cotton and other things like that so
the water goes to do something
and doesn't go to the dead sea nope
doesn't go to the dead sea it goes into
the factory they use it up
and then it ends up in the in the in the
drain or you know going down the sewer
that kind of thing not in the dead sea
where of course it should be
for example i only eat food
that has not been processed in any way
alright so if you're eating fresh
vegetables those have not been processed
if you're eating vegetables that are
frozen or in a can
or made into some kind of microwave food
that you cook very quickly at home
those types of vegetables have been
processed something has been done to
them
in a factory in some way let's take a
break and then we'll be back with more
amazing geography facts
hello
he quickly pumped the water out of the
boat
to prevent it from sinking
down
can help lower blood pressure
surprising geography facts the world's
tallest mountain
is in hawaii mount everest is known for
having the highest peak above sea level
but it's not actually the tallest
mountain on earth
no that distinction belongs to hawaii's
mauna kea
which stands ten thousand two hundred
meters high
when it is measured from its undersea
base to its top
okay next we're going to talk about the
world's
tallest mountain which duh
is mount everest right
wrong the world's tallest mountain
is in hawaii
hawaii hawaii those beautiful islands in
the middle of the
i mean i know they have volcanoes there
they are volcanoes yeah exactly but
a big tall mountain no that doesn't make
any sense well it depends
how you look at it what are you calling
a
mountain it says on sea level it does
depend on sea level
mount everest is known for having the
highest peak
above sea level so if you want to get up
near the clouds
mount everest is the place to go but
if you're looking for just a big pile of
rock that you can go
from the bottom to the top of mount
everest in it baby
but it's not actually the tallest
mountain
on earth no mike if you're looking for
the biggest or tallest mountain i should
say
from base to peak well
you shouldn't look to mount everest no
that distinction belongs to hawaii's
mauna kea which stands ten thousand two
hundred meters high
when it is measured from its undersea
base
to its top how about that okay everyone
with that
with that it's time for us to take a
break but don't go away
we'll be right back after this
surprising geography facts australia
is wider than the moon the continent of
australia
is roughly 4 000 kilometers from east to
west
while the moon is only 3 400 kilometers
across
this makes australia wider than the moon
itself
it may be over 4.5 billion years old
but the earth can still surprise us it
just
goes to show what an amazing planet we
live on
[Music]
okay everybody we
we've been waiting for this we haven't
talked about
australia yet so let's talk about
australia mates get this
australia is wider
than the moon australia is wider than
the moon i'm sorry my australian accent
is atrocious well i won't argue with
that but i won't argue either
with the fact that australia is wider is
bigger from side to side
than the moon is yeah it's true the
continent of australia
is big well we know that but actually
the sentence says
the continent of australia is roughly
4 000 kilometers from east
to west if you drove across the country
you would be driving approximately 4 000
kilometers
in a straight line while the moon while
the moon is only
3 400 kilometers across
600 kilometers less so there you go
yeah anyways here we have the adverb
roughly to talk about
here the word roughly means
approximately or
about is it exactly 4 000 kilometers
no we're estimating it's close for
example
roughly half of my neighborhood lost
power
after the storm did i go out there and
count
every single house and do the figures
no i looked out my window and it looked
like
about half of the neighborhood lost
power there you go okay let's go ahead
and
move on this makes australia
wider than the moon itself
amazing and there's more kangaroos in
australia too than on the moon
that's another great geography fact
anyway let's move on
it may be over 4.5 billion years old
but the earth can still surprise us
that's right most of us
have gone through geography class many
maybe many years of geography class
but today in our two articles we've
learned a few facts that i'm sure
not every single one of you knew all of
these facts so the
earth is old but it's still amazing it
just goes to show
what an amazing planet we live on
with big continents cold deserts
tiny islands on different days it's it's
incredible
and there are mountains that you can't
really climb because most of them are
underwater
and there are also more kangaroos here
than on the moon that's another amazing
fact isn't it wow
yeah wow yeah and koala was mind-blowing
all right here we've got a question
we've got to ask and answer
the rethink question do you
know any other geography
fun facts that weren't mentioned in the
article
and if you don't which fact did you find
the most
interesting and why and you can't use
the fact that there are more
kangaroos in australia than on the moon
oh i don't know that's a pretty good
fact no it's not
all right trivially like best well all
right
i know i know that there are certain
places and i
believe in canada the bay of fundy is
one of them where the tides are
so high they can come up 20 or 30
feet and rivers can flow backwards
rivers flow uphill that's a pretty cool
fact
i've seen it happen it's true really
you've seen it okay families from that
area oh nice nice
anyways folks with that it's time for us
to end our lesson and to say
bye bye take care come on
howie
approximately a-p-p-r-o-x-i-m-a-t-e-l-y
it goes to show that with hard work
anything
is possible
[Music]
the adelaide town hall is an iconic
landmark in adelaide australia
the clock tower is part of the downtown
area
on king williams street the albert tower
bells
ring during important moments in the
history of the city
the adelaide town hall was built between
and 1865. the clock was added later
in 1935. there are a bronze statue of
queen
adelaide and art galleries inside
all kinds of events such as meetings
gatherings
concerts and other civic and cultural
events
take place at the adelaide town hall the
design was the result
of a contest held by mayor tom english
back in the 1860s if you want to see a
famous band perform in adelaide
this is probably the best place
here is more information
landmark the eiffel tower is the most
famous landmark in paris purchase
michael purchased his clothes at the
shopping mall
exhibit there will be an exhibit of
chinese paintings at the museum next
week
attract put the food away or
it will attract ants crowd
a big crowd went to the festival
complex we live in this
apartment complex centerpiece
mom used flowers to make a centerpiece
for the table
organ mandy plays the organ beautifully
fan sports fans like to watch soccer
games
conference i will attend the conference
tomorrow morning thank you very much for
watching and we'll see you again next
[Music]
time