[Music]
hello everyone this is carrot hey
everybody I am Shane today we're looking
at part 1 of the life of a pro gamer and
the vocabulary words are salary salary
Jeremy left his job for one with a
better salary intense intense during
dinner Lindsey had an intense debate
with her uncle over climate change
schedule schedule Darren has a really
busy schedule this week so he can't meet
up with you drill drill the basketball
coach drilled his players on their
shooting skills a right aspect aspect
social media has become an important
aspect of modern life so we're talking
about something that's really
interesting but I do not know too much
about yep the life of a pro gamer yeah
so what is you know like when we say pro
gamer what does that mean well basically
we mean somebody's playing online video
games I professionally definitely Wow
and what does it mean to be professional
it means you get paid for what you do
some people who love playing games
that's like really good news right if
you're going to turn your hobby into a
career yes but like any career it if you
want to be good at it and you want to
become a professional and make a lot of
money and become famous if you have to
practice a lot but I guess they probably
would have mind too much practicing
right yeah well it's pretty intense like
the Korean gamers are pretty famous for
their intense schedule
okay practice playing for fifteen hours
a day no way yeah and that doesn't even
count at the time that they're just
playing for themselves for fun it's 15
hours per day this is really practicing
their skills yeah so no that's like the
whole day wow I can't imagine even
working over 8 hours a day and
yeah they're practicing 15 hours a day
that's crazy
no wonder they're really good and no
wonder they get paid a big bucks for it
yeah but like you said at least they're
doing something that they really enjoy
doing true you they have the passion for
it nobody's parents is telling their
kids I want you to be a pro gamer right
it means that me some I don't know we
don't know all right let's learn more
about the life of a pro gamer all right
enjoy the life of a pro gamer the latest
sport isn't played on a field or in a
park instead its matches are played
between players seated at high end
computers professional video game
playing or pro gaming is the hottest new
spectator sport its best players are big
stars that can earn huge prizes and
salaries for playing their favorite
games sound like a dream the reality
isn't quite so pleasant
today's lesson is called the life of a
pro gamer part 1 hello everyone my name
is Jeff and I'm Mike yeah pro gamer role
gaming the newest sort of rank or the
newest category of professional athletes
I guess we could call them athlete or
their athletes in the same their
athletes in the same way that chess
players are yeah sometimes sometimes you
turn on a sports Network and two people
are battling it out over a chess board
now is chess a sport right people can
debate that they say the same thing
about golf as well isn't really a sport
what we're darts or darts but one way or
the other apparently people are now
gaming and they're making money to do so
people are becoming pro gamers how about
that it sounds great you know dying
video games something you do in your
free time but getting paid to do it all
the time but we're gonna be reading over
the next two days the reality of the
life of a pro gamer so it might make you
question whether playing pro games
professionally is what you really want
to do it's metal stick yeah not only is
it very tough to be a pro gamer it's
extremely competitive as well anyways
the latest sport isn't played on a field
or in a park instead its matches are
played between players seated at high
end computers yeah really big fancy
computers with really really cool
components that allow you to play really
cool video games as fast as you want
with as much memory or whatever as you
want in the same way that professional
basketball players would spend a lot on
their shoes and other equipment
professional gamers have to spend a lot
on their equipment because professional
video game playing or pro gaming
professional gaming is the hottest new
spectator sport it is a billion-dollar
industry so let's find out more about
professional gaming it says it's best
players are big stars that can earn huge
prizes and salaries for playing their
favorite games so yeah think of the are
the most famous basketball players or
most
famous football players in the world
professional gamers can be up on the
same level they earned huge prizes I
mentioned million-dollar prizes and also
a salary so even if you don't win you
just get paid a wage like a normal
worker for playing game yeah there you
go
by the way here we use the word salary
not talking about a vegetable celery no
no salary s a l a are why when you're
talking about your salary you're talking
about the money you make doing a job per
some period of time and we're not
talking per hour sometimes people they
sign a contract and they say you're
gonna work here for one year and you're
going to make this amount of money that
would be your salary for example Jeremy
left his job for one with a better
salary he left his current job because a
new job was offering him more money
anyways pro-gaming sounds great mmm does
this sound like a dream to you well the
reality isn't quite so pleasant being a
pro gamer isn't all it's cracked up to
be
yeah don't tell anyone but it's it's
hard work anyways folks with that it's
time for us to take a break but don't go
away we'll be back after this hello
Annie - Annie singsong the Mong Chang
soo yeah mom he entire city attention
this is Jaime Hollow
no I'm Juliana come on Josh I can't
injection show the chance to show ho
should we shoot some of me huh Cohen
hadashah that's really one your Chung
wait ng - it's a room and the
Shing Shing Guanzhong senior in top
limit injection shot was a cult and a
notch every encounter that come on so
either Yoshi like or the trio chanting
handshake
so teens hydrogen sugar main mom
Kristina change King Kong commute some
real how Gong cha hwa-jung da something
is not all it's cracked up to be
something is not all it's cracked up to
be
gotta show emotion pin with Shannon - oh
the juma ha ha the Mad Ants
salary salary high purchasing straight
shinsa-dong hunter too cold in the shin
trail not her Madrid had a fine
jin-tae Odin shall we worship - bad idea
salaries and she machines not show it
celery
such as the chins hack hazard Pinto Cele
or why how do I win John the pro PR oath
has a professional associate came a
dong-hyun session trainee that you yet
he okay down means idea that religion
should hire high-end high-end focus on
sahaja National Championship go down God
Yahweh de chef lasheeda tangentially had
a tea now show baby yet
hello Jean Dow component tickets a CEO
NPO and ent tickets I can change it Bing
Jin - coach on yahoo co Jaco and wrong
the life of a pro gamer for professional
gamers playing is a full-time job
some players practice 50 hours a week
with their team and that's on top of how
much they play alone Korean teams in
particular are known for intense
schedules they practice up to 15 hours
per day during the gaming season that
only leaves time for meals short breaks
and a little sleep
professional gamers everyone they have
to put in a whole lot of work to be pros
yes professional gamers for I should say
for professional gamers playing is a
full-time job oh yeah I get to play
games all the time fantastic
well here if you want to be a pro gamer
you're gonna have to play all the time
it's a full-time job some players
practice 40 50 60 hours a week that's
right it's actually more than a
full-time job right because most
full-time jobs would be around 40 40
hours a week five days a week eight
hours a day some players though some
players practice 50 hours a week with
their team and that's on top of how much
they play alone so this isn't total time
this is organized team practice but
imagine if you're organized professional
football player went to the team
practice then went home and played more
football just at home by himself in the
evening by herself in the evening that's
kind of what it's like so you practice
with the team and then you play on your
own so it would probably work out to
what 80 90 hours a week sitting in front
of the computer or whatever playing the
same game and Korean teams some of the
best in the world Korean teams in
particular are known for intense
schedules it's a tough military army
like schedule a little very very intense
a little bit of sleep yeah a whole lot
of playing a little bit eating whole lot
of playing that's right a little more
sleep living with the same people you
know kind of in a college dorm tie
playing where's very little break from
it there's very little way to get away
and you know get away from your
teammates or your job or your work it's
very intense
in other words this adjective is
something we use for something that's
powerful very strong very concentrated
it's a lot going on at once I had a
really intense day my boss yelled at me
I lost my phone my dog was sick I had to
take it to the vet stuff a lot of crazy
things were going on in a very short
time we could also use it to say
something's powerful or strong like an
intense storm intense winds during the
typhoon
can be very dangerous or someone is
always talking and they're serious and
they never smile or crack a joke you
might say man guys really intense he
should relax a little bit
for example during dinner Lindsay had an
intense debate with her uncle over
climate change by the way here we have
the noun scheduled to talk about a
schedule is a document either on your
computer or actually on a piece of paper
that tells you what you'll be doing and
when you'll be doing it so the schedule
for a gamer in Korea might be sleep a
little wake up at 5 a.m.
play games until noon take a 10-minute
lunch break and then play until you go
to sleep again that would be your
schedule well maybe it's not that
extreme but hey it's pretty tough
anyways for example Darren has a really
busy schedule this week so he can't meet
up with you he just doesn't have any
time now before I before I was what I
was talking about the schedule of a
Korean gamer I wasn't kidding get this
they practice up to 15 hours per day
during the gaming season so you have 9
hours in which to eat sleep and to take
care of your personal hygiene Wow
everything else is just gaming so over
well over 6 5 that would be what like 75
hours or something of playing games a
little bit more than that 50 we
mentioned before so you can see that is
very very intense it only leaves a
little time for meals short breaks and a
little sleep it's game game game game
they miss dream of the game when they're
sleeping they must brush their teeth
with one hand and continue playing
what's the other hand it sounds a little
too intense for me but I don't know
anyways let's take a break and then
we'll be back with more about the life
of a pro gamer HD a 10-0 Angela show can
also change the console tantra position
so java which only help you show the
Shang Hall : hide I'll show you when I
eat soy Okinawa Chilean sea to the South
it's a high Papa Hanuman City 10 to 13
some decided he gently gently Otunga
sugar shop you can have earth the South
Dakota sugar shouted to say
Joker's house suggested a nice young
like chiffon honi plant and a show she
hello Johnny how sushi also hakuren ways
and back natural of Chicago yonder Hye
Jin's against hy g IE and e hi ginger be
ovation Najimy holobands intense intense
passion says she know me GG do ho sang
near de ha not had a mean since it read
out the way eats a JIT why pension
intensity intensity kph and oh what a
sham it my closet yes she dances younger
concentrated concentrated passionate
each on the leadership concentrate to
the trench in friend jiggity homi Bhabha
in fencing
how do i can schedule schedule Tabuchi
Pacquiao Oceaneer Chung Empire Jayhawk
ku and John the life of a pro gamer
although some games have practice modes
that players can use to drill specific
skills professional players are so good
at every aspect of the game that they
mostly play exhibition matches against
other players these practice games are
often against the very players they will
compete against in tournaments just as
often pro gamers play online with
ordinary people if you start getting
really good at a game you may find
yourself matched with some of your
favorite gaming stars
okay everyone let's talk some more about
pro gaming although some games have
practice modes that players can use to
drill specific skills professional
players pro gamers are so good at every
aspect of the game that they mostly play
exhibition matches against other players
yeah
the drills in these games these practice
mode drills they're not enough for these
pro pro gamers they have to play
exhibition matches for it to be worth it
as far as practice is concerned
interesting but yeah if you're trying to
get good at something especially if it's
something involving sports or physical
activity drills are one of the best way
to do it here we're using it as a verb
we can talk about the players are doing
drills or they are drilling different
skills basically it means practicing
something over and over and over again
to become better at it until you finally
get really good until you master this
skill in sports for example in baseball
they might have base running drills
where you practice to run around the
bases faster and more efficiently
batting drills catching pitching things
like that so you do it again and again
and again maybe just two players working
together small groups working together
and again it's about the repetition
about doing it over and over till it
becomes just part of you and you don't
have to think about it for example the
basketball coach drilled his players on
their shooting skills so they might have
spent 40 minutes of one practice just
shooting free-throws
we also had the word aspect here we said
pro gamers are good at every aspect of
the game at their play they have to be
now what's an aspect though an aspect is
a part of something or it's a feature of
something and usually we're talking
about that harder feature we're saying
that this thing is part of a bigger
thing so there's one thing let's say
we're talking about these players are
doing in the game that's the aspect of
the game that they're playing at that
moment but the game has many aspects to
it for example social media has become
an important ass
fact of modern life is social media our
entire lives
no but it does play an important part in
our lives now more on these exhibition
or practice games that pro gamers have
to play they have to do these things to
get better because other forms of
practice just aren't enough these
practice games are often against the
very players they will compete against
in tournaments Wow
slaves things yeah they kind of play
exhibitions against the people that
they'll be playing for real
in tournaments okay so this is sort of
like before the basketball season NBA
players might play sort of friendly
games you know go overseas play in other
countries it doesn't count but it's
better than just practicing against your
teammates so they'll do that in pro
gaming I guess it's also a good way to
kind of learn about your opponent's
skills so later on when you're playing
for big money and prizes you have an
idea of how they play it says just as
often pro gamers play online with
ordinary people of course there's lots
of game hosting sites where you can go
and find the game find another player in
another part of the world and it could
be a pro gamer it says if you start
getting really good at a game you may
find yourself matched with some of your
favorite gaming stars of course your
skill in the game will be high they
probably have rankings based on how many
wins and losses but if you get up there
in the rankings if you're in the top 100
maybe you might be playing against some
famous pro gamers so watch out yeah be
careful they're very very good yes a
chant get the chance but if you lose
don't be too upset every everyone it's
time for us to now end today's lesson
but don't go away we'll be back next
time with more commend Concetta Yoshi
Yoshi Ionians emotion carry on you I'll
be including Sugiyama
but when you try I went out to you see
the me found me know her now she'll say
I haven't opened she consider Wan Jia
like boots and a chef and say 9:30 she
did she said I meet you dr. Schaack Tung
Chung Georgia Tech they also meet
without pinching shin jung-hwan job
children jeong cho sites in the USA
how long until i can't dance
drill drill Tong Tong zookeeper that
Charlie Sheen in the madam means
educated then she shouldn't it
the metallian Drosophila and she a bush
in there check out my closet IO younger
repetitions it gets it repe TI tion
repetition to become full fat fool
fashion sang a dance aspect aspect Tapia
should submit funny and down means
no concert hall t da ji wang jian jian
jian cheng on a barren to a chance sir
uber mogul Yoshi knee pad hyung how you
should references it since I can say
either thing I mean since I played all
know me a chance is did John see dojin
biz okay Michelle
[Music]
jehoash in handy when you show come the
one fat on your in see now just how the
woman Valjean did Yoli go bigger so
Josh anxious the whole food sad that
it's the truth
Jurgis should find Josh Olsen Josh shows
the boy the trishing how much Elijah so
- she knows the whole food - Jack that's
the truth
Joshua Russa Samia eat choose a young
face hunter me antiquity meow Dante
atresia I turned out so homey machine
super foods to show me moshu the jungle
go down south Shamu could see a koala
mama that's the true Joshua a Adachi
equal when I can angle redrew the book
was so interesting that she couldn't
stop reading it the mercial fate hung
your true it irritated me Babu no Jake
laughed so hard that he choked on his
spit Jake Sheldon I only issued her with
the kosher Chang dollar Nutella lashes
she find Josh old Josh shows the Buddha
trishing don't suffice the debenture
fashion patria the Mahamaya shows the
data shows the poetry / - or fashion
more hormone shoot show image of drunk
type how cheat on the shorts the boil
mchao machine offense got your friends
to the position Yangtze now I can't have
a Trish in Joey I should find Jack
shouts Jack VI ng push a PP oh yeah
she knows how shunsui on me young VI ng
Joe Pesci shows the true don't
watch it turns 18 she moved on so nano
shown PP do PR shows that happy don't
you show don't owe my sauce angrily trip
when he got home he found the dog
sleeping on his bed cha-cha-cha fashion
cocoa tea and since is a hatch on
Shanghai Hana to show mercy oceans Evans
sleeping my data translating Sheena
Danza fake Hangul eg they returned to
their hotel room and found the door
unlocked
tomorrow a diluent fountain fashion meso
Lanter shoulders young coach events
unlocked like that admin bay don't you
show dr. Haas a kindly drew the little
girl found her grandma asleep on the
couch Shanghai fashion ha
sebastian cerisola Emma Amani Toomer
make and you took one course on my own
since asleep like show me a Mahal tree
shades out gyeongtae ha ha ha he sounds
and Johnny and only wish asses in love
[Music]
hi sorry today I'm a little bit off I
don't know what's wrong
welcome to English in action I'm home I
am Shane yes sorry I was just maybe I
was thinking about ok tinea topic
doesn't miss youla ok ok yeshuaa
ok sorry everybody yeah anyway did it
like just dialogue but dialogues yeah
this is good I don't know sorry sorry
about that not important
[Music]
sorry I'm late it wasn't my fault that
the bus wasn't on time put a sock in it
I'm tired of your excuses
sock in it guess I'll get my sock what's
wrong with you hmm what is wrong with
you I told you put a sock in it not put
a sock in it put a sock in it right you
meant my mouth right right let's not
literally put a sock what's in a Mentos
though that's like a beer oh my goodness
akut attach it to the shoe don't you
sighs I need a bandage on Paula shut up
[Laughter]
how did I get might say solve it I got
shown some bad yeah save it's like save
your breath say there's a cheese yeah
I'm not I'm not listening anymore
I don't care save it for it all right
miss out so can choose just one doesn't
need such a favor on a bad call yeah not
to Lila yeah okay all right so we are
never going to put a sock in it we're
not we're gonna just keep talking and
keep talking and teaching you English
yes yes so no Cola where's my sock put a
sock in it put a sock in it save it save
it
can it can it
[Music]