[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody
i'm spider-shane today we're looking at
part two of
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond and the vocabulary words are
backgrounds background the company
hasn't hired susan yet because they want
to know more about her background
be fine define travis feels that his job
does not define who he is as a person
career career i think a career in
science
best suits you adventure adventure
brett told me about an adventure novel
that he is reading
charity charity my brother works for a
charity that provides food and clothing
for the homeless
so we're still talking about this
talented actor and dancer tom holland
choo choo choo choo spider-man right did
you know that in fact he performs his
own stunts in spider-man you are joking
usually they have a stunt man right
that's right especially if you're a big
actor or something like that
because it could be a little dangerous
right or perhaps you don't have the
skills
to do some of the movements that you
need to do but because of his dancing
background
he's actually really good at doing flips
and everything you see him doing
that's not a stuntman that's him that's
pretty awesome and i think he doesn't
want to
just have spider-man define his career
so he's actually trying out different
kind of roles like you know crimes
adventures
or there's also like different many many
different even sci-fi too wow
yeah well it doesn't just stop there
because he also helps the
community right so they have something
called the brothers trust
that's right and what that does is help
get money for
some charities that don't get a lot of
public attention
wow so of course you know if the
charity's not in the spotlight maybe
people aren't going to be giving money
so he tries to
get money to those important but not so
well-known charities
what an awesome person awesome person
from an awesome family too all right
let's learn more about
tom holland
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond today everyone knows holland
as peter parker
the teenager who fights evil alongside
other marvel heroes like
iron man and thor thanks to his dance
background
he's able to perform all of his own
stunts in the films
when you see spider-man do a backflip
that's really holland showing off his
own amazing abilities
welcome to today's lesson it's called
tom holland from ballet
to spider-man and
beyond part two
hi everyone my name is jeff and i'm mike
and yes we are
traveling through the career of young
tom
holland he's still young he started very
young
he continues to be young but he won't be
young forever but he did start
very young as a young dancer and then he
learned ballet
for two years he started as billy
elliott in the west end sort of broadway
here in london doing
the musical billy elliot but of course
it was his
star turn his big chance his big
opportunity as
peter parker or or spider-man but he's
got a lot of other things coming up too
he's not gonna be spider-man forever no
he's got a six-picture deal after that
he'll probably
move on and do something else cool or
retire because he'll have
tons of money anyways though let's get
started with today's lesson
today everyone knows
holland as peter parker the
teenager who fights evil
alongside other marvel heroes like
iron man and thor on the
avengers now thanks to his
dance background he's able to perform
all of his own stunts
in the films by the way here
when we're using the word background
we're talking about someone's
history or experience with something for
example
the company hasn't hired susan yet
because they want to know more about her
background
yeah your resume is kind of incomplete
we need to know
more about your past of course now yes
when you've seen the
avengers movies the spider-man movies as
you said spider-man
doesn't dance very much but with an
experience
in dance with a background in dance he's
very
physically capable he can do things with
his
body that other people non-dancers
might have more trouble with and of
course they've used these skills
as spider-man so when you see spider-man
do a backflip in the movies that's
really holland
showing off his own amazing abilities so
if it was someone
without a dance background they might
have to get a stunt person
to do these tricks i know i would right
i don't
do a backflip you don't have a dance
background they might have to use
cgi and things like that now of course
when he's climbing up the side of a
building
that's probably some computers at work
there
but when he's jumping around when he's
doing some amazing things on his own two
feet
that really is tom holland under that
mask
and not a stunt person because of these
amazing abilities
and his dance background where we're
gonna dance off to a quick break
and then we'll tap our way back for part
the next part of the
article
is
foreign
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond although spider-man is a huge
role
holland doesn't want to let it define
his whole career
that's why in addition to another
spider-man film
holland has crime adventure and even
science fiction films all coming up
he hopes that all this work will help
him move on to a role as a director
in fact he already has some film ideas
in the works
okay tom holland he's spider-man
and that's that he's known
worldwide for being spider-man
but although spider-man is
a huge role holland
doesn't want to let it define
his whole career he wants to have a life
outside of acting maybe and being
spider-man maybe he wants to go back to
being a
carpenter one day after he leaves acting
ah okay well that's a good idea for an
actor you don't want to be defined as
one type of actor
or limited to one style of movie when we
define
things well we could use this to say we
describe them we kind of
give you an idea of what they are we
draw a picture using words to give you
you know a more of a clear idea of
something of what something is
but we also use it to kind of say we put
things in a category
or we put things in a box when actors
are defined by a certain type of movie
we might say oh the rock he does action
movies where he uses his big muscles and
that's who you are that's that that's
who you are we put you in that category
let's talk about this uh word defined by
looking at the example sentence
travis feels that his job does not
define
who he is as a person yeah he's a
computer engineer
people might think that he's a little
boring and he's always tapping away on
his computer
but he actually likes to play jazz music
on the weekends and he's an
artist too so he's not defined by his
job
that's what i do for a living it's not
me that's my career
my whole personality but it's not who i
am
down deep it doesn't define me now
speaking of the word career
the word career refers
to your job but more specifically your
career
is something that you often train
for to do for your entire
life to make money to support yourself
so on so forth for example
i think a career in science
best suits you yeah you should be
a researcher or something like
that anyways tom holland he doesn't want
spider-man to define him and that's why
in addition to another spider-man film
holland has crime
adventure and even
science fiction films
all coming up get ready folks
he is going to be everywhere
his mug is going to be plastered
everywhere his face on a lot of movie
posters
all right so yes he does have another
superhero film coming up another
spider-man film but as you can see he
doesn't want to be defined as just a
superhero
action movie actor he's going to do a
crime film
an adventure film and some science
fiction not
spider-man and space something totally
different when we talk about adventure
we talk about an exciting experience if
you go
canoeing through the amazon that would
be an adventure that would be an
exciting experience and so an adventure
film
would kind of be like an action film
there'll be some danger there'll be some
exciting scenes
fist fights car chases things like that
it won't leave you sitting in your chair
falling asleep after
20 minutes it will have a lot of action
excitement
and adventure for example brett told me
about an
adventure novel that he is reading so
tom holland has a lot of different
movies coming up and he hopes we read as
we come to the break
he hopes that all this work will help
him
move on to a role as a director
how ambitious interesting he wants to
move from being an
actor to a director
cut yeah in fact he already has
some film ideas in the works how about
that all right folks with that it's time
for another break but don't go away
we'll be back soon
tom holland joshua
[Music]
he was diagnosed with cancer that's why
he quit smoking done
i'd like some chicken nuggets in
addition to
french fries
something be coming up
tom holland from ballet to spider-man
and beyond besides acting holland works
with his parents and his three younger
brothers to run the family's charity
the brothers trust the organization
raises money for charities
that don't get a lot of public attention
for someone who's only 24 years old
holland sure has made his mark on
popular culture
as he swings into the next chapter of
his cinematic career
tom holland is out to show the world
that you don't need to be spider-man to
be spectacular
[Music]
okay so besides acting
holland well he does other stuff
really very interesting let's find out
what he's doing when he's not
acting or preparing movies to direct it
says besides acting
holland works with his parents and his
three
younger brothers to run the family's
charity
the brothers trust how nice how
wonderful what a great thing for them to
do as a family
i like how he hasn't even put his name
on it but tom holland foundation
that would sound audacious and kind of
pretentious no
this is just the brothers trust
how nice and yes this is a family
charity a charity everyone by the way
is an organization that helps
people out okay it usually helps people
who needs who need help i should say
it's an organization that helps the
needy one thing
usually charities are non-profit
they're not in it for the dollar or to
make money for example my
brother works for a charity that
provides
food and clothing for the homeless
so there you go that's wonderful that
sounds like a really good
charity what about the brothers trust
the tom holland or the holland
family charity it says the organization
or
the charity the brothers trust the
organization
raises money for charities that don't
get
a lot of public attention oh interesting
so he can kind of
move from idea to you know issue to
you know good cause that he thinks
really needs a bit of attention there
are a lot of charities out there
a lot of us know some of the well-known
ones greenpeace or
amnesty international but there are many
that don't get a lot of public
attention maybe they're helping people
in a smaller less
noticed part of the world or an issue
that only
a few people have problems with but they
still need help
they still need attention and tom
holland being a big star
can bring some attention and some money
to these
charities that's a great idea let's
start wrapping things up
for someone who's only 24 years old
holland sure has made his mark on
popular culture and
when i shook my head there i wasn't
shaking my head at
tom holland he's a great guy i'm
thinking about
how little i've achieved in my life i'm
a lot
older than 24. anyways
as he swings into the next
chapter of his cinematic career tom
holland
is out to show the world that you don't
need to be spider-man to be
spectacular you could be someone like
just
tom holland anyways folks that's it
for our article and now we have the what
do you think
hey mike yes which movie featuring
tom holland is your favorite and if you
haven't
seen any of tom holland's movies
which one would you like to see
hmm well i actually haven't looked at a
list of many of his movies but
i'd say my favorite movie is
avengers civil note
captain america civil war i think he was
in that one there was a
spider say say spider-man homecoming
spider-man hope
i didn't see that one anyways one of the
marvel movies i thought was pretty good
in that movie
tom holland played spider-man he was
kind of young
he was kind of enthusiastic you know
iron man was kind of
acting his his mentor it was very good
and i thought
tom howland was entertaining but i would
also be interested to see him in a crime
film or that science fiction film pretty
much
anything where he's not spider-man
because yeah i think he is
a young talented guy and i just like to
see him in
something different so i will definitely
be paying attention
to what's coming up could tom holland be
a bad guy
hmm good question or maybe could he be
james bond in
10 20 years possibly who knows
anyways folks with that our lesson is
now in the
in the books and it's time for us to say
bye bye
take care tom holland
the brothers trust
her passion for teaching left its mark
on her students
on
[Music]
foreign
is there anybody out there
that is a question many people have
thought about for a long time
scientists have been using radio
telescopes to listen for
signals from space in the past
people have also sent messages to the
stars
nasa sent out radio waves of popular
music
and old tv shows they hoped that
aliens would receive the messages and
establish contact with earth
however not everyone thinks it's a good
idea
to search for life on other planets what
if the aliens are dangerous
maybe they will attack us if they find
out earth's location
still some people believe contacting
aliens
is a good idea it would be nice to know
if humans are
alone in the universe or not what do you
think
should we continue to look for aliens or
is it better to remain silent so that no
one can find us
here is more information
abduct the man tried to abduct
the child but the police stopped him
analyze the doctor analyzed
jim's blood astronomer
the astronomer found a new planet
claim she claims she saw an
alien but i don't believe her
detect the dog detected the earthquake
before it happened
infected clean that cut or
it will get infected
participate eight people
participated in the game
quarantine tina was quarantined
at the airport because she had a fever
sighting there was a bear sighting this
morning
so be careful on your hike
support ian works hard to
support his family
so what did you think of today's lesson
pretty interesting right
we hope to see you again next time