[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen hola
everybody
I'm Shane today we're looking at part 1
of marvellous Majorca Toyota and the
vocabulary words are relatively
relatively compared to most years this
winter has been relatively warm steep
steep my grandpa had trouble climbing
the steep stairs curve curve the road
curves to the left after the post office
cliff cliff Tim stood at the edge of the
cliff
and took a picture professional
professional
Nelson's cousin is a professional dancer
so we're talking about marvelous of
Majorca it's a beautiful place in Spain
that's right like a little island off of
Spain right have you been - been to
Majorca no I lived in Barcelona ok but I
never travel to any of the islands
really too bad because my Orca sounds
amazing yeah I heard it's a beautiful
vacation spot yeah so it's a really
great place to go to enjoy nature
especially beaches and especially when
you're riding the bicycle so they do
have mountains there and the people
actually professional cyclists cyclists
thank you
bikers nyquist that's right practice for
the Tour de France there really so it's
quite challenging yes it's quite
challenging and it's just well it's also
very beautiful why not practice in a
very beautiful environment I guess
you're right so a great way to travel
around by riding the bicycle and there
it's got like a lot of beautiful beaches
yeah that's the part I'm looking forward
to and I go definitely meet you
ok so maybe when I have a chance I will
definitely visit my York oh yeah next
time you're in Spain head over to my
Orca alright ok enjoy enjoy
marvelous Majorca located off the
southern coast of Spain the island of
Majorca is often praised as one of the
jewels of the Mediterranean as the
Spanish royal families preferred summer
vacation spot Majorca effortlessly
charms visitors with its picturesque
villages rich vineyards and mountains
covered in orange and lemon trees
today's lesson is called marvellous
Majorca part 1 hello everyone my name is
Jeff and I'm Mike now my Orca might not
be a name that is familiar to you but if
we tell you that it is part of the
country of Spain ah now you probably
have a much better idea of where in the
world we are my Orca yeah it's an island
or it's one of several islands off the
coast of Spain in the beautiful
Mediterranean Sea and if you're looking
for a wonderful beach island holiday
with destination with a Spanish twist
look no further than my Orca well you
could either go to Spain for the Spanish
twister or to Majorca if you want to get
even deeper into things in Spain it's
not an island so Spain is not an island
though it's a peninsula it's actually a
part of the Iberian Peninsula but yes my
Orca is most definitely in island and
it's most definitely wonderful marvelous
and Spanish as well so I think we'll
just stick with my Orca for now but yes
located off the southern coast of Spain
it is a part of the country of Spain the
island of Majorca is often praised as
one of the jewels of the Mediterranean
one of the wonderful little islands
there in the Mediterranean it's a
wonderful wonderful place now as the
Spanish royal families preferred summer
vacation spot my York effortlessly
charms visitors with its picturesque
villages rich vineyards and mountains
covered in orange and lemon trees so
there you go go to my Orca cuz it's
marvellous stay because the oranges and
the lemons of
there's a lot of citrus to be found on
this particular island and on top of
that it's also the Spanish royal
family's preferred summer vacation spot
pretty pretty good are you in the
royalty Mike and not that I know it's
not that you know if so you can't visit
on those pretenses but you can buy a
ticket and fly there anytime you'd like
alright folks with that it's time for us
to take a short break but don't go away
we'll be right back after this hello
Joao de semana de maua de Majorca
how are you teacher hey teacher not a
guitar you should see bang a gong show
show that shot in 2008 now Shanghai
orphans in return John your food how Ian
hey old pizza dough chan handing moon
shoes of full guidance mi ha ha me near
in the Saturn language I got a
functional Hadouken Wonka Oh mr.
high-camp Oh Chun Dan's vineyard
vineyard Thai food how nice
Nakano showed a Leo Chen Han li mo Chou
social Jaguar young Joey gets a citrus
CIT
our us citrus special can't relay who
she can't reshoot you have a royal
degradation no one should Wan Jia de los
Yungas other means the royalty the
homogeneity why royalty bi sure one
should want to wash it one should show
yet how they were poor choice yeah the
Mediterranean charity jeonghye
namashivaya - will I believe Andalusia
the Iberian Peninsula
- such an EP li panda she Jones a Capon
insalata Japan though the ISA - Jaco and
John marvelous Majorca since it is a
relatively small island the Orca is best
seen by bicycle the Sarah Dutra Montana
mountain range runs along the islands
north western coast and covers nearly
30% of the islands territory which makes
it a cyclists dream the steep curving
roads that cross the tall peaks and
rocky cliffs provide some of the most
challenging cycling on the island in
fact the roads are often used as
practice for the Tour de France by
cyclists everyone we're back and we're
still talking about marvelous marvelous
my Orca
do you like my York I'm like I'm a big
fan of it but I've never actually been
so I'm only going on the little bit that
I know so let's find out more about my
Orca because then I'm sure we will all
be fans and some of us will be booking
our tickets it says since it is a
relatively small island Majorca is best
seen by bicycle well that's great you
don't have to rent a car you can see
that see the whole island from the back
of a bike and get some exercise at the
same time yeah they say the same thing
about LAN you here off the coast of
Taiwan it's a small enough island that
you can get around by bicycle you can go
you can go all the way around the island
and one day no problem on a bike so why
aren't a car or a scooter if you don't
have to anyways here it says that
Majorca is a relatively small island
what are we saying we're saying compared
to other islands it's quite small like
Taiwan is a very large island you
probably couldn't bike around it in one
day but compared to Taiwan LAN U is a
relatively small island it is small
compared to something else that's what
this adverb relatively means in this
case for example compared to most years
this winter has been relatively warm
compared to other years this has been a
warm season on average the temperatures
were warmer than you would expect
alright so let's imagine we're on our
bikes we're traveling around my Orca
taking in some of the sights what would
we see it says visera
detriment Anna mountain range runs along
the island's northwestern coast and
covers nearly 30% of the islands
territory which makes it a cyclists
dreams it dreams it to dream on the way
down on the way up maybe not so much but
all the way down fun or maybe park your
bike in the morning do some hiking in
the mountain ranges and then cycle back
to town downhill but there are beautiful
mountains there so it's not just sort of
beaches
you know seaside you can definitely get
up into this Serra tum tana there you go
that's the mountain range now the steep
curving roads that cross the tall peaks
and rocky cliffs provides some of the
most challenging cycling on the island
so there you go it's a cyclists dream
let's say you like those really really
hard steep mountains
that's the steep mountain roads I should
say you're gonna love this but for
someone like me or maybe Mike there
maybe it's just a dream and we're
coasting downhill because it does sound
like this is going to be some
challenging cycling there on my Yorkin
anyways we've got three vocabulary words
to cover right now next up we have the
word steep that's right when you're
recycling if you're riding up a steep
hill you'll be working very hard your
leg muscles will be getting a really
good workout and you'll probably be
going slowly because steep means at a
very high angle it's definitely not flat
and it's not a small rise it's quite a
quick rise so you're going up at a high
angle of course if you're riding down a
steep hill that's much easier you
probably won't have to work at all but
you might be going quite fast at the
bottom so steep means at a high angle
and then when we're thinking about
mountain climbing or hiking walking or
riding up a steep hill would be much
harder than walking or riding on a
flatland for example my grandpa had
trouble climbing the steep stairs
anyways we also said that these roads
are curving or curvy if something is
curving or we call it curving or curvy
it's not straight like curly hair is not
straight hair it might be as far as this
curly road is concerned it might Bend
around a certain thing or something else
like that
for example the road curves to the left
after the post office so notice in the
example sentence we've used this word as
a verb okay curvy lines curving lines
aren't straight if you curve you follow
that curvy path next up we also have the
word
- talking yes a cliff is a natural
feature of the landscape it's basically
where a part of the land has dropped
down very quickly maybe because of an
earthquake or weather erosion or
something like that and you have
basically a wall of rock that would be a
cliff you have standing at the top of
the cliff if you look down between your
toes you'll see the ground of far below
you it's dangerous of course standing on
the edge of a cliff but if you're a rock
climber maybe climbing up the face or
the front of the cliff would be an
exciting challenge but it's something
that you'll see out in nature where some
land has dropped down very quickly and
you have basically a very steep rock
wall for example Tim stood at the edge
of the cliff and took a picture
be careful Tim it was a hopefully he
wasn't taking a selfie while leaning
over the cliff bad bad idea by the way
off and cliffs fall straight into the
water there or - into the ocean so
really be careful okay don't fall off a
cliff the water is there but it probably
won't break your fall anyways let's go
ahead and finish up this part of our
lesson the next sentence says in fact
the roads are often used as practice for
the tour the falls by professional
cyclists so this is a cyclists heaven
okay you've got mountains and stuff like
that
well how demanding is the cycling going
to be there apparently
it's tough enough demanding enough and
challenging enough that professional
cyclists practice for the Tour de France
there by the way the most important
biking race or bike bicycling race in
the world is called the Tour de France
and apparently these professional
cyclists they practice here in Majorca
because the mountains there are perfect
for practice apparently now here we've
got professional cyclists I can call
myself a cyclist but I don't get paid
money to ride a bicycle around ok I'm an
amateur cyclists professional cyclists
get paid to ride their bikes and to race
their bikes against other cyclists for
example Nelson's cousin is a
professional dance
this person gets paid to dance okay and
of course we would only use this for
jobs or activities but you could do as a
hobby you would never say my friend is a
professional doctor because there are no
amateur doctors that's just weird but a
professional musician a professional
dancer a professional chef or something
like that shows you that this person is
doing it at a high level and they're
getting paid money it's their job
all right let's take a break we'll be
getting our bikes out maybe not no and
then we'll be back after this to find
out more about marvelous majorca Monica
Garcia Shanghai Bajaj Auto you know each
other yoga and faster to citizenship
Toshiba Pune your Kalimantan a sham my
time in Jeju channel targeting a magic
hat ascension to your wall or jiggity
founder should sit in church he should
attend town near Taisha to church and
see the decision should shut out anyway
I don't touch how once you tell now
tranquil cows on the Sun from han-shan
yay
that's just a Xiaolin Showdown
compatriots chinchou chinchou na young
my tongues audience she took one fatso
da vinci taru have not had to go from
fancy your choice I know should mean Ian
ship and the tour site on concludes your
choice I say Andrew Beatrice issue fine
Jo Fargo a joke how do we help dance it
bigger
relatively relatively take a food cigar
Shashank duty Hoosier pitch out she like
the material got such a steep steep
sashimi incision Ianto chowder notice
angle curve curved chute on Sebastian
One Tree Lodge Tsushima one true omen :
imagery on how to send Evans the curving
light on Sheehan says you know one
should agenda chat logs show that curvy
Cu rvy her vehicle SEO should one one
shoot Rita this is a dancer cliff cliff
should Shanghai choppy shaiiaja cannon
shooting will take a foam quarter
changes were seeing chunda oh my gosh
initiation weather ring just 10 see
whether home enjoy ing weathering say
it's okay ma fung-kwok the my erosion
erosion such a kingship foosh it was
emotion has a pain so er
as I am the only dancer professional
professional - essentially a ADA
Nauvoo nebula here you doman amateur -
Sekulow a ma te you are amateur should
you go and roll marvellous Majorca
however most of the islands visitors
come to see Mayorkas splendid coast
though there are several busy beach
resorts built specifically for tourists
you're better off exploring the over 260
beaches scattered around the island on
your own along the south coast you'll
find bone white sands and clear blue
waters seemingly made just for diving in
the East keep an eye out for hidden
Bay's that allow for peaceful swimming
even in high season
now these mountains sound great but I'm
not a professional cyclist and when I go
on vacation I want to relax okay so if
you want to relax and see the coast of
my York a beautiful coast hey don't
worry we've got a coast for you and it's
splendid yes however most of the islands
visitors come to see my orcas splendid
coast like I said before there are
coasts to be had there in Majorca and
they are splendid wonderful great
beautiful I think you guys get the idea
absolutely and when anyone's on a
Mediterranean Beach holiday they do want
to spend some time on the sand down by
the sea so there are a lot of options
for you if you want to do this it says
though there are several busy beach
resorts built specifically for tourists
you're better off exploring the over 260
beaches scattered around the island on
your own so there you go a lot of
opportunities for just exploring and
discovering maybe even your own private
little beach sure there are the beach
resorts these are the ones that you
might find down intending you have the
big hotel and the beach right in front
and you might have to pay to go on the
beach or stay in the hotel but you don't
have to worry about that in my Orca hop
on your bike ride out of the town for a
few minutes and you'll find one of 260
smaller beaches that you don't have to
pay for and as we said you might be the
only person there and if you do find
that perfect Beach what would it be like
well there are different types of
beaches in different places there in
Majorca I said there are coasts let's
talk about the south coast there and
then we'll talk about the East yes first
of all along the south coast you'll find
you'll find bone white sands and clear
blue waters seemingly made just for dyes
and a postcard if you go diving there
the waters clear you'll be able to see
everything as sand beach blue ocean blue
perfect for diving yes now in the East
keep an eye out for hidden Bay's that
allow for peace
swimming even in high season so let's
say you're a diver hey head to the South
if you're more of a person and for
peaceful swimming and privacy maybe
maybe head to the east there you go and
these hidden Bay's will be popular or
sorry you can find hidden Bay's even in
high season that means when the the
tourists are the largest number of
tourists are there high season would be
sort of in the mid to late summer high
you know prices might be higher but you
can still find your private little
swimming area very cool but there's
gonna be a lot more about my Orca
tomorrow so please don't hop on a plane
tonight come back and join us tomorrow
then you can head off with everything
you'll need to know about marvellous
Majorca we'll see you then bye bye well
when she hide out when want on shampoo
asia2010 is on quintet's in Sudama
nicole dirty da da da de Yoker those
ruching shall become a leader hi and
serological another high tension day
castrato sound CCO Leon below Chattooga
high channel
mitsuhashi to attend so she's not suited
to show me the height Han na ago she in
turn am being high and we cannot buy so
the shot on hello channel and Kingfisher
you know Tom Boonen so coz Amira hi Juan
Jose and said Rio 1g near catalog atiba
and Gina yo-yo how well Joanie enough
for her she runs boom white boom white
Tasha to buy soda number Waters water
stress when hydrogen motor the Saiga hi
Johanna strange doctrine is a gesture
cooling well for shushing no me Jonesy
Jonesy a Toni Basil hi Michele
[Music]
taja Howard she can eat playing show
come the one fat is she now - how the
one fight song did yoga bigger
better off there go on ones own
this anger should keep an eye out for
somebody or something this ego should
allow for the ownership high season how
many last better off better off
passage in Rome to the kitchen
jomkwan geun-hye was a hard drive no
matter how challenging widget with for
sure without say damn means challenge it
Ryan is better off without his
ex-girlfriend Ryan
mio-chan you cortical how sahaja Potter
fans oh hello
juni Kayla me curry Joe token called
how's that I can better off homie okay
tone to the ing sound town UOIT
immigrants resume oh I thought I
saw Jay how'd some Yahoo do for
roots him yeah
miru it's burning hot outside you'd be
better off staying at home why matura
Danny Trejo died a jolly Hannah did
Elijah on ones own on ones own gon tell
me ecology oh dude no it's ugly
drew Bob built the treehouse on his own
Bob Cousy too ignorant since Allah show
Jessie often goes to the movies on her
own Jesse James huncles that you can be
Hannah material I should keep an eye out
for somebody or something keep an eye
out for submission Manhattan to show the
Oh II mean she Jewish of the true
namaho me incursion horseshoe the matter
via tree I said to be and hashcode
Inventure wall Veeru Sean is keeping an
eye out for a cheap used car
chanted amici di pH on gucchy tanto chef
Joe Pesci La Juicy dirty - I found out
in the hall the Oh III engine turning is
a joy - Zoe - total don't see Josh and
amici the wisdom the truth a lot Hannah
did Alicia she allow for
pay me known to allow for that didn't
happy I'll xuxa machungwa Cunha
logically to me yeah liberal their new
furniture arrangement allows for more
space
Thomas address in the Python version ah
hey Ogando donggeun how to her lashes
she high season means the high season
recalled Egidio or Shibuya 1g
the mellow season Joe Pesci 10g
challenge it cheap flights are difficult
to find during high season say want
attention and other ket powder Hannah me
sounds gentleman tell me on Saturday low
okay what's wrong with you sorry okay
haha did you pull Emily was her
intent don't harm my gear so she shot a
dialog box oh my god I read Sunday haha
[Music]
you weren't serious when you said you
were quitting this job yesterday right
I kid you not I won the lottery I was
super rich now but what I want some
money
Oh Oh miss rich lady is back can I have
somebody no all right so I thought you
were done you thought you're quitting
yeah this is it or incision just hide
zoomin tight precious that we shall play
like Joyce yet oh my gosh Wow yeah I'm
not here for you though yeah
Wow mmm anyway kid you not so dare when
fired she quiet I kid you not
Susan how that easily just that I'm not
kidding
cuz I kid you not the woman vibrator I'm
not Jim - I'm Toby it doesn't call you
dad you know I did you knock the drill
head I kid you know it's not doesn't
like a fourth thing money for my to wear
so team so we can jam this kid you not
yeah okay or you could say no joke no
joke want him in there come on Jeff or
I'm not messing around
Oh one time out there gonna juice I'm
messing around Justin yes sir each zone
come on shower just so was i won they
just didn't push or zegermans shadows
then right up on it stop messing around
get serious yes don't gadget or just
serve you sir I'm serious yeah we're
very serious about you learning English
so if you have any problems Calvin drove
Lyla I kid you not I kid you not no joke
no joke
I'm not messing around I'm not messing
around I'm serious I'm serious
[Music]