[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hey everybody
i'm shane today we're looking at part
one
of the duck build platypus
the impossible animal and the vocabulary
words are
species species it is said that there
are over 9
000 bird species in the world poisonous
poisonous dan ate poisonous mushrooms by
accident
and had to go to the hospital amazed
amazed i was amazed that so many people
attended the concert
gene gene according to scientists
at least eight genes influence the final
color
of eyes
mirror you call that a mountain it is a
mere
hill okay so we're talking about this
impossible animal so you called it yes
the
duck build well what
makes it so impossible looking
is that it kind of looks like a duck
because of its bill
and its feet that's right but it also
has like the tail of a beaver
okay and it has the body of like an
otter so it's kind of like something
that you know you would see
in the in a kid's drawing yeah like a
kid will just draw something really
weird
and say it's an animal and you're like
that's not an animal
and it's an egg-laying mammal
which is so unique yes that's right well
that's because i think
it shares genes not only with mammals
but also with reptiles and birds that's
right
so they lay eggs right because usually
we know that mammals they don't lay eggs
it's like the definition of a mammal
exactly so that's what was so surprising
when they discovered this
animal and i think a long time ago they
used to be
much bigger right and they have become
you know like
smaller over the years right evolution
right
yeah they're adapting to the environment
that's pretty cool let's learn more
about this impossible animal
the duck build a platypus
the duck-billed platypus the impossible
animal
the duck-billed platypus is unique in
the animal kingdom
native to tasmania and southeastern
australia
this egg-laying mammal has the bill and
feet of a duck
the wide tail of a beaver and the body
of an otter
the male of the species even has
poisonous stingers
on the heels of its back feet
[Music]
today's lesson is called the duck build
platypus the
impossible animal part one
hi everyone my name is jeff and i'm
mike how does it exist if it's
impossible well it's just that
weird and actually when you do look at
lists or you know programs or
anything you might see about really
strange bizarre
animals that are almost too weird to
believe
the duckbilled platypus is right up
there at the top
of the list but impossible well it's
just really strange
really close to impossible close to him
somehow
someone told you about it and you didn't
know it was real you'd say that's not
real but it is but it is yeah i've heard
that the duck bill
platypus is a mammal
but it lays eggs which is weird that's
something that usually never happens but
let's not
get ahead of ourselves let's start
reading today's lesson
the duck build platypus is unique
in the animal kingdom it's unique
it's one of a kind so
should it exist based on the fact
that it's this unique probably not
but here we have it the duck build
platypus
and when you find out where it's from
that kind of explains why it might be so
unusual
native to tasmania and southeastern
australia
this egg-laying mammal has the bill
and feet of a duck the wide
tail of a beaver and the body
of an otter and get this hey
the male of the species
ease even has poisonous stingers
on the heels of its back feet it's also
very poisonous
wow so you got the duck
bill and you got the laying
oh my gosh what a weird creature but
also
a very cute creature i should say
anyways let's go ahead and talk about
the word
species scientists group animals
into different categories usually you go
from
big to small okay you start out with a
kingdom like
animals and you move all the way down
until you can't
separate animals any further okay when
you've gone the furthest you can
you've gotten to a species
okay a species of animal is a group of
animal okay the members of which can
mate with one another and produce viable
youth okay they can make babies and
those babies can make babies
as well like dogs and cats they're not
in the same species okay that's just not
the way that it works for example
it is said that there are over 9 000
bird species
in the world that's a lot of species
that is a lot of species absolutely and
we also have this word
poisonous it's an adjective that just
says
it has poison there is poison
in that thing something that if you get
it into your body
it can make you sick or possibly even
kill you and of course in the animal
world we talk about poisonous animals
spiders or certain types of little frogs
or snakes
things like this lions are very
dangerous
sharks are very dangerous but not
because they're poisonous
because they have big sharp teeth but
some smaller animals and some types of
plants
mushrooms for example if you eat them if
they
bite you if they put their poison inside
you
it can make you very sick they are
poisonous for example
dan ate poisonous mushrooms by accident
and had to go to the hospital yeah many
mushrooms can be poisonous
don't go wild mushroom picking unless
you're very
sure about what you're doing all right
let's take a break and then we'll be
back with
nature's freak show
[Music]
v-i-a-b-l-e
the duck-billed platypus the impossible
animal
the platypus truly is like something out
of a child's imagination
it's no wonder that in the late 18th
century when the first
samples were brought back to europe from
the australian continent
scientists of the time didn't believe
they were real
okay earlier i said that the duck
build platypus kind of sounds like
something that
comes out of science fiction well
more precisely the platypus here
truly is like something out of a child's
imagination i would say that's more
or a fairy tale or something like that
the platypus is
truly is like is truly
is like something out of a child's
imagination and
actually a lot of people didn't believe
it when they first heard about it it's
no wonder or it's no surprise that in
the late
18th century when the first samples were
brought back to europe
from the australian continent scientists
of the time
didn't believe they were real they
thought someone had just taken some
different animals and
put it together and said look we found
this body of this strange animal
and a lot of scientists in europe who
didn't see it
living said that's not real you just
made that up in your lab or something
like that this is what happened
in the late 18th century the first
explorers going down there to australia
caught some animals brought them home
some of them i guess didn't live
they only brought the bodies back and so
these scientists in paris and london and
places like that would look at these
things and go that can't be
real you just put together a bunch of
different animals and you're trying to
sell us a whole story it's not
true that doesn't jive without european
science like a mermaid weird australian
animals no way we're not accepting this
anyways folks with that it's time for us
to take a short break but don't go away
we have more for you on the duck bill
platypus after this yeah
are cute fluffy and cuddly
it's no wonder that people love keeping
them
as pets
the duck build platypus the impossible
animal
more recently researchers were amazed to
discover
that platypuses share genes with not
only mammals
but also reptiles and birds it turns out
that these odd creatures split off from
the rest of the mammal class
some 166 million years ago
during the age of the dinosaurs ancient
platypuses were about a meter long
but over time they got smaller today the
average platypus measures a mere 50
centimeters from its head
to the tip of its tail and weighs in at
around 1.5 kilograms
anyways let's let's forget about the
past and talk about
right now real science yeah more science
real science right now more recently
researchers were amazed to discover
that platypuses shared genes
with not only mammals but
also reptiles and birds so
if you're gonna classify this particular
animal based on its genetics
is it a reptile is it a mammal
is it a bird it's all of those is it all
of those
weird by the way if you are amazed by
something
you are usually really surprised by that
thing
in a good way you're amazed you're
shocked in a good way
for example i was amazed that so many
people
attended the concert okay well yeah and
if you didn't want them you might have
been
horrified or shocked or something like
that but you said this is a good thing
so you were amazed and sure when you're
a scientist and you make some incredible
discovery that's not you know a terrible
thing
you put on your genes you will be amazed
and especially
it might be involved with jeans but
we're not talking about blue jeans those
pants
cowboy wear no not cowboy cool
that's not j-e-a-n
those are j-e-a-n genes these are
n e genes we're talking about the
building blocks
of life protein dna the things that
create life yeah when we're talking
about dna
we're talking about genes and we're
talking about parents having children
and passing on traits like blonde hair
or dark eyes or
things like that we're talking about
genes and yes
animals of course you know will give
their genes to their children and
different species of animals sometimes
share
genes right we look different from
gorillas
or chimpanzees those those apes but we
share
many of the same genes making us similar
but not quite the same so apparently a
platypus is similar to birds
and mammals and things like that we
humans we're mammals but we don't have
many of the same genes that birds would
because we're quite different if we
share genes with uh
ducks we might have a duck bill feathers
but uh we don't we don't quack unlike
females
duck filled platypus exactly and
according to scientists
at least eight genes influence the final
color of
eyes of all the genes that go up to
making a people
making a person eight different genes
can affect the color of your eyes that's
a very interesting fact
anyways let's dive deeper into this
whole gene
thing it turns out that these odd
creatures split off from the rest of the
mammal
class like us some 166
million years ago during the age
of the dinosaurs wow yeah
just that long ago humans have been our
own special group for like half a
million years or something like that yep
now
ancient platypuses were about
a meter long but over time
they got smaller oh yeah animals over
the
over the course of the last oh 100
million uh 150 million years have
generally gotten smaller
that's true oh pretty much across the
board so that makes sense so there you
go a meter long
duck build platypus would be a little
bit of a scarier type of
that would be a big duck-billed platter
if it was angry with you
all right well let's move on and see
what it says next today the average
platypus
measures a mere 50 centimeters
from its head to the tip of its tail and
weighs in at around
1.5 kilograms these are not
large animals 50 centimeters that's
like half a meter that's half a meter
yeah
pretty small anyways here we have the
word mir the word
mir means only or just it's
that's all you have to know it's these
animals are
just 50 centimeters okay
you can measure them from there from the
head to the tip of the tail
and they'll only or just be 50
centimeters long that's all there is to
it
for example you call that a mountain
it's a mere hill
that's something they might say in
australia all right folks
let's go ahead and end today's lesson
well i'll see you next time chaps
he split off from the other hikers and
ended up getting lost
[Music]
foreign
there is an area at the zoo to keep the
birds that can't fly
emus are large birds similar to
ostriches
in fact they are the second tallest
birds in the world
after ostriches they can grow to be just
under 2 meters tall only 6 months
after being hatched from their eggs
emirs can't fly
but they can run really fast for a short
time
they can reach up to 50 kilometers per
hour
male emus take care of the eggs and take
a break from eating for weeks
male and female emus look very similar
these birds are representative of
australia
the government puts emus on coins
and the coat of arms for the country
their legs don't have any feathers their
eyesight and hearing
are really good at keeping them safe
from predators
at the zoo they have nothing to worry
about
emus usually live between 10 to
30 years we have one named larry that is
15 years old
here is more information
adapt cindy tried hard to
adapt herself to the new school
camouflage an octopus can
camouflage itself to hide from other
animals
balance lisa lost her balance
and fell from the chair eyesight
sam has excellent eyesight so
he doesn't need glasses flightless
penguins are flightless birds
hearing rick's hearing is bad
so you have to yell when you talk to him
incubate birds incubate their eggs
by sitting on them nurture
zoe will stay at home and nurture her
children
overheat my car
overheated and broke down
unsuited he is unsuited for this job
let's find someone else thank you for
watching today's lesson
we'll see you here next time