[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome
everybody i'm shane
today we're looking at part one of
putting pen to
paper the history of ballpoint pens
and the vocabulary words are invention
invention the telephone is one of the
most
important inventions of all time i agree
leak leak air is leaking out of the tire
and i don't know what to do about it
familiar familiar food delivery drivers
are a familiar site
on the streets of most big cities
inconvenience inconvenience my computer
crashed this morning which is a major
inconvenience for me transfer
transfer i transferred the money into
your bank account thank you
inspiration inspiration the artist says
he gets his inspiration from his daily
life
so we're talking about ballpoint pen
ballpoint pens yes because they have a
ball
right that's right kind of like the key
so the guys what a great invention
the guy who invented it is laszlo bureau
spiro that's right
yeah so before before that they would
use
fountain pens but i like fountain pens
dough well
they're very cool yes they're very cool
and they're kind of retro
uh-huh right but have you ever used one
i have used it but
they're not that easy to use and i have
to say the inconvenience is that you
have to
refill the ink all the time and
sometimes
it would you know probably smudge
writing so it's
not exactly that convenient but it just
feels really cool because
no one really uses it anymore right but
the reason they started
used wanted to change this type of
writing instrument to another one was
because of the inconveniences
that's right so the way the ballpoint
pen works
is that the ink is kind of like inside a
little tube and when the ball is pushed
down it gets
the little ball wet with the ink
that's right and it's a constant supply
i think
it doesn't really smudge yeah but it's
pretty cool where he got his idea from
because one time i remember
he saw some kids playing with the marble
and it went through the puddle and he
saw like a line
you know of like you know muddy water
he's like hey maybe i can turn that
into a ballpoint pen that's super
interesting
okay let's learn more about the
ballpoint pen all right enjoy
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
ballpoint pens may not seem like
anything special but they've made our
lives more convenient than you might
realize
the story behind their invention may
also surprise you
today's lesson is called putting pen
to paper the history of ball
point pens part one hello everyone my
name is jeff
and i'm mike now if you look around you
right now look at the desk and maybe
you're sitting at school or at home
you'll probably see a nice little pen
lying around on a table
in a drawer maybe in your pocket and
there's a good chance
that will be a ball point pen they're
cheap they're convenient you always got
one around
if you're like me there's a drawer at
home full of old ballpoint pens
so we use these things all the time but
we never
really think about them but you're old
enough do you remember when you had to
like go to school and write on a slate
with a piece of chalk
no do you remember not having more point
no i don't remember not having a
ballpoint pen
anyways ballpoint pens are definitely an
improvement on them they are
yeah ballpoint pens yes
may not seem like anything special
but they've made our lives
more convenient than you might
realize yes ballpoint pens
are really super cool
and you know what they've got a super
cool
story too wonderful yeah the story
behind their invention may also
surprise you so you know how they came
to be
where they came from who created them or
invented them
all of this will probably be unknown to
you and will also
when we tell you surprise you by the way
invent
that's the verb when you invent
something you create
something that never existed before
okay now what you create what you invent
that's your invention for example
the telephone is one of the most
important inventions of
all time which is true
all right folks with that it's time for
us to take a short break but don't go
away
we will be back after
foreign
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
laszlo bureau a hungarian journalist is
said to have invented the ballpoint pen
in 1938 before the ballpoint pen
people used fountain pens these
old-fashioned pens had to be refilled
often
and they leaked and smudged easily since
biro spent much of his day writing
he was all too familiar with these
inconveniences
[Music]
okay the history of the ballpoint pen
takes us to hungary
h u n g a
roi it it's a country i'm not actually
hungry anyways laszlo biro
a hungarian journalist a journalist
from hungary the country of hungary is
said to have invented the ballpoint pen
in 1938.
all right so not that long ago so what
were people using before the ballpoint
pen
came along like a feather well they they
did use that but
after that they had another more modern
pen before the ballpoint pen
people used fountain pens ah these are
the ones with that
metal tip and liquid ink that you have
to fill
quite frequently they spill places you
know
they can be a little bit inconvenient
but they were better
than the feather they were better than
hammering words into stone but fountain
pens yeah most people had those
they cost a bit more you had to be more
careful with them
and as we read these old fashioned pens
had to be refilled
often and they leaked and smudged
easily so yes these old fountain pens
they would
sometimes leak they wouldn't explode
shooting
ink all over the place no but it would
come out of them slowly maybe in your
pocket or
on the paper you're writing on because a
leak is a very
small amount or a small thing that's
escaping all right we're not talking
about
a huge amount we're talking a small
amount through probably a small
hole for example if you're riding your
bicycle
and you have a small leak that means the
air is
coming out of your tire very slowly as
it says in our example sentence
air is leaking out of the tire and i
don't know what to do well you can patch
it
cover up that little hole and stop that
leak
or if it's leaking slowly maybe ride to
a bike repair shop and buy a new tire
but you might be able to ride
for a little while longer because it's a
leak it's just coming out
slowly since biro spent much of his day
writing he was all too familiar
with these inconveniences those
old-fashioned pens were pains
and he knew all about these pains by the
way
if you are familiar with something
you know all about that thing
okay if you're if you're familiar with
someone you know that person
pretty well if you're unfamiliar with
them
not so well for example food delivery
drivers
are a familiar sight on the streets of
most
big cities okay and also
what's an inconvenience an inconvenience
is a small
but kind of annoying problem it's not a
major problem that's going to
totally change your life in a bad way
but it's one of those things that makes
you go
ah like that and then you'll move on and
you'll find a way to fix it if you need
to get
money out of the bank and you go to your
local atm machine and it's
it doesn't work for some reason well
that's an inconvenience you'll just have
to walk down to the next bank
and find one but if the whole banking
computer system breaks down
and you can't get any money out for 24
hours
that could be more than an inconvenience
that could be a problem
especially if you really need money at
that time but a small
problem that just makes your life a
little more difficult
but it's a problem you can easily work
your way around eventually
that would be an inconvenience my
computer crashed this
morning which is a major inconvenience
for me yeah it'll work tonight
but my boss or my teacher is waiting for
an important report
now i'll have to call them and explain
why
and say sorry but eventually the
computer will work
thank you very much for that there you
go anyways folks with that it's time for
us to take a short break but don't go
away we'll be right back well that's an
inconvenience
the house is said to have several secret
passageways
quill
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
many inventors had tried to design
similar types of pens before b-roll
but none had succeeded biro's ballpoint
pen design used a small ball instead of
a nib
when the ball is pressed onto paper it
rolls to pick up
ink inside the pen and transfer it onto
paper
the inspiration for this design came
from an unexpected source
one day biro happened to see children
playing with marbles
a boy rolled a marble through a puddle
creating a line of water on the street
and giving biro the idea for the
ballpoint design
however the real breakthrough came when
biro got help from his brother
who was a scientist he developed a thick
fast drying
ink for biro's pen
wow what an inventor this uh bureau
guy was and i'm being serious
get this many inventors had
tried to design similar types of pens
before bureau but none
not a one had succeeded
bureau's ballpoint pen design
used a small ball
instead of a
nib oh okay well yeah fountain pens used
a nib that would basically
channel ink right down to the end and
that's what you would write with
but biro used a ball that kind of
spread the ink as you moved it over the
page or as we read when the ball
is pressed onto paper it rolls to pick
up
ink inside the pen and transfer it
onto the paper think about if there's
you know
paint or water on the ground and a car
rolls through it
it carries that water or paint in a
straight line it transfers
that water or paint down the road in a
line
there you go it goes from one place
to another it's being transferred
now very often well at least when i was
growing up
you would call some place like an office
or something like that
and you would be transferred
between departments let's say on the
telephone so
no one would be hanging up on you okay
the phone call wouldn't
end they would just be transferring you
from
one person to another until you got to
the
right person okay so you're trying to
make contact with the right person
you're trying to get transferred to the
right person but here the idea is a
little bit
simpler there is ink inside of the pen
and you want that ink onto the paper so
you go ahead
and you press down using that ballpoint
pen
and you're able to transfer that ink
onto the paper how simple is that
for example i transferred the money
into your bank account by the way yes in
these situations you would say transfer
and not transport okay
transfer is the word of choice here
anyways the inspiration for this
design came from an
unexpected source so there you go
everybody else was stuck with this nib
idea but hey this bureau guy he got
some inspiration from an unexpected
place
where you might not think that he would
get an idea
for a new type of pen and that's what an
ins that's what
inspiration is it's an idea for
something
new inventors need inspiration they
see something in the world that needs to
be fixed and there's not a machine
for it and then they think and think and
suddenly like a flash of light it comes
to them
i know what i'm going to do so an
inventor might need
inspiration for some new machine or new
technology
artists also will get inspiration for a
new
painting or a new song or a new story
idea
no one's done it before they're just
walking around or
sitting around or washing the dishes
when suddenly
a new a new melody a new bit of music
pops into their head or a new idea for a
painting or a sculpture
whatever something new and creative is
born
in an instant that is inspiration or
what you see
gives you that inspiration that magic
creative spark
for example the artist says he gets his
inspiration from his daily life
inspiration that could happen but hey
with bureau it it did happen
okay what was the inspiration for his
pen it
it came from everyday life one day
biro happened to see children playing
with marbles oh those little little
glass balls
that the kids nothing special played
with
now a boy rolled a marble
through a puddle creating a line of
water on the street and
giving biro the idea for the ballpoint
design
oh so the ball went through this puddle
this small amount of water
rolled down probably a dry street and
made a nice
dark line of water there you go i'll
just do the same thing with a pen
and some ink however the real
breakthrough this that was the
inspiration
but the real breakthrough came when
bureau got help from his brother
who was a scientist because of course
you need the right kind of ink and his
brother
says he developed a thick fast
drying ink for beerus pen yeah it had to
be
thick because the other type of ink from
the fountain pen would just leak out
but also you want it to be fast drying
because one of the problems with
fountain pens is that
you often would spread that ink with
your hand and that's what make
would make it so messy so thick it stays
in the pen
fast drying when it hits the paper it
dries quickly
no mess there you go brilliant amazing
okay folks that's it for today's lesson
and it's time for us to say bye bye
take care of your ballpoint pens
kate didn't order coffee she ordered
tea instead kate milden coffee
cafe
challenge
[Music]
hunters in the australian outback use a
tool called a
boomerang to go on a hunt with
aboriginal bushmen
when you throw it the right way it flies
back to you
that way you don't have to go find it
over and over again
the bent shape makes it fly in a curved
direction boomerangs have also been used
as weapons for
tens of thousands of years most people
think of australia
when they see a boomerang and they are
popular souvenirs for tourists who visit
the land down under but actually
the oldest boomerang was found in a cave
in poland
it was dated back to about 20 000
years ago there are a few designs of
boomerangs that fly
in different ways some don't fly back in
a curve
but they can be thrown faster and fly
further distances
you have to hold it vertically and throw
it at a 10 to 20 degree
angle when you release it
here is more information
bent i sat on my glasses
so now they are bent club
the golf player uses the club to hit the
ball
curved you must drive slowly
on the curved road ellipse
the earth goes around the sun in an
ellipse
origin germany is the origin
of hamburgers axis
the planet spins on its axis
soar the bird soars
high in the sky thrower
the thrower of the ball broke the window
weapon they are testing a new weapon
wooden the wooden house is
very old i hope you enjoyed today's
lesson
hope to see you again soon