[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hey everybody
i'm batman
today we're looking at part one of i can
do it
i'm batman and the vocabulary words are
psychological psychological treatments
for psychological conditions
have improved in recent years
frustration
frustration the constant construction
delays
have been a big source of frustration
for us
anxiety anxiety pete has been feeling
a lot of anxiety over his decision to
break up with his girlfriend
investigate investigate the company
created a team
to investigate what caused the accident
at its factory researcher
researcher through their experiments
researchers have learned a lot
about the disease so we're talking about
i can do it
i'm batman what does that mean
so this is a very interesting like
psychological
effect okay that's called the batman
effect
the batman effect so it basically it's
like you imagine
that you are a fictional character
usually somebody who has like
super powers or who's very very
strong or amazing and then you kind of
pretend you're that person when you're
doing things that you
need to do especially some challenges
that you're facing
and usually when you think with that
kind of mentality
you would usually perform better right
so they did an experiment right with
some kids
that's right and they divided the kids
up in three different groups and then
they were given tasks
to complete right so the first group i
think uh they were told to ask
the children to ask themselves the
question uh am i working hard
for the first group and the second group
was you know thinking from
a third person narrative it's like is
sam working hard
is shane working hard that's right but
the third group
you're trying to pretend that you are a
fictional character for example batman
is batman working hard obviously not
hard enough because batman will work
really hard
and that has superpowers yeah and so
those those
kids actually performed better that's
right
so that's really interesting that's our
interesting psychological effect
i'm definitely going to try it well
maybe it can be well you can be batman
why not
wonder woman i want wonder woman okay
cool
okay enjoy today's lesson
i can do it i'm batman when you're faced
with a challenging situation
have you ever tried to encourage
yourself by thinking
i can do it i'm batman that might seem
like a ridiculous statement to make
but it's actually the basis of a
surprising psychological effect that can
help you get over feelings of
frustration
and anxiety
[Music]
today's lesson is called i can
do it i'm batman
part one hello everyone my name is jeff
and my name is mike i can do it
i'm batman is the name
of this article it's not just a line
from a movie or a comic book
it's the title of our article so let's
find out how you can do it
if you are batman but i'm not batman
so i don't but no you are bad man batman
is a superhero but he's one of these
super heroes who does
not actually have super powers i see
what you
mean he's able to do amazing things
he's bad he said you can be batman he
said i can do it i'm
superman well no you're not superman you
weren't born on another planet you can't
fly batman though he's just a normal guy
but he's also
incredibly rich that's
true all right well let's find out more
about this anyways when you're faced
with a challenging situation okay have
you ever
tried to encourage yourself by thinking
i can do it i'm batman
have i ever tried to encourage myself by
saying that
no i have not well okay okay that might
seem like a ridiculous statement to make
right
that yeah but it's actually the basis
of a surprising psychological effect
that can help you get over feelings of
frustration and anxiety wow
really i'm batman okay interesting
if there's some studies that show that
this is true well
i'm all ears i have an open mind i will
listen to it so yeah it might seem like
a ridiculous statement
to make or ridiculous a strange a funny
a bizarre thing to think or say i can do
it i'm batman but
yeah it's actually the basis of a
surprising psychological
effect and when we use this adjective
psychological
we're talking about the mind about
thinking about behavior
about your emotions about that kind of
thing so
if you're trying to lift a car and you
say i can do it i'm batman it won't make
your muscles get bigger
or turn you into a superhero but it
might change your mental
attitude your mental state the kind of
way it would be like i'm good enough i'm
smart enough i can do this you know say
that to yourself and it could have a
psychological effect an effect on your
mind
for example treatments for psychological
conditions have improved in recent years
okay next let's talk about frustration
frustration i
can't do it i want to i want to do
trying so hard yeah just think
okay if you want okay if you want a good
picture of frustration
picture that rubik's cube that
has not been finished since 1987. for
that video game boss you just can't
beat that game you haven't beat since
the rubik's cube you haven't been able
to solve since 1987.
these things that you want to do but you
can't
and they leave you frustrated you're not
hitting your head against
your head against the wall to frustrate
would be the verb
frustration is the feeling that's the
noun for example
the constant construction delays have
been
a big source of frustration for us oh
we can't finish our work because they
won't stop
absolutely and frustration can lead to
problems
with your psychology right problems with
your feelings and your
thinking and that could lead to anxiety
now that's a psychological condition
because anxiety is stress
it's worry it's that feeling that things
are bad and they're only going to get
worse and nothing's going to go well and
i'm so nervous and stressed out and i
can't relax i can't sleep i can't eat
i'm filled with anxiety i need to do
some yoga
i need to calm down maybe take a little
holiday
you know relax a little bit because
anxiety
is that feeling of stress and worry like
you have problems and you can't shut
them off in your mind
you're always thinking always worrying
and it's affecting your life
for example pete has been feeling a lot
of anxiety
over his decision to break up with his
girlfriend
all right well let's take a break we can
do it we're batman
and we'll be back and nothing's going to
stop us
except the joker maybe i'm batman hello
um
i can do it i'm batman the effect which
has become known as
the batman effect was first formally
investigated in a 2016
study at the university of minnesota
researchers gave a group of six-year-old
children a difficult task to complete on
a computer
[Music]
i could do it you can do it i'm back
because you are
i'm a batman you're batman kind of
batman i can't be wonder woman
i suppose yeah but anyway yeah believing
that you can do it and saying you are
batman or
wonder woman possibly well it's a real
thing but again
you can say i'm wondering a wonder woman
but wonder woman
has super powers she's like a goddess
whereas batman is just
a rich human regular human anyways
stuff with with cool stuff the effect
which has become known as the batman
effect
good name was first formally
investigated
in 2000 in a 2016 study
at the university of minnesota and yes
sometimes these studies they come up
with with some very
boring names hmm so people
feel more confident about themselves
when they say
i can do it i'm batman a positive
reinforcement effect let's call this the
positive reinforcement effect or oh i
don't know the
batman effect that's that's another word
associated with that
with this anyways anyways if we are
talking about
um research let's say if we're talking
about studies let's say
usually we're talking about things that
people have done smart people like
scientists
people these people have looked into
something to learn a lot about it
they have investigated these things yes
when you investigate
something you look into that thing you
study that thing deeply in order to
learn more about it you can be a
scientist
and investigate something to learn about
it
let's say you want to learn more about
physics or some subject or something
like that
for example a company created a team to
investigate
what caused the accident at its factory
detective i batman they're here way to
go
all right now researchers in order to
investigate the batman effect what did
they exactly do they didn't read a bunch
of comic books or watch a bunch of
batman movies no
researchers gave a group of six-year-old
children
a difficult task to complete on a
computer
alright so this kind of thing that would
be frustrating a difficult
task it's not easy to do it's easy to
mess up and
make mistakes so they gave a bunch of
kids six-year-old children
something difficult to do or to complete
on a computer and we can imagine that a
lot of them won't do it they'll get
frustrated
this was the study this is what the
researchers were doing researchers will
investigate things
not a detective but the same kind of
idea they're looking into something they
have a lot of questions
they're looking for answers they use
tests and science and information
and all of that kind of stuff when
scientists want to know anything about
anything
what people do how animals behave what
kind of medicine will
fight covid researchers will do studies
smart people will do tests in other
words for example
through their experiments researchers
have learned a lot
about the disease scientists doing
experiments
researchers doing studies they want to
answer
questions there you go all right folks
with that it's time for us to
take a break we'll see you after the
break
detective i'm batman he's batman
is
i can do it i'm batman the children were
then divided into three groups
in the first the children were told to
regularly ask themselves
am i working hard in the second they
were told to ask themselves the same
question
in the third person as in is sam working
hard
and in the third group they were told to
pretend they were a hard-working
fictional character
and to ask themselves if the character
was working hard
for example they could ask themselves is
batman working hard
remarkably the children in the third
group performed by far the best
and took fewer breaks than the children
in the other two groups
okay let's get back into things we were
talking about a
study some research before the break
there now the children
in this research were then divided
into three groups so they're all doing
the same task
but three groups now three groups okay
okay but they're all doing the same
thing yes right now right
in the first the children were told to
regularly ask themselves am i
working hard this is difficult am i
working hard i'm working hard i'm having
trouble but am i working hard
okay am i working hard in the second
they were told to ask themselves the
same question
in the third person so not am
i is he as in is sam
working hard so if i was doing it is
mike
working hard is jeff working and you're
thinking not
am i working about am is is okay so like
another person is watching me do this
job i know where this is going this is
this is awesome
okay and in the third group they were
told to pretend
they were a hard-working fictional
character
superhero and to ask themselves
if the character was working
hard now a hard-working
fictional character right who's not a
superhero with super powers
well i mean hard-working guy he this
person
this person has to work hard because
they don't have superpowers
who comes to mind batman
for example they could ask themselves is
batman working hard you could like is
james bond
working hard you know something like
that
interesting so am i working hard is
mike working hard is batman working i'm
batman am i
working hard and what happened well
remarkably
amazingly the children in the third
group the batman group
performed by far by far
the best and took fewer breaks than the
children
in the other two groups this is a
difficult task
and the kids who thought of themselves
as batman doing it
they did better not just a little bit a
lot
better by far the best and they worked
harder they took
fewer breaks than the kids in the other
group does batman take breaks
no no does he fail no no of course not
so
that's pretty cool the batman effect
it's a thing
all right folks with that that's it for
this part of our lesson
we'll see you next time
i don't know if it's a good idea
i don't know whether it's a good idea
and today
after hours of shopping they took a
break
at a coffee shop
[Music]
today i'm going to introduce a great
20th century american named
martin luther king jr also known as
mlk king was a civil rights leader
during the 1950s
and 60s he inspired countless people
with his ideas
of freedom and peace specifically
he used peaceful methods to protest the
unfair treatment of african americans
king also spread messages of faith
and love did you know that king was
influenced by mahatma gandhi king never
met gandhi
but he spent one month in india and met
gandhi's family
when he returned to the united states he
spread gandhi's ideas
and made them popular thanks to martin
luther king jr
people in the united states began to
open their eyes
to the terrible treatment of african
americans in the south
finally the government made laws to
protect the civil rights of
all americans thanks to men
like both king and gandhi the world
has become a better place
here is more information
achieve gary achieved so much last year
the man was arrested for driving too
fast
assault the woman was assaulted
in the parking lot former
gina is a former dancer
inspire the book was inspired by a
brave woman
judge you can't judge a book
by its cover owner
the owner of this store is a nice man
protest there will be a big protest
next week
protester 5 000 protesters went to the
protest yesterday
slave slaves were finally free
in 1865.
thanks for joining us today i hope you
learned a lot
we'll catch you later
see you next time