it is not death most people are afraid
of it is getting to the end of life only
to realize that you never truly lived
there was a study done a hospital study
on 100 elderly people facing death close
to their last breath they were asked to
reflect about their life's biggest
regret nearly all of them said they
regretted not the things they did but
the things they didn't do the risks they
never took the dreams they didn't pursue
I ask you would your last words be if
only I had hey you wake up why do you
exist life is not meant to simply work
wait for the weekend and pay rent no no
I don't know much but I know this every
person on this earth has a gift and I
apologize to the black community but I
can no longer pretend Martin Luther King
that man never had a dream that dream
had him see people don't choose dreams
dreams choose them so the question I'm
getting to is do you have the courage to
grab the dream that picked you that be
fits you and grips you a would you let
it get away and slip through
you know I learned the fact about
airplanes the other day now this was
this was so surprised and see I was
talking to a pilot and he told me that
many of his passengers they planes are
dangerous to fly in but he said actually
it is a lot more dangerous for a plane
to stay on the ground I said what like
how does that sound well he said he said
because on the ground the plane starts
to rust malfunction and we're much
faster than it ever would if it was in
the air as I walked away I thought yeah
makes total sense
because planes were built to live in the
skies and every person was built to live
out the dream they have inside so it is
perhaps the saddest loss to live a life
on the ground without ever taking off
see most of us are afraid of the thief
that comes in the night to steal all of
our things but there's a thief in your
mind who is after your dreams
his name is doubt if you see him call
the cops and keep him away from the kids
cuz he is wanted for murder for he is
killed more dreams than failure ever did
he wears many disguises and like a virus
will leave you blind and divided and
turned you into a kinda see kinda is
lethal
you know what kinda is it's a lot of
kind of people you kind of want a career
change you kind of want to get straight
A's you kind of want to get in shape
simple math no numbers to crunch if you
kind of want something that you will
kind of get the results you want what is
your dream what ignites that spark you
can't kind of want that
you gotta wonder with every part of your
whole heart would you struggle yeah yeah
you will struggle no way around it you
will fall many times but who's counting
just remember there's no such thing as a
smooth Mountain if you want to make it
to the top then there are sharp ridges
that must be stepped over there will be
times you get stressed and things you
get depressed over but let me tell you
something Steven Spielberg was rejected
from film school three times three times
but he kept going the television execs
fired Oprah said she wasn't fit for TV
but she kept going critics told beyond
saving she couldn't sing she went
through depression but she kept going
struggle and criticisms are
prerequisites for greatness that is the
law of this universe and no one escapes
it because pain is life but you can
choose what type either the pain on the
road to success or the pain of being
haunted with regret
you are my advice don't think twice we
have been given a gift then we call life
so don't blow it you are not defined by
your past instead you are born anew in
each moment so own it now
sometimes you gotta leap and grow your
wings on the way down you better get the
shot off before the clock runs out
because they know over time in life no
do-over and I know I sound like I'm
preaching on speaking with force but if
you don't use your gift then you sail
not only yourself but the whole world
sure so what invention that you have
buried in your mind what idea what cure
what skill do you have inside to bring
out to this universe you need meaning
one verse meaning song you have a part
to play in this song so grab that
microphone and be brave sing your heart
out on life stage you cannot go back in
and make a brand new beginning but you
can start now
and make a brand new ending