[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen welcome
everybody I am Shane today we're looking
at part 1 of gal gadot a wonder of a
woman and the vocabulary words are
courageous courageous the leader is a
courageous woman who isn't afraid to
stand up for what she believes in
athletic athletic due to his athletic
build many people think that Johnny
plays a lot of sports grace grace the
president showed considerable grace
during the crisis instructor instructor
my dancing instructor studied for many
years in France discipline discipline
Tony quit taking guitar lessons because
he didn't have the discipline to stick
with them well same thing happened to me
oh really
what guitar guitar didn't stick with it
really okay but we do know someone who
would stick with it yeah something that
she believes in right yeah well I think
the character of wonder woman and
actress who plays her gal gadot good dud
yes oh she's really pretty she is very
pretty and she's also very fit that's
why she was chosen for the part of
Wonder Woman yeah she actually won Miss
Israel at the age of 18 18 right I think
that's what really launched her career
that's right right it says then she had
a modeling career mm-hmm but before that
she had to join the military service it
was hired I think she wasn't at for
about two years I think she was an
instructor for like fighting her fitness
or something too so she's quite fit and
strong exactly and then she got into
movies and television by being in a TV
show in Israel and then came her big
break 2009 fast and furious right and
then finally of course as we all know
she was cast as Wonder Woman
and she was the perfect person for the
role she really is yeah it's just
beautiful it's just not as fit she has
that you know image yes
yes that's right okay let's learn more
about the beautiful actress gal gadot
gal gadot a wonder of a woman Wonder
Woman is one of the strongest female
characters in the superhero universe to
play that part you need someone who is
courageous beautiful and caring luckily
gal gadot matches that description
perfectly
today's lesson is called gal gadot a
wonder of a woman part 1 hello everyone
my name is Jeff and I'm Mike and yes if
you've ever heard of a wonder of a woman
or a Wonder Woman than you've probably
also heard of gal gadot she is the most
recent Kerrison actor to play the
character of Wonder Woman in a very
popular movie that came out a couple of
years ago and I think I hear a sequel
coming because it was a super super
popular movie critics loved it
audiences loved it it made tons of money
I think it actually was the most popular
of those DC comics I believe right with
Superman Aquaman I think Wonder Woman
was by far their biggest movie and it
was it was a good film anyways it was a
big success one way or another and
because it's a superhero movie you have
to make a sequel more I actually believe
this is going to be the third movie with
gal gadot playing Wonder Woman but yes
this is going to be Wonder Woman too
anyways
Wonder Woman is a wonder of a woman
Wonder Woman is one of the strongest
female characters in the superhero
universe yeah Black Widow is pretty good
but she's not as good as Wonder Woman so
to play the part to play that part of
Wonder Woman you need someone who is one
courageous too beautiful and three
caring yes Wonder Woman is a very caring
person but also courageous who are
courageous by the way you are very brave
you're willing to do risky things for
example the leader is a courageous woman
who isn't afraid to stand up for what
she believes in there you go she might
she might be afraid but she's still
going to do it because she's courageous
or brave there you go courageous
beautiful and care and caring and then
we finished before our break with
luckily gal gadot matches that
description perfectly if you want to
find someone beautiful courageous and
caring look no further than gal gadot
and if you want to know why
look no further than the next part of
our article where we'll explain it all
to you so come back after the break
chamomile concoction a new challenge of
Athena Nestle Jota Jota
kanako-sama can go ahead Oh tink oppa
matsujun hi outro sanguinis idiot in
elementary auntie juju Shenzhen
miniature in the new Georgia gal gadot
Kurchatov how cool entire shop
Geneva Sharon should shouting genre
tournaments witch hunt atoms in Java
three Maori intelligence official
youngin mainly yo eye syndrome her diary
chato at one show for saimyosho Rogers
had Sunday and tuna don't wear no or
teen either torture how Michelle I can't
answer courageous courageous patience
SEO young ganda Wei de
now when John de chillon su caring
caring physician yo I seen depends
empirical engine gal gadot a wonder of a
woman with her long brown hair and
athletic build
she certainly looks the part born in
Israel gadot achieved early success
thanks to her looks winning the Miss
Israel competition when she was 18 this
victory eventually led to a modeling
career but first she would have to
complete her required two-year military
service she took on the challenge with
grace working as an instructor in the
Israeli Defense Force you give two or
three years and it
not about you she said in a 2016
interview you learn discipline and
respect not right to be Wonder Woman you
have to be courageous have to be caring
hmm you have to be awesome you have to
be great you have to be wonderful
luckily gal gadot she's all of these
things and more yes with her long brown
hair and athletic build she certainly
looks the part a Wonder Woman yeah if
you look at the old comic books of
Wonder Woman she had long black or brown
hair and she was very fit she was very
athletic as gal gadot is as many other
actors are these days too athletic this
adjective basically means sporty you
look like someone who plays a lot of
sports as good at sports enjoy sports
exercises a lot you keep yourself in
good shape you go to the gym you look
quite athletic for example due to his
athletic build many people think that
Johnny plays a lot of sports
anyways gal gadot okay born in
Israel gadot achieved early success
thanks to her looks yes you have to be
courageous caring and also beautiful
don't forget that yeah
she earned early success or achieved it
thanks to her looks winning the Miss
Israel competition when she was eight
teen now this victory eventually led to
a modeling career but first she would
have to complete her required two-year
military service so here nowadays in
Taiwan I believe you have to go to the
military for a certain period of time
it's not as long of time as it once was
but in Israel they take the defence very
seriously people have to go into the
military boy or girl
for two years that's right and it's a
pretty tough service what the real army
in the in the Israeli Defense Forces so
we read she took on the challenge with
grace working as an instructor in the
Israeli Defence Force the IDF that's
what we call the Israeli army
Air Force Navy all of that stuff yeah
and everyone all young people have to
serve two years in the IDF but she took
on the challenge with grace
oh it says she took on the challenge and
she made it look good
okay when you do something with grace
you do it with style okay let's say you
dance with grace
people might think there that your
movements are beautiful yes basically if
you do something with grace you do that
thing and you look good while you're
doing that thing for example the
president showed considerable grace
during the crisis did he cry that he
loses temper no way and yes gal gadot is
very similar this she took on this
challenge with grace it was tough but
she did it and she did it well okay so
you handle things well with some
sensitivity with some thought with some
wisdom in a stressful situation you do
very very well when many other people
might just really panic or not handle it
so good for her joining the army being
an instructor would be a challenging
stressful job she did it well what is an
instructor basically it's a teacher
it's a coach it's someone who teaches
you how to do things yeah you could call
your math teacher your math instructor
but we often use it for a more
specialized kind of skill something more
like a coach more like learning how to
play a musical instrument a piano
instructor you could have someone
teaching you how to dance or act or sing
or something like that so they're
teaching you a skill but often it's a
more specialized skill than what
teachers in normal schools do for
example my dancing instructor studied
for many years in France calling it your
dance teacher your dance coach yeah
instructors probably just as good a word
anyways more on service they're in the
IDF let's hear from gal gadot right now
you give two or three years and it's not
about you she said in a 2016 interview
yes you give over two or three years of
your life to a cause it's not about you
at all and she also says you learn this
Appling and respect by the way here we
have the word discipline it's a noun
okay if you have discipline you have
self-control okay you've practice a lot
and now you have control over yourself
your movements your schedule and stuff
like that when I was growing up I got
very lucky as far as discipline was
concerned my parents always made me get
up and do my make my bed every single
day I woke up early and I made my bed
every day and to this day I still do
that I have carried that discipline with
me all the way to where I am now
anyways our example sentence for the
noun discipline is Toni quit taking
guitar lessons because he didn't have
the discipline to stick with them he
wouldn't practice every day he wouldn't
do the exercises he just didn't have
that self-control yeah that's true when
you're teaching yourself to do something
you need a lot more discipline than if
you have someone telling you to do it or
if you're doing it with others self
discipline is important well alright
we'll take a quick break and then we'll
be back with more from gal gadot Carey
Thiago sugar young khomeini your icing
Darrell I tell you it holds some sample
to me that he can tie a few Joseph a
song sugary insanity torrential Java
Hanauma when John yonder build since all
the secrets it has economy certain means
oh my - Oh chica teaching la matanza
athletic athletic secession Ashanti
change on the Indonesian diversion dr.
Hanna controversial Avianca awesome
suggestions and I'm young so today when
reunion awesome subpoena AWS om e Hashim
England sent and ahora hay Banda
calendar T - okay yeah gonna nachos on a
survey ship a sailor soldier in the
isolation session maybe say namaho
lights on Kayla motors Shanghai potent
solution Papa Qi wen Zhang Liang Linda
ping e AE sodapoppin an utopia loop in
it today July shopping precision and
taiyo Aid Society show Jersey is
recovering 20 min tangent joke one tanto
de Jong Sola turnarounds and
- - attention Joe how when John yonder
Israeli Defense Force trabocchi in
silico foundry now Haryana sang thanks
grace grace Jubilee oh yeah phone to
shut down means instructor instructor
Kate Chopin mm oh child in
discipline discipline say come on
diamond diamond statue phone gee what
educated it's really yeah which is
shouldn't you have control gal gadot a
wonder of a woman after beginning her
acting career in an Israeli TV show
gadot made her feature film debut in
2009 s fast and furious she would later
star in several entries of the popular
franchise but it was her performance as
Wonder Woman in Batman V Superman dawn
of Justice and the heroines eponymous
film in 2017 that gadot is best known
for this would turn out to be the role
of a lifetime for the Israeli actress
okay moving on let's learn some more
about gal gadot after beginning her
acting career in an Israeli TV show
gadot made her feature film debut in
2009 fast and furious I'm sure everybody
knows of these movies they've made nine
of them now I think oh my goodness what
a film franchise that is anyways she got
out of the military maybe did some
modeling and then she started her acting
career yeah and she started off strong
first in a TV show there in Israel and
then she made her debut she got her big
start in Fast and Furious there in 2009
Wow two things that was eleven years ago
that movie came out that's amazing and
it's also seems that she was popular in
the films because we read she would
later star in several entries of the
popular franchise so maybe part two
three four a few of the other Fast &
Furious movies if you watch them again
she'll be in there I don't remember her
it might be worth watching one of those
older ones again but anyways it was her
performance as Wonder Woman in Batman vs
Superman dawn of Justice and the
heroines eponymous film in 2017 that
gadot is best known for yes here she
wasn't Batman vs Superman that makes
four films that she has been a part of
as Wonder Woman I believe it's Batman vs
Superman Wonder Woman Justice League and
now Wonder Woman part two how about that
anyways yes she became Wonder Woman and
this would turn out to be the role of a
lifetime for the Israeli actress there
you know the role of a lifetime to land
this role it means that you're pretty
much set for life as an actress
absolutely it's kind of what we would
say the role that turned her into a
household name she was in some other
movies before but this is the one that
made
everyone know her name up there with
some of the big stars in Hollywood all
right yep that's it for today but that's
not it for gal gadot she's got a lot
more going for in the future and we have
a lot more of her at least tomorrow in
the next part of our article we'll see
you then bye bye bye bye que todo de eso
es eso es la fiesta de muchacha de na
hey hey na Mangione no way men cuando
ella me tips again true team champion
mendoza cocina de pista national Hydro
poutine la jolla tangihanga film
franchise latisha movie franchise Joshua
a pietà see dat yo yo yo 10th region
true a decir en la Mancha John de
Franchi so my penita f ra NC h is a
company dr.xu china 13 shout release ha
Naniwa Putrajaya new gravity in the
shootie home on currency codes et seq e
l sickle kappa - ooh attendant of the
shootie Honaker jajaja rio rancho
painful shadow a challenging issue Gwang
Jo Chandni gentleman team challenge her
entire jaw surgery on achievement ah da
zhangwei da Ashanti Johnny other Java
how you John band's eponymous eponymous
take leadership imagine Tom Mendoza
remove our hands open sheet on Yan Ming
Chang de shi shi Yan said Honami transit
agency visit I'm Michelle
[Music]
doctor how is your handi why you shall
come the one fat diet see now just how
one Valjean bien
yo suka Peter should fund Socotra
Perrigo should achieve success this
angle thanks to this leadership
funding through the young back home
until - to the culture eternal minutes
the end the in jail they are the truth
the shanked on the suggestion
oh my Christian without end session
which she joined real truths
now how about now enjoy the don't sit -
see no don't say you don't
jongshin's Evans V ing paid on John
coach - CPP had really shot he walked
into his study sitting down at the desk
that's all James oval toe - erosion
nationalism in a sitting position and he
said Jaguar Lida Tasha Berlin gets an
end
hiya Shangdong chiusa he now hi but you
don't own the set catch on shame defense
is sitting ja ja ja I thought our
offense is sitting title defence
Gogi sitting down at the desk how did
Elijah achieve success
don't say achieve tapia should touch
endow a cheap success trip Yehuda jungle
Mirel
you need to work hard if you want to
achieve success you juanita holder
jungle natural beauty koh-sama ikazuchi
by 2001 Sanjaya
as I can thanks to pay digits
thanks to touch to the occasion which is
sure about that both Wailers about Yahoo
shimma shimma
sound thanks to modern technology
communication is easier than ever before
boooo pollution die cozy the father tone
should be you want oh there we go
how not the whole I should familiar the
young fan now chenggao Arizona mobile
French Open champion - me reducing had a
young fighter ship ing to the young God
abhava by say it is hand that to jinho
sure it was hand that reject ho chun-yan
of authentication ventures demeanor
jutsu shows the shooting
oh they found food sitting de la
mattina tepid juices shouldn't shout a
bullfighter at that to hold now I can't
had attrition Joseph it is for sure it
was Jack Chang down the Puffin yeah that
say Jack treats that - MS wrote her
beautiful smile charmed everyone family
- ro dah dah dah dah gamey jula non -
Shalu Ganesha Changa Jang Hana Manila
Shiro dashi agony too much hangout
routes her beautiful smile not to
shoulder kpop I say it was handed to Jen
I hope I shan't anticipate out that hole
found Joe - dear drew it was her
beautiful smile that charmed everyone
how he sounds yeah Johnny Antonio
Machado jello hey everybody I am Shane
hi I'm Holly what's wrong with you I
don't know I just don't feel like this
is an action we need a lot of shirt
alright well what's what's the topic
today can you at least tell me that
so was your mom Howell I wore Josh
Bhushan
[Applause]
[Laughter]
[Music]
why don't you want to go on a date with
me I just don't feel like it
so sad why are you so mean to me
oh yeah just one day to ask all the
girls on base so I don't feel like it
okay whatever just don't feel like it
Johnson Korean don't bail Jess you don't
feel like it so one chance inside me
like a few big I just don't feel like it
yeah I have no motivation
okay so motivations against Joseph only
well it didn't don't leave the mail but
is it to go again lubos you want to go
on a date with me and usual I have no
motivation desert in cheek why so no
motivation desert kinda just y'all gone
for sure what are ya patterns I'm a move
y'all no emails no motivation mm-hmm
what's in the case wha I'm not in the
mood mood okay mood is sinking so I
didn't say one two missing cheese right
I'm in a bad mood in the mood you want
to go on a date with me do you want to
maybe help them with their English
oh yeah I'm in the mood to help you with
your English yeah so if you have
problems Cowell and Tyler I just don't
feel like it I just don't feel like it I
have no motivation I have no motivation
I'm not in the mood I'm not in the mood
[Music]