[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody this is shane
today we're looking at part two of our
story called
the hounds of fate and the vocabulary
words are
content content with a belly full of
food
roy was content to lie on the couch for
a few hours
community community after the recent
robberies
people in the community no longer feel
safe
confess confess randy confessed to
stealing john's eraser
my friend warned me not to go out at
such a late hour
hopeful hopeful the movie contains a
hopeful message
so we're still talking about this
interesting story about this guy named
martin
right so now he's tom so now he's down
right but he's
really martin that's right pretending to
be tom
and i think he's enjoying his life at
the farmhouse yeah
so i think he's going to at least stay
for a while
because he's going to enjoy it while he
can
he doesn't want to go back to his
troubled life before
i guess you're right and then he noticed
something weird though when he's walking
around in the neighborhood or community
he noticed that people are kind of just
staring at him and they
are not very friendly right so i wonder
what this
tom guy did it looks like tom did
something pretty bad or he was just a
bad guy in general we're not really sure
and then one day the old guy george
warned him about something yeah there's
somebody called michael lay
and he wants to kill tom
so he knows that michael's going to be
coming to try to kill him
that's right martin who he thinks is tom
right
and so george gives him some money and
it says okay why don't you go away for a
few days
so he does that's right okay that's you
know
a lot of money i can pretty much have a
fresh start
and see what happens so maybe he doesn't
need to go back maybe he can
start his own farm somewhere or it
sounds like
a really good story for martin yeah but
you never know but you'll have to keep
reading to find out maybe there will be
a twist
in the end enjoy the story enjoy
the hounds of fate as the days went by
martin became more and more content on
the farm
while riding tom's horse into town he
thought it wouldn't be so bad to stay
for a while
but there was a lot about tom that
martin didn't know
today's lesson is called the hounds of
fate
part two hello everyone i am jeff
and i am mike and we are not martin
stoner or
master tom no they are the same
character
we think in our story martin stoner was
this
lost young man who felt that life was
going really badly
until he found a farmhouse where this
family welcomed him in but called him
master tom now martin was so hungry and
tired he didn't care what they called
him
he was happy they were giving him food
and a place to rest but it turns out
the family at least the aunt in the
family
was very angry with him and she said you
can come in my house
but i'm not going to talk to you or even
look at you
for what you did before martin has no
idea what's going on
he's just happy to be somewhere safe now
martin is martin
martin and the hounds of fate are on his
heels he felt they were and he's luck
into the situation you've got
uncle george there he's going to take
him in there
the aunt there she doesn't like master
tom but
george thinks yes that martin stoner is
master tom right but he's not that's
right
martin but martin's happy to pretend to
be tom
because his life is better now he's
happy to
assume the role and as the days went by
martin became more and more content
on the farm he's great this is great
i'll i'll stay here as long as i need to
this is
great sure awesome i'm tom whatever i
can stay here i got food these people
are not
kicking me out the door they're happy to
have me live with them and if you're
content with something
you're pretty happy with it you're
satisfied it might not be the
greatest thing that ever happened to you
and you're overjoyed all the time but
you don't have anything serious to
complain about everything is just
it's okay it's fine it's it's good
enough
for example with a belly full of food
roy was content to lie on the couch
for a few hours it wasn't the best meal
of his life
he wasn't sitting in a luxury spot a
five-star hotel
or anything but he was perfectly happy
he had a good sandwich
there's a baseball game on tv life's not
bad yep while riding tom's horse into
town
it's not his own it's tom's yeah but
he's tom remember
he thinks he is he's assuming he's
pretending to be while
riding tom's horse into town he thought
it wouldn't be so
bad to stay for a while it's pretty good
i'm gonna stay on this farm i'm gonna
i'm content here but there was a lot
about tom that martin
didn't know remember the aunt she
doesn't want to talk to him
or see him so what
did tom do he's pretending to be someone
he doesn't know
and maybe that person he's pretending to
be
has a bad past anyways folks let's go
ahead and
take a break and when we come back we'll
continue
reading from the hounds of faith
ed overjoyed
the hounds of fate in town the locals
scowled and stared at martin
he wondered what tom could have done to
anger the entire community
but he didn't want to confess his true
identity and go back to a life of
rambling around the countryside
one day martin discovered an album with
photos of tom
and saw with his own eyes the uncanny
resemblance between them
later george warned martin that michael
lay was back in the village
and that he had sworn to kill tom he
gave martin some money from tom's aunt
and told him to get away for a few days
so there he was riding a horse
yeah not long ago things were looking
bad for
martin stoner now he's master tom he's
living on the farm he's content and he's
riding a horse into town but
in town the locals scowled
and stared at martin
this tom guy he did something bad
that's right everyone still thinks he's
tom now martin thought i'll just pretend
to be tom who cares well it turns out
people don't like tom so maybe he's
pretending
to be a pretty bad person so martin of
course starts to wonder
why are people scowling at me and giving
me dirty looks
and stuff like that he wondered what tom
could have done to anger the entire
community
but he didn't want to confess his true
identity
and go back to a life of rambling around
the countryside remember
before he found this family that took
him in he was
rambling around the countryside he was
on his own he was poor he had nowhere to
stay
no food life was pretty tough he doesn't
want to go back to that
but he doesn't want to tell the truth of
course then he'll get kicked out and
have to go back to his difficult life
but what did he do or what did this tom
guy do
to make everyone so angry with him and
if they all think he's
tom he can't ask them what did i
do what did i do that's right you know
what you did
tom yeah anyways here we've got the word
community
here we're talking about a community
we're talking about
a group of people who live together
like a small village is a community in
this particular situation a community
is a small group of people who live
together
who share common bonds that's pretty
much
the idea here for example after the
recent
robberies people in the community
no longer feel safe yes
everybody in the community they're all
paying attention they're
all being very very careful at night
because they don't want to be robbed
right in this case the community is this
village and the farms that all are
that are all around it all the people
there and of course
martin doesn't want to tell the truth
and say hey i'm not tom
i don't know why you're angry with me
i'm just pretending to be tom that's of
course a terrible thing to do
so he doesn't want to tell the truth and
say i'm just this other guy and i was
pretending
i'm just taking food from this family
because i'm kind of a not nice person
but i'm not tom
no because that would be to confess to
confess is to tell the truth
especially when you're telling the truth
about something bad about a
crime or some terrible action to come
clean if you're lying about it that's
one thing but then if you say i don't
want to lie anymore i want to tell the
truth
about something bad you are confessing
for example
randy confessed to stealing john's
eraser
anyways go ahead and move on yeah one
day martin discovered
an album with photos a photo album a
photo album okay
with photos of tom and
saw with his own eyes the uncanny
amazing resemblance between them
it's like they're twins like looking in
a mirror
they look exactly alike
that's why everyone's getting him but
everybody
thinks that martin stoner
is master tom amazing
anyways let's go ahead and read on
okay moving on the next sentence says
later
george warned martin that that
michael lay was back in the village
and that he had sworn
to give tom flowers
no no he had sworn to
kill tom wow what the heck
did tom do nobody likes his hum
aunt won't look at him won't talk to him
no one likes him
and this guy michael lay he's back in
town
and he has sworn to kill
tom oh man
anyways here if you warn someone of
something
you tell that person that there is some
danger in the future possibly okay
be careful this bad thing might happen
to you so george went
into town heard about this came back and
said
hey master tom this guy michael lays in
town
and he might have sworn
to kill you so you might want to be
careful
with that whole situation don't go to
town don't go to town ever again
for example my friend warned me not to
go
out at such a late hour yeah you've got
an exam
tomorrow go to bed get get some
sleep okay don't go out anyways he gave
martin some money from tom's
aunt and told him to get away
for a few days escape this guy he's
gonna kill you so george
not only warned him but also gave him
some money from the
ant who's still angry with tom but
doesn't want him to be killed
here's some money take a holiday get out
of town for a few days
let michael lay stay here then hopefully
he'll leave
well hopefully that will keep martin out
of danger we'll find out
after the break
down
come
helen gave up her well-paying job to
pursue a life
of helping others
the hounds of fate martin decided not to
return
he had enough money for a fresh start
and as he left
he felt hopeful almost happy however
as he was riding along the road michael
lay stepped out from behind a tree
and shot him dead in the end the hounds
of fate
had finally caught up with martin
okay so martin decided not to return
he's not going to stay at the farm or
he's not going to come back
the farm i should say getting out of
town he's had his fill yeah
okay plenty of food plenty of sleep got
that horse
probably probably has the horse there
and he's got some money now from
his aunt so he's not coming back and he
probably won't be killed by that guy
michael lay that's right he decides he's
stayed here
long enough things are getting a little
scary he's got this money
it's time to go he had enough money for
a fresh start to start a new life
away from this place and as he left he
felt hopeful
almost happy so he'd come to town with
nothing
as you say he got some rest he got some
food probably a horse a bit of money
so things aren't terrible he's got to go
but
it could be worse so he feels hopeful
almost
happy all right if you're hopeful this
adjective means you're positive you
feel good about the future you are full
of hope
you think things are okay now and
they're probably going to be better
tomorrow
and into the future for example the
movie
contains a hopeful message things might
be
tough now you might be going through
troubles but all things pass all things
change bad times will turn into good
times eventually
have hope be hopeful so he's feeling
things are good
things are hey he's feeling things are
good
things are good yep actually they're not
however you see as he was writing along
the road thinking those hopeful thoughts
michael lay stepped out from behind a
tree
master tom yeah
michael a stepped out from behind a tree
said that menacingly
brandished a firearm and shot him dead
whoa just like that he will he was
warned that michael lay was out for
blood and sure enough michael lay
ambushed him
surprised him from behind a tree with a
weapon and
killed him it's just too bad that this
villain here michael lay
didn't like tell him why he was killing
him it's true
sir i'm killing you because of so-and-so
although michael a here i guess he's not
really the villain
anyways in the end the hounds of fate
had finally caught up with martin
anyways what do you
think mike what no what do you think tom
did
that made the people in the community
hate him so much
i'm not sure but tom probably did
something especially bad to michael lay
or his
family he probably stole their horses
stole their horses i'm thinking maybe he
like promised to marry michael
a's sister and then ran away with her
money leaving her heart broken or
something like that i don't know
but nothing good nothing good he wasn't
everyone's favorite person
that's for sure anyways folks with that
it's time for us to say
bye bye see you next time
because
[Music]
elvis presley was known as the king of
rock and roll
young people today might not understand
why he was so
famous in the 1950s the term rock and
roll
didn't exist yet back then the only
forms of popular music
were country music and the blues elvis
presley did something new
by combining those two styles of music
the new style he played was called rock
and roll
although he didn't invent rock and roll
he did make it popular
elvis presley also had a strong
influence on
youth culture largely because of him
teenagers began to develop their own
fashion
they also acted differently from people
of their parents
age as he became older his music
and fashion styles changed too but
that's okay
rock and roll is for young people it was
time for him to step down
and make room for the next generation
here is more information
calorie there are 400 calories
in this sandwich
chart this popular new song is
at the top of the music charts
gospel angel loves to listen
to gospel music
hit this song is the number one hit
in the country right now
impersonator you can see many elvis
impersonators
in las vegas
twin jesse and karen are twins
they are eight years old
perform our band performed well
in the concert yesterday
blonde that blonde man is our new
neighbor
stillborn anna's first baby was
stillborn
but her second baby was very healthy
unfortunately i want to go to the beach
unfortunately it is raining
today's lesson was quite fascinating
right
i know i thought so well we hope to see
you here again
next time
see you next time