[Music]
hello everyone this is Karen welcome
back everybody
I am Shane today we're looking at part
two of our story called the man who
would be king and the vocabulary words
are idol idol the treasure hunter gently
lifted the golden idol from its stand
conquer conquer the King conquered a
large amount of territory during his
rule Empire Empire even the mightiest of
empires has to come to an end sooner or
later establish establish the government
established a national health care
system in 1911 bleed bleed the wounded
soldier was bleeding from his stomach
oh that sounds painful
mmm so we found out last time these two
guys want to become kings xi and dravot
they want to become kings and they're
going on this journey but on the way to
to Afghanistan what's the place called
cuff Faris first them yeah they had a
lot of trouble but finally they get bare
mm-hmm and they convince the natives
that they're like an idol they know
Umbra Umbro yeah that's right so it's
like one of the idols so they convinced
that they know an idol God that they
worship right so everyone's looking up
to them said oh oh my god I can't
believe it Thanks the third gods that's
right basically right so they they
started telling people what to do giving
orders they're like an army they're
conquering other villages things are
going pretty awesome that's right so
until until until I remember one of the
guy wanted a wife yeah he got greedy
right I want a wife and then I remember
the girl didn't really want to be his
wife
so she bit him she bit was like that
that's right look and then he started
bleeding but wait gods don't bleed
that's right right so they realize they
just realized that hey they're not God
so they killed him right Daniel Dravot
that's right peachy they crucified him
put him on a cross like this and he
actually survived throughout the night
so they just let him go so he went back
to India to find the newspaper reporter
right so what's gonna hearing that bad
right so there's a bag so we're gonna
wondering what's in that bag maybe
that's important I really don't know all
right let's find out what happens all
right enjoy the man who would be king
soon after Dravo claimed to know Umbra
the idol God the locals worshiped at
this discovery the people began to
worship peachy and Dravo as gods the two
men began wearing crowns of gold upon
their heads they ordered the natives
around train them to use guns and
conquered village after village for
their new empire they established new
farming practices and even a legal
system
today's lesson is called the man who
would be king Park - hello everyone my
name is Jeff and I'm Mike and yes it's
part two of our very exciting and
slightly crazy story about peachy
carnahan and Danielle Dravo two
adventurers from about a hundred hundred
and fifty years ago went off to
Afghanistan to become kings of a local
tribe in a foreign country but the plan
that they have these two guys it didn't
go very well
did it no I believe they suffered
through a bunch of really bad stuff they
had to eat camels and mules and when
they finally arrived where they were
going they had to participate in a civil
war to fight a war so it yeah I don't
think their plan really worked out also
never peachy carnahan he's gone nuts
that's what that's what people think of
him right now he's also been crippled so
yeah things didn't really turn out well
for anyone but he does have that bag
what's in the bag yes that's true he did
show up back in town with a bag that he
brought back from his great adventure so
let's find out about the bag well the
article for today at least begins soon
after soon after telling his story to
the reporter that he met a few years ago
soon after Dravo claimed to know Umbra
the idol god the locals worshipped oh so
this would be soon after the civil war
that we just left off with at the end of
yesterday so they got to the village
where they wanted to become kings they
had this war and then soon after Dravo
the other partner in this plan claimed
to know in bruh the idol god the locals
worshipped so these would be the local
Afghan people Afghani people they
worship this God but the God was in the
form of an idol there you go an idol and
here by the way an idol is something
that you worship it's like a god-like
entity maybe a statue or something like
that that people think is holy that they
worship you're not talking about a teen
idol here someone who's popular and
famous and that
other people want to be like here no
we're talking about something that is
worshiped an idol for example the
treasure hunter gently lifted the golden
idol from its stand when they when he
said that he had the idol at this
discovery the people began to worship
Peachy and drove Oh as gods the sky
drove Oh shows up he's from a foreign
country he looks very different he's got
an idol in his bag he must be one of
these odds that's what the local people
were thinking so the plan might just
work these people here think that peachy
and drove over gods and yes the two men
began wearing crowns of gold upon their
heads it sounds like they have become
kings that's absolutely right and then
they began to behave like kings even
though of course they had no right to be
the kings of these people or this land
but they acted like they were and what
did they do next they ordered the
natives around told the native the local
people do this get me food build me a
house or whatever train them to use guns
and conquered village after village so
these guys are just warlords basically
go out to a country give guns to a bunch
of poor people and then use them as
their own personal army yeah I'm not
sure this is the right thing to do but
again this story is from a long time ago
so they ordered people around like they
were kings they trained the locals to a
to become an army and then they used
that army to conquer the villages in the
nearby area what is it to conquer to
conquer is to beat but in a warlike or
military kind of way you won't conquer
the other team in a baseball game you
conquer another country or another
Kingdom if you're playing a video game
or in a history book you know one
country will start a war and if they
invade another country and win that war
then they will conquer that country they
come in attack invade and then take over
when the fighting is done for example
the king conquered a large amount of
territory during his rule he made his
kingdom much
bigger he took that territory by force
maybe with his army or something like
that anyways back to our two kings
peachie karna Hannon one mr. Bravo for
their new empire they established new
farming practices and even a legal
system before we move on we do have to
talk about the noun empire an empire is
kind of like a really really big country
but it's slightly different from a from
a country an empire is usually a
collection of countries that are all
ruled by another country that would be
the Emperor by the way the person who
ran who runs that country and also the
Empire's countries or territories that
would be the Emperor but yes here an
empire is a very large country or a very
large collection of companies come
countries I should say under the control
of a single person for example even the
mightiest of empires has to come to an
end sooner or later ancient Rome Roman
Empire the British Empire they've all
come and gone all right anyways so
they're trying to set up their own
little Empire and to do that they
established laws and some other things
as well what is it to establish this
verb basically means to set something up
it's kind of like to create something we
might also use that word to found
something right you establish something
probably big maybe an institution like a
hospital or a university businesses can
be established it's when it starts it's
when the first large buildings maybe are
put up when the company sort of goes
public with its name and starts hiring
workers you know it's the beginning of
some kind of organization like that for
example we could also say the government
established a national healthcare system
in 1911 all right yeah so the government
set up or established this program to
give health care to all the people it's
a big thing but it has to begin
somewhere there you go all right folks
with that it's time for us to take a
break but don't go away
we'll be back after this hello how is a
handy for sitting in the peachy corn
hands hand Daniel Dravot Challenger
483 Chong Guang Shan Shan one dilution
quinine Chong Chong boomerang command P
aah - OH - um Chang Chu Lai poncho issue
in Hungarian in Berlin agent Michael
situation and rental magician stream
Pharma how la Shanda warlord w AR l rd
warlord trebuchet rympha hello sir how
young Afghan washer Afghani tokei wa
gyaku Honda Naaman ship into a FG h KN
home in Ketchikan I pension Afghani how
conceited hadashah put Johanna travelin
County in shinchon tyrant Umbra Impala
say Impala in battalion Chong by the
junction near certainty NGO capital
angle while a motion Transocean mo pay
Hanuman worship reggaeton CJ pursuit
song by Jin Young Jeezy's a language ok
Jetta Santa Shangguan Jin Hwan Kwon
Hoshi want and era national harmony on
Chang concha y yo y su mo
nation's highway they rescinded ego
Jenna - in a non conforto for duty
during an Occidental idol Idol Tapia
home by tuition conscience out how Shan
Shan just changshan youngest edema now
modulus Redondo God like God like
Jerusalem sanction a find the position
gender how younger entertains against
the ENT ity entity deputy Washington's a
segment
conquer conquer Asia Tanisha - Chun soo
conquer hostage and a nylon shortie
daddy send in Swedish answer yo D triple
shooting to reduce emissions and into
the English territory te RR itor why
take acetylene to pan - horrible
memories
omens are like Hank an empire empire
capacity equal mahadesh and wanton
co-emperor
EMP er o our emperor gaozong be Jinju
hi o Empress Empress EMP ress the supe
one who on hope was a new one how's Ella
can abandon established established
gently Chumlee see Jaco and Joel the man
who would be king it was all going so
well until drove Oh mad with power
asked for a wife the bride to be
frightened for her life bit his neck he
bled and the locals knowing that gods
don't bleed realized that he was an
impostor they killed him by forcing him
onto a bridge before cutting the ropes
for his part peachy was crucified but
when he survived the night they let him
go and he returned to India okay so
things started off a little bit violent
okay
Bravo and Carnahan were training the
locals there in Afghanistan to fight and
use guns and stuff like that but later
on they did some good stuff they
established a legal system and ways of
farming and stuff like that so it was
all going so well until travaux mad with
power
asked for a wife one of the kings once a
queen I suppose but he probably didn't
ask nicely he probably maybe was mad
with power
yeah he probably stole the prettiest
girl from her family or something like
that because it seems that this woman
who was to marry him didn't really like
the idea of marrying him the bride-to-be
the woman who would be his bride the
bride to be frightened for her life bit
his neck I guess he went in for a kiss
and she didn't want to be kissed so she
bit his neck which of course is a
natural thing to do but that caused a
strange reaction from all the other
local people once they see that this man
had been bitten
well what happened they saw blood he
bled that's the problem or okay she bit
him that's not a problem no then he bled
yeah he bled that's okay too and the
locals knowing that gods don't bleed not
for a God realized that he was an
impostor stars don't bleed you can bite
a God but that God will never
bleed here we've got a bleeding God it
can't be a gun because well gods don't
believe this guy is a fake he's an
imposter the locals know this now
anyways here you've got the verb bleed
to talk about the past tense form is
bled bleed bled bled anyways here this
word bleed it's a verb okay let's say
you've been cut and blood is coming out
of the cut or the wound you are bleeding
there you go yes I've been cut then the
blood is coming out of the wound oh gosh
I'm bleeding yikes
that's what's going on here for example
the wounded soldier was bleeding from
his stomach
that's not good and it's not good blood
coming out of your body is generally not
a good thing so if you're bleeding make
sure to take care of that all right so
then what happens so the locals find out
that this this guy isn't a god and then
they probably quickly figure out that
both of them are not gods and it's all
been a big trick a big lie these two
foreigners have come in and done a lot
of really bad stuff so what did the
villagers do they killed him they killed
Dravo by forcing him onto a bridge
before cutting the ropes so they forced
him onto one of those rope bridges and
then when he's in the middle they cut
the ropes from both ends and well he's
science again it sounds like an Indiana
Jones movie and so that happened to dr.
Vose gone he was killed so what about
peepee Carnahan peachy well he's gonna
get punished too for his part for his
part in this charade for his part
peachie was crucified put on a cross but
when he survived the night they let him
go and he returned to India so he got
away but what's in the bag truly in the
bag there's a bag
anyways folks with that it's time for us
to take a break but don't go away we'll
be right back after this surrender and
shanira Chang Wanquan shebang period Oh
Tina Shandy do down Travolta patronage
genre at Hotel Julia Tootsie
her name entrancing young you hardly see
me in Papa really Travolta ports today
isn't in sahaja means Amitabh Bachchan's
Travolta Coppa Italia Conti
reintroduction supported mr. Jordan
without sayin super multi ho-hum Jupiter
votes although charge and her passions
she passes beyond naturally P traitors
should pay ping Chang shoots a not
that her up when I went to the whole
town danger Baha found Zola the Maha YPG
joke without endo harsh and I can't
dance it bleed bleed ticket insertion
Belushi and the don'ts ascent I should
bleed bled let her know more when Jang
Hong dal bride-to-be Saiga is inertia
trench in yuen-han America follow me
Natasha bride Shin Jung ji Chang to be
jung geun's holy sh t
not too busy to shorty Johnson Yun
byung-se hotel just G Jung Chang wishing
and urgent is retention and low heart
rate for young man's an imposter
imposter has Jamal PAHO mom in pink
either n Chavez Ocala how young does
charades gets CH a ra te
charade - you're wrong mode so young so
geodesy Oaxaca Winchell the man who
would be king after finishing his story
peachy reveals the contents of his bag
the crowned head of drove oh and leaves
the reporters office the next day the
reporter comes across peachy lying in
the hot Sun and sends him to a mental
hospital that is the last he ever sees
of him a couple of days later peachy
dies of heatstroke leaving no trace of
the bag with dravot's head inside
what's in the bag peachie carnahan what
is in your bag I want to know and get
this next we're going to learn what is
in the bag after finishing his story
peachie reveals the contents of his bag
the crowned head of Dhruv oh and leaves
the reporter's office so he just dumps
dravot's head in the office there and
leaves a dead smelly head
that's gross in a bag that's disgusting
that is that is pretty gross but when
you think about a what else was gonna be
in the bag he was sent away from the
village in disgrace it's not like he was
bringing gold back with him but still
that is horrible so there's this
reporter he's got this head in the bag
this man just told him the craziest
story he's ever heard what does the
reporter do well we read the next day
the reporter comes across peachy lying
in the hot Sun and sends him to a mental
hospital okay obviously peachy has had
some mental illness maybe the the the
experience that he had has made him go
slightly crazy and so the reporter does
the right thing sends him off to a
hospital and that is the last he ever
sees of him he never sees peachy ever
again and a couple of days later peachy
dies of heatstroke leaving no trace of
the bag with dravot's head inside so
apparently he keeps the head because
he's crazy I don't know why but when he
disappears when he dies the bag and the
head they disappear too that is very
mysterious but a very strange end to a
very strange strange story what do you
think everyone do you think that peachy
and drove oz punishment fit their crimes
why or why not Mike what do you think
this is a hard question to answer but
I'd say I think the punishment was fair
because it's not right to trick local
people into thinking you're a god
but then again
know what the punishment should be for
that so you know I just don't don't
pretend to be a god I think that's
probably the best advice we can give you
yeah also if you fall down into a ravine
or off a rope bridge how does someone
retrieve your head good question
that's weird yeah anyways maybe when he
hit the ground it popped off okay
sounds plausible to me all right all
right everyone with that it's time for
us to say bye bye
we'll see you next time take care well
minion bouzouki doc a treat nausea pain
Zima happy trip it is a challenger hona
hydro natural pet easy don't Sheila ha
Jodi hatches a penguin coach at an
event all the trauma sees the
dimensional should travel the Tolu
torsion Hypatia franconi Tina Harmons
whole cube had a because it was aware
fasten your pecans head is sitting
whether that's on Buchan cities in their
homes in wherever my closet come about
disgrace to gets it home LLL shoot out
Chris CEO Yama Yama Ted Simmons around T
is disgraced happier should shrew
building koushaku kwang-soo demean CEO
how cautious a hottie - or Korean
teacher / and fashion peachy pounds at
that high and Isha Naja bajas century
judging champ Ingrid nashit odd see how
its agenda peachy
jeetendra Hopi treated song so Stella
meld oceanic transit revolt all the path
the river how the man went on
yonder heat stroke such a juncture is a
trilogy ginger how a meal punishment
Kate's headache antibody fashion show an
Oregon ciaochao ciaochao ciaochao
ciaochao ciaochao dara shikoh the
Patriots amateur treated at all WA how
communication zhang chao nan og young
bow ravines it gets it RAV i and ii
ravines agra means in happier Shashank
Uchiko Shashank oh how young now
retrieve our EGR ieve retr iëve
retrieved repair should jog wait wait
how the mean sounds did Jonesy Toshiba's
okay Michelle
[Music]
Takahashi handy when show come to one
fat Damian see now a shallow one pouch
on get your lilka biggest none
other
dan dare go show whom in doubt questions
through the face and in young fat this
angle should in a pusher and Josh
Johnson Jack State this cigar should a
couple of the older should die of
something the logo should leave no trace
of John means how much Elijah none other
than none other than home in cage area
whose shoe diode shinya-san tango -
infinitely Chi Yong Hwa Chong Bell
pusher Peter Chung mr. Mishima seeing
ranchers shimma shimma how should one of
the men sitting at the next table was
none other than her ex-boyfriend Jose
Escobedo an answer novel she's doing a
thing I said that she and Daniel Jensen
Joseph Simmons house no it's a domain
zone cuz a Chennai or ecological parts
it tastes like
whom endow concedes to the face and in
your back whom should show coke
Wednesday that means it man Tommy on
when she time in select she meant he
doubted run it just has changed since
then I can rent a quench its ingenious
opinion shows the ja ja ja ja whom night
on Quincy time until all ha - 18 2013 2
attention on Brianna sending fun way to
show whom the Chairman Ianto how her
consensus to the calmness you might
change in social me real I show my
friend Amanda whom I have known for many
years moved to New York last month with
Apollo Aman - angry Pannonia way
generational Antonia how Jason is
changing my friend Amanda Tasha told
intuition OMB on Trish ending - anyway
non Shoshanna Ianto ha ba whom
intervening question citric I light whom
I have known for many years so she only
pay with a poem a man Tarte au pomme
show me so way Jenna's dad owned a
mansion down Giotto how a potential
mentor stationed in Nova
how did Elijah in Russia in joshan's
Josh on state
State down means said hired ronk ronk
ronk IDs nama in a bush in Sharon's
estate repair should chew a chamois
ladronka truly chamois on the drunk hua
Chaun when they bought the house it
was in a terrible state
Don Harmon did my channel Jane found to
the Shona Huang fei-hung so how did
eyelashes she a couple of period a
couple of Sangha how chica now homie
idea for show kosher means mineral we
bumped into each other a couple of days
ago on Monday attention transaction was
a bump into each other states rehearsal
home detention show you how did Elijah
die of something rapacious immersion
suits cheap enchilada
Mira his father died of cancer three
years ago pathogens as an agency I joke
how to Elisha she leave no trace of
jamuns traced I owed some jihun CDs
leave no trace of jam in Zootopia
yoshiyama that song G the mail -
am the Shin Dong Hyun Jae dong dong Chan
sure the murder left no trace of
evidence at the crime scene show show
the fans and mildew shall relish in
solution Joo Han emissions engine
Antonio Machado jello
[Music]
hi everybody
alright my name is holly yeah can I show
that every day can you help me with this
sure this is right up my alley
your mojo went for me hahaha up your
alley
listen to have a very big alley and
you're very familiar with your alley
alley chooses a shouting through the
east not right up my alley to just you
didn't answer door sounds the worthy
that's what people don't show they don't
gantry this is like specialty specialty
doesn't need judging this itching yeah
so did I my duty at that mmm or you
could say this is my thing I'll call you
that my thing to the country you didn't
sitting hen sit down what's a
heavyweight or does it takes this cerini
you're Yoda eating named Harley don't
stop to him it's my thing it's nothing
yeah yeah so you know what else is my
thing
yeah what what oh to make them
understand exactly you don't understand
how to say something in English don't
worry that's our thing that's her thing
okay Oh
hmm
this is right up my alley this is right
up my alley this is my specialty this is
my specialty this is my thing this is my
thing
[Music]