[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hey everybody
i am shane today we're looking at part
one of our story and it's called the
hounds of fate
that's right and the vocabulary words
are
exhausted exhausted the farmer is
exhausted from working in the fields all
day
approach approach pam raised the slipper
and slowly approached the cockroach on
her coffee table
assume assume the mob was after john
so he moved to a small town and assumed
a false name remark remark
dave remarked that he only slept for
four hours last night
in form inform inform jane informed her
boss
of her decision to quit so we're looking
at the story called the hounds of fate
right that's correct so we have this guy
named martin martin so martin
seems like he's homeless and he's just
poor and he's wandering around in the
country
and he doesn't know if he's going to
make it through the night
he's exhausted he's super excited
starving but then he sees something
a farmhouse yes but he gets there and he
doesn't even have enough energy to knock
on the door
but somebody comes out and sees him and
this
old man is named george right
and then what does george say he said oh
master tom that's right you're back
i knew you would be back wait a minute
his name is martin not my mom
so they think he's somebody named tom
but does martin correct him he doesn't
correct him because
there's a warm house there there's food
and they called him master so that must
mean that he was pretty important there
so they'll take good care of him
so he keeps his mouth shut
so she decided to stay for a little
while
i guess i would too yeah if i were
hungry and i were cold i
really were desperate at least get some
food
first and get warm and then maybe
explain later
that's right all right let's see what
happens on day two
enjoy the story
the hounds of fate it was a rainy autumn
afternoon when martin stoner found
himself wandering aimlessly in the
country
he was exhausted starving and had no
idea whether he would even make it
through the night
he could feel the hounds of fate
catching up with him
[Music]
today's lesson is called the hounds
of fate part one
hello everyone my name is jeff
my name is mike so this is our story and
what a
title our story has the hounds
of fate well fate is basically your
fortune your future
what will happen to you and you can't
escape
you can't escape it that's right if you
go to a fortune teller and they say
you will die in five years and you say
what can i do to change that i don't
want to die
they'll say you can't change it it is
your fate
it only happens in stories don't worry
but that's basically a future that's
like
written in stone it's been decided by
the gods or whatever
and of course in stories it will mean
that the hero
or the bad guy something was going to
happen to them and it probably won't be
good what does this have to do with
hounds
towns are big hunting dogs
right what the hounds of faith what what
it probably means that something is
going to chase you to your
death nothing you can do about it kind
of
it's not good if the fortune teller says
you will be chased by the hounds of
fate until you die in five years
you should probably buy life insurance
your fate
follows you and there's nothing you can
do about it yeah that's right don't make
any blood it follows you like a hound
that's right
yeah anyways it was a rainy autumn
afternoon
when martin stoner found himself
wandering aimlessly in the country
well where am i okay so
he was exhausted he was very very tired
he was
exhausted he was very very tired and
very very
hungry absolutely he was exhausted tired
starving hungry and had no idea whether
he would even
make it through the night wow it sounds
like the hounds of
fate are already chasing this guy down
nothing is going well
he doesn't know if he will make it
through the night or survive
he's afraid he might die before the sun
comes up
he's starving very hungry and really
tired he needs a nap
he needs a smack he is exhausted
by the way you wouldn't use this day you
wouldn't use this word i should say
if it was early in the day and you were
just
tired from waking up you wouldn't say oh
i'm so exhausted
you'd say you were sleepy you'd use this
to
you'd use this word if you had been
working all day long and you had no
energy left you'd say
oh my goodness i'm exhausted i have no
energy left
i need to go to bed and go to sleep i'm
extremely tired i'm exhausted for
example
the farmer is exhausted from working in
the fields
all day if you're if you're if you're a
cell phone your battery is below
five percent you're basically going to
shut down all right as you
think about that we get back to martin
stoner yes he could feel the hounds of
fate
catching up with him he could feel you
know terrible things are about to happen
to him the hounds of fate are about to
bite him in the bum he's really in bad
shape
things are not going well for mr stoner
we'll be back after this break hello
catch up
zach ran so fast that nobody could catch
up with him
the little girl found her grandma asleep
on the couch
asleep
on
the hounds of fate just when it seemed
he couldn't go any further
he came upon a farmhouse he approached
the door which opened before he could
even knock
an old man named george welcomed the
weary martin come in master tom
i knew you would come back one of these
days
martin entered the house happy to assume
the role of tom if it meant a meal to
eat and a bed to sleep in
he was promptly served a supper of cold
meat cheese and bread
[Music]
all right so the hounds of fate
are on this stoner fella and
just just when it seemed he couldn't go
any further
he came upon a farmhouse now
remember he's exhausted and hungry so
he's thinking
maybe i can sleep here maybe i can get a
bite to eat
absolutely he definitely needs a place
to rest
and a farmhouse is as good as any place
so he approached the door
of the farmhouse which opened before he
could even
knock ooh creepy so he walks up to this
farmhouse or he approaches
the door of it and before he can knock
the door
opens slowly that's very mysterious and
strange
because of course you would expect to
approach a door and
knock on it or ring the bell before the
door
opens right to approach is just to go
near to something to
and to go closer to it to go towards it
if you're walking towards your house and
you're getting
nearer and nearer especially in the the
last few steps before you reach your
front door
you are approaching something if someone
approaches you
they are walking towards you not away
from you towards you for example pam
raised the slipper and slowly approached
the cockroach
on her coffee table she picked up a
slipper or a shoe
and she has to walk towards the
cockroach to smash it
with her shoe she can't reach it from
the other side of the room so there he
is he's approaching the door
he's about to knock and suddenly the
door starts to open
before he knocks on it who's there
what's going on
an old man named george
welcomed the weary martin martin stoner
and says come
in master tom tom
i knew you would come back
one of these days tom he called him
tom he called him master master tom
okay well master something he used to
call like
younger men right instead of calling him
mister they would call a master
but his name's martin it's not tom so
this is very confusing but remember
martin is exhausted he's hungry he just
needs a place to rest so he doesn't care
if they call him jane as long as he can
sit down martin entered that column any
name he just wants to sit down
martin entered the house happy to assume
the role of tom if it meant a meal to
eat and a bed to sleep
in call me susan call me mary yeah call
me barnaby
i don't care i want food and i want to
sit down
i'm exhausted and starving i've
i'll be whoever you want yes i'll be
i'll be whoever you want me to be
whatever just get me something to eat
and a place to sleep
anyways let's talk about the verb assume
if you assume
something is true okay
usually you decide something is
the case or is true before
you have all the facts okay you assume
something is true even though it might
not be true
here though he says that he's happy to
assume
the role of tom that means he's happy to
play this role
to take this role that's the idea here
for example the mob was after john
so he moved to a small town
and assumed a false name
he took a false name he started going by
a different name anyways
he got that meal he did yeah call him
tom call him whatever but just
give me some food and a place to rest so
that's what happened he was promptly
served a supper
of cold meat cheese and bread
just what a starving person would want
to eat
and this happened quickly or promptly so
not a lot of questions not a lot of tom
where have you been
uh he didn't have to make up a big lie
he just said yeah i'm tom okay sure
whatever and they gave him food and
that's what happened so
confusing but at this point martin's not
worried
he's just happy to be eating his food
now we'll take a break and then we'll be
back and find out
what happens with martin tom and all
this
strange stuff
[Music]
they came upon a bear during their hike
these four years the old man remarked
he left to inform tom's aunt that they
had a guest
she'd always said they'd take tom in if
he ever returned
however she refused to speak to or look
at him again
after supper martin was led to tom's
room and he had a good night's sleep
the first in a very long time
okay so master tom
i thought we were dealing with a
character named
martin stoner who is being
hounded by the hounded by fate or the
the hounds of faith well that's they
were after him that's what was happening
but luckily he found this farmhouse they
welcomed him in like he was some
long-lost person named tom but he didn't
care he was tired and hungry so
he's eating his meat and cheese and
bread he's finally getting some food
and as he's eating the old man who lives
in the farmhouse who welcomed him in who
called him tom
starts to talk to him and this old man
says you
little change these four years the old
man remarked in this kind of
old timey english hume little change
these four years master
tom says this old man or he remarks when
you remark this verb
basically means you you say something
you comment
on something probably something you're
seeing or a
pin an opinion you have what you think
about what's going on you might remark
about the beautiful weather we're having
today or
remark about what a lovely song they're
playing over there
so it's basically just your opinion or
your comment
on something that's going on or
happening around you for example dave
remarked
that he only slept for four hours last
night it's
interesting it might relate to what's
going on
why dave's yawning all the time and
seems a little
slow today but it's not the most
important thing in the world
it's just a little comment though so
there's this man he's
looking at this young martin or tom
eating and says oh
you know you you you kind of look pretty
good
he said something he remarked something
and then he left
he left to inform tom's
aunt or aunt that they
had a guest this is family there you go
by the way he left to inform
toms on if you inform
someone of something you're
giving them information okay i've got
this news for you
and i'm going to give it to you i'm
going to
inform you of what i know for example
jane informed her boss of her decision
to quit i've decided that this is what i
want to do
and i'm telling you about it now i'm
informing you of it
right now anyways
while tom or martin while they're alone
what happens next i don't know so let's
go ahead
and read on all right so the and we're
now with the aunt of
tom or who they they think is martin
she'd always said they'd take tom in
if he ever returned however
she refused to speak to or look at him
again very very interesting so this is
obviously a
family that's had some kind of trouble
in the past
right so they're happy to welcome tom
back whoever this tom guy is
but the aunt it says she refused to
speak
or to speak to or look at him again she
she was upset with him from the past you
can come into my house but i'm not going
to talk to you
i'm not even gonna look at you i'm still
angry with you
i guess for something that tom did she
won't speak
or look at him that's right something
that tom did in the past was so
terrible that the ant won't speak to him
or look at him
again but of course martin this real
young man who's there is kind of like
okay i'm just happy you gave me food
it's actually this actually makes things
easier for martin you can kind of pull
this thing this thing
off he doesn't have to be seen by the
second person
anyways after his supper martin was led
to tom's room
and he had a good night's sleep the
first
in a very long time so he got his food
he got his rest and he's with this weird
family
maybe this is his fate this is where
he's going to end up
anyways folks that's it for today and
we'll
[Music]
you may often see cowboys as characters
in old western movies
the exciting fighting and shooting
scenes are regarded as an
essential part of american culture
besides
do you know that cowboys are important
to american agriculture
over a million beef producers in america
are responsible
for more than 94 million heads of cattle
also let's not forget the sheep goats
and horses that must be taken care of
with all of these animals to look after
the life of a cowboy
isn't easy that's why many children
begin to learn about being a cowboy
at an early age they wake up early in
the morning to work
with animals by doing so they begin to
understand the importance
of responsibility and hard work
so the next time you see a cowboy movie
remember what cowboys really do
here is more information
cowboy you can see real cowboys
when you travel to southwestern america
ride emma likes to ride horses
in her free time cattle
lenny's father has 50 cattle on his farm
ranch the brown family has been running
a ranch
for 30 years
boot michael is wearing a
new pair of boots
hat look that
cowboy's hat is very handsome
saddle amy saddled her horse
and then rode away
bridal nick is bridling his horse
rope please tie the rope
to the back of the car
rodeo rodeo is an exciting activity
but it can be dangerous
thanks for joining us today i hope you
learned a lot
we'll catch you later