[Music]
hi everyone this is Karen welcome back
everybody
this is Shannon today we're looking at
part two of Miguel good for the body
good for the earth and the vocabulary
words are popularity popularity because
of the restaurants popularity
you should call ahead to book a table
weekend weekend the floods weakened the
structure of the building hmm retain
retained this pan retains heat very well
sensitive sensitive I have sensitive
teeth so I try not to eat cold food oh
no ice cream for me for you pollution
pollution big cities often have high
levels of air pollution hmm so we're
still talking about this yummy yummy
Miguel right yes so I don't really know
much about it because I've never tried
it but so far I've heard that it's tasty
that's right me according to your oh
that's right it's good for the body
mm-hmm so today we'll talk about how
it's good for the earth for the earth
that's right okay because in will lie I
think a lot of farmers they try to grow
different kind of crops and growing the
other kind of crops like rise vegetable
these kind of crops was weaken the soil
and you would have to use some
fertilizer which is not really good for
the environment it requires a lot of
water that's that kind of resource but
Miguel the way that the plant grows the
roots are quite deep that's right so
it's quite stable for the soil and when
they pick the macaw
it doesn't really they're not to pull
out the roots the roots stay in there so
it's very easy to maintain
exactly and you don't have to you don't
need a lot of water yeah and you don't
need a fertilizer so no chemical is
needed which is really good for our
environment yeah because there's a lot
of pollution when we are
when we have crops right growing crops
so if we can have a crop that is good
for us and good for the earth I think
people like me should really try it yeah
exactly occasionally all right so let's
learn more about gal Maga good for the
body good for the earth
the popularity of Maga is good news for
both local farmers and the environment
in the past farmers in all I cleared
forest land to grow crops which
consisted of rice and vegetables
initially and persimmon mushroom and
bamboo shoots later on the problem with
some of these crops is that they either
weaken the soil when harvested or need
lots of pesticides or fertilizers
[Music]
today's lesson is called Macau good for
the body good for the earth part 2 hi
everyone my name is Jeff and I might
guess McGaw of the mountain pepper a
local fruit grown up in Li the
@il people have known about its
wonderful health benefits and its great
taste in food for a very long time but
only now is the rest of the world
catching up we've learned that it can be
used in food you can eat it fresh and
maybe a salad make it into tea turn it
into medicine it can be good for that
digestive system all sorts of wonderful
benefits of this plant the mug ow yes
and it's fruit Macau is catching on big
time and this is good news yeah the
popularity of Macau is good news for
both local farmers and the environment
so yes because Macau is now popular
local farmers people who are growing
them a Gao they're gonna sell more make
more money but Macau is also apparently
good for the environment mmm absolutely
yeah when we talk about how popular
something is we can use the noun
popularity all right we're just
basically saying how well-known how
famous how much your average person
knows about this as trends and styles
and
fashions come and go their popularity
goes up and it goes down depending on
the year and what's going on for example
because of the restaurants popularity
you should call ahead to book a table
the restaurants popularity tells us it's
popular so it's very busy maybe five
years from now the popularity will have
gone down but right now it's hot hot hot
everyone wants to go there it is very
popular it has lots of popularity you
might even be famous it could be yeah
anyways moving on in the past farmers in
a lie
cleared forest land to grow crops which
consisted of rice and vegetables
initially and persimmon mushroom and
bamboo shoots later on and yes when you
clear a forest land that's not really
ever a good thing you shouldn't cut down
forests or clear forest land and you
have a problem with some of these other
crops that we're just talking about a
problem with some of these crops is that
they either weaken the soil when
harvested or need lots of pesticides or
fertilizers so not only are you clearing
forest land
you're also weakening the soil and using
a lot of chemicals chemical pesticides
and fertilizers and stuff like that so
none of these things are good for the
environment ok before we take a break
let's talk about the verb weakened ok
the verb weakened is the opposite of the
verb strengthened if you make something
strong or stronger you strengthen that
thing
now when you weaken something you do the
opposite you make it weaker than it was
before so maybe before you are very
strong ok and then you stop working out
or you got sick or something
oh you're not as strong anymore that
means you have been weakened
for example the floods weakened the
structure of the building before it was
a strong building but then the floods
showed up the whole area flooded and yes
the building's structure weakened it
might even fall down Oh No all right
folks at that it's time for us to take a
short break but
go away we'll be back after this hello
how she honey from Turkey and Cohen
through da na da Jung soo young Asian
nation he seemed an inline not here to
render shots in McCulloch ocean I don't
know Aloha Yahoo ha Nam children katma
31 seniors from each country all I don't
know mean haven't seen chillin daylight
from Nam so it has a don't tell me I
should say Hawaii don't change
shanku hand juice and coconut she Joey I
said so - Oh chummy shot how is some
don't around your dad sir she was shot
or shot when she was a failure
lights out some coins in the won t the
machines and Macau shoulder-high
incident in Norman - Tito she'll see
when we see like a man the band's
popularity popularity happiest urgency
for the show high in the Chengdu nammal
we can we can be sushi Michelle role
being the Shiro dashi oh she owns a week
- Zhang don't sue yen - Chanda come when
you're in Java she owns the home in
Jersey - she Pendleton a young animal
weekend the championship strengthen stre
ng th en strengthen Titan chanko gochang
wada is it number poach on dancin
persimmon persimmon tapioca shoots it
pesticide pesticide a shot on GJ vodka
and Joel Macau good for the body good
for the earth on the other hand
Macau has deep roots which make the
shrub an effective soil stabilizer it's
also easy to plant and the plant retains
its structure when it's fruit is
harvested but perhaps most importantly
it requires less water and no chemicals
to help it grow in fact using chemicals
on this sensitive plant would likely
damage or kill it
so once upon a time farmers in wool I
they cleared a bunch of forest land
which is not good and then they started
planting stuff plants crops that were
one bad for the soil that would weaken
the soil and then two they would plant
these crops that would also require the
use of fertilizers and stuff like that
chemical pesticides you name them and
these aren't good things and apparently
though Mugello is good for the
environment it's going to solve these
problems well hopefully I mean it is a
problem in Taiwan where a lot of the
land is on hillsides and during the
heavy rains that come with our typhoons
which are a part of life that can make
the whole side of the hill slide off
farms can be destroyed it can be really
really destructive and you know people
need to eat
but some of these foods that they're
growing up on those hillsides are not
the best thing on the other hand we read
Macau has deep roots which make the
shrub an effective soil stabilizer those
deep roots basically help to sort of
glue or stick or hold the soil in place
so if the rains come a lot of the soil
will not get washed the roof
strengthened the soil that's exactly
right gather in a living place you get
this it's also easy to plant and the
plant retains its structure when it's
fruit is harvested so there you go it's
easy to plant and also you won't have to
tear the entire shrub out of the ground
tear those roots out - no no no it will
retain its structure when you harvest it
that's very cool kind of like just if
you pick an apple off a tree the apple
tree just stays perfectly the same it's
not changed it's not like pulling the
whole rice plant out of the ground like
with other things retain to retain
something this verb means to keep it to
hold it it's something that you have
something might be trying to take it
away from you but you're holding on to
it okay one simple thing we try to
retain when we're cold is heat if you
wear a jacket if you put on a hat and
cover your hands or your ears one on a
very cold day it will keep your body
warmer those things especially a hat on
head and gloves on your hands will help
you retain or keep that heat in your
body keeping you feeling warm all right
we do actually use this word a lot now
talking about heat and cold or things
like that
here's another example from the world of
cooking this pan retains heat very well
so you warm it up and then it keeps the
heat so it will cook your food in a very
even regular way stays hot for a long
time days hot that's no more Miguel
though but perhaps most importantly it
requires less water and no chemicals to
help it grow somewhat Gao it sounds
really good to me if you plant Macao you
will strengthen the soil and get this
you can't use chemicals either when
growing it so you wouldn't have to use
pesticides or fertilizers or anything
else like that in fact using chemicals
like this on this sensitive plant would
like the damage or kill it so there you
go we're undoing all the damage that
conventional crops can do here in Taiwan
we're not weakening soil and we're also
not using it chemicals
sounds good to me now before we take our
break let's go ahead and take a look at
the adjectives sensitive if something is
sensitive it is easily affected by other
things like sensitive people react very
strongly to insults and stuff like that
in fact they might perceive things that
other people don't perceive now what
we're saying here is that the McGowen is
very sensitive so you can't add
chemicals and you've got to be careful
with it because you can hurt it you can
hurt it easily I should say or it will
be easily affected by things the things
that you do to it so be careful for
example I have sensitive teeth so I try
not to eat cold foods yes if I eat ice
cream oh it really affects me I can feel
that cold because I've got sensitive
teeth all right everyone with that it's
time for us to take a break but don't go
away we'll be right back after this all
I know mink what you told it so you're
the show chung chigga a song don't fool
around
Jasha and don't you have face yeah
Buchanan's on gin mark I'll choke well
to say we went along
Emmitt Otterton hanshan Kato shadow
cutroso negotiation lasagna keep all
doors open he chooses owatta no it's a
John shiroyasha wretched happy young
fashion you July solution John Shoshanna
today John Mangano Rubio washer would
fire you can wear on a show show horses
no tribunal de thé dansant retained
retain hypership polio the otro worship
out sensitive sensitive just you
know mean ganda not mean gander can
recharge without bein made without the
shooting come on cha cha cha Joo Jung da
perceives it you don't see PE are CEI ve
/ sepia Shadrach and JIT how many well
she showed John Jim a cockapoo Joe trend
owns all show it's out on the shin-hye
now she younger undo tickets you and do
and do to keep you at a shout true for
you and watch it tak see welcome John
Macao good for the body good for the
earth
Macau is therefore an ideal crop because
it is highly adaptable to eco-friendly
farming methods it helps keep pollution
out of the waters and it plays a role in
maintaining a balance in the ecosystem
in addition since the demand for Miguel
for medicine and cooking and as a source
of essential oil is there farmers can
make a profit from it
Macau is indeed one powerful plant
Mike I think I'm gonna do it are you I
think that I'm gonna move out of the
country okay and open I'm a gal
plantation that would be great
what do you know about farming I don't
know anything about farming but I know
that Macau if I were to plant it then I
would be doing the right thing as far as
the environment is concerned well you
have a point there I would suggest you
know watching a youtube video about
farming or something before you do it
but that is a very good point and that
is also what we have in our next
sentence Macau is therefore an ideal
crop it's a perfect crop because it is
highly adaptable to eco-friendly farming
methods so this is a good product for
farmers even beginner farmers like our
friend here and it's also really good
for the environment so it's one of those
things that a farmer can grow and not
really worry about the bad effects of
the chemical or damaging the soil the
chemicals these damaging the soil it
doesn't have any of those problems there
you go it helps keep pollution out of
the waters and it plays a role in
maintaining a balance in the ecosystem
so there you go once I catch on and like
Macau plantation becomes prosperous and
fruitful not only will I have tons of
cash for selling all this Macau but I'll
also be helping out the environment okay
remember it says here Miguel plays a
role in maintaining a balance in the
ecosystem don't forget it also keeps a
pollution out of the waters and that
would be a good thing because pollution
is a bad thing pollution this noun is
dirt and poison and junk and stuff we
don't want in the environment it's the
smoke in the air it's the chemicals in
the river it's the chemicals on the dirt
on the ground and the in the soil it's
garbage piles outside all the big cities
we can also talk about other things like
noise pollution all those loud trucks
and sounds you luciene light pollution
why can't I see the stars when I'm in
the city light pollution so these are
sort of negative things produced by
people or what people do
and it's in the environment it has a an
effect on our lives we try to reduce
pollution but pollution is a part of
life but there are things we can do to
make it better for example big cities
big cities often have high levels of air
pollution cars trucks factories putting
stuff into the air that chemicals those
chemicals that's the pollution as as
developing countries very often as those
countries are modernizing and building
factories sometimes they produce a lot
of pollution especially air pollution
anyways back to Macau and how it's going
to save the day in addition since the
demand for Macau for medicine and
cooking and as a source of essential oil
is there farmers can make a profit from
it so not only will it be good for the
environment but the farmers who make it
can make a profit so again once I open
my plantation and get it up and running
maybe I can make some money but no I
won't do this all-out local farmers to
make the Mogao and to make the profit as
well anyways this much is for certain
Macau is indeed one powerful plant it's
the answer to our prayers all right we
are done reading our article do we have
a question we do have a question then
Hey look at that it's about the Mageau
what is the best thing about Macau what
do you think and please explain your and
are you are you kidding the best thing
about Macau the best thing about Macau
is that when you plant it you're saving
the earth ok other crops you put them in
the ground the weak in the soil you have
to use all sorts of nasty chemicals to
make sure they grow properly if you
plant my gal you strengthen the soil and
you also allow pollution to not get into
water sources ok you're actually
removing pollution from water oh my
goodness the best thing about Macau is
mug out it's awesome there's nothing bad
about it at all and it tastes good too
and it tastes good too so there you go
Macau it's amazing it's incredible go to
Li try it out make the tea you have the
medicine put it in a salad and just in
joy it because it's good for the
environment too bye bye for now everyone
take care yourself some McGowan Ashima
calcio shelled akuto so suppose aphasia
you jo-jo Sansa ha sido hecho chauhan
sonam so fancy deletion su na kono te
aho mark our children Lauren Venetian
today with Shanghai Chippenham Femina -
virtuoso in shock Tina Macondo yo Joey
Gallo kevinturtle Hagen Marco Rubio show
corner to the fans in Japan Judah have
Ariana plantations education to you
would turn on cha choose a true plant
home enjoy a tion
hallo Sharonda fruitful fruitful shishio
yo tengo de Chickasaw Cession equal
fruit who enjoy ful Harnam bag contains
pollution pollution our children our
children erosion cover - gorgeous heavy
dong goo JA - endemic ocean John Connor
away our Father yokai ganja without
chicken children - Allah who show the
developing country Georgia - Georgia
hell did our modern nice to the don't
say shin-bi mother home in ji z european
don'ts modernize shin tae-hwan
let me transited challenge it told you
this ok Michelle
[Music]
Gaja house in handy playing show come
the wooden fat diamond see now just how
the will fight song did yo Sangha Degas
should on the other hand the Ergo should
keep something out of shimma shimma this
anger should play a role in zsa zsa
means the hotel means it only sell a
share on the other hand Philippi on the
other hand then you found me okay by
that Trisha was a true Joan you don't
like the Italian championship Bhutan for
sure you three be the team qualms me
rule Richard is a quiet person his
sister on the other hand is very
talkative
Richard sugar chin walk while I run
nothing he found me and other digits as
she fades in pan Colleen Wellman
chaozhong well on the one hand like that
Bay on the other hand the Adagio if I
mean to me young Bohemians and Mia you
lian-chu lian-chu bhutan gorgeous young
find the Quantico sound
on the one hand he wants to spend
more time with his family but on the
other hand he has to work overtime to
earn more money if I mean - Tom
Walkinshaw temp Evangeline then they
found me and happy she job and I trunk
under the chin and y'all said chatting
Hank enjoy agent Reid open hands and
ahankhah not even suggesting a
money
so you're the pusher women love the G
hey see we were talking all good
didn't I say she keep something out of
keep Altec appearing unhappy I should
switch opinion keep something out of had
repair shop sure mo Oh fancy new shimmer
or just be me mo th Oh Sheila
Chan should keep the dog out of the
kitchen we are round logical coating
true found happenin - holy she play
a role in jamming suho don't mean to
play a role sue me in the Easter should
sure you catch Elsa the mature located
in Josh young she drew saw him I got a
short session without don't sure you eat
job or play a role in jamming Soho don't
mean to keep y'all down say shimma
shimma found me a bunion each other too
much about yo any sound take a roll that
shim in case our
Shousha shannon jj' are important John
Yoda major to yell de Keigwin Jean de
dum de San Shi
Gavin played a key role in last night's
game Gavin said - and the piéce edge on
banging Quentin so how he sounds gently
and gently or massage the devil okay
[Music]
she's not really right yeah so that
topic is Eid in yen witching Yeah Yeah
right good
[Music]
uh-huh break just broke up with me he
said you found a new girlfriend I'm
shocked
I thought you guys are really happy
together feel better now
yeah yeah there's other people who could
be your boys okay just kidding
put a dunk cancel my song say it shocked
that your life doesn't sound the same
they two days on your hand yeah okay
okay
or you could say this is unbelievable
unbelievable
why drums boxes because yeah this is
unbelievable Wow
or this one's funny I'm blown away
yo ting Dao someone well we're going to
go through our check information oh I
took a shower just ah Ching really
shines bright sweet although shocked you
know no well maybe a little bit if you
like being shocked then then will shock
you yeah thank our man
haha I'm shocked I'm shocked
this is unbelievable this is
unbelievable
I'm blown away I'm blown away
[Music]