[Music]
hi everyone this is Karen everybody I am
Shane today we're looking at part 1 of
Macau get for the body good for the
earth and the vocabulary words are
unique unique the unique design of the
church makes it a popular spot for
tourists consume consume according to
some experts you should consume 2 cups
of fruit per day
mmm delicate delicate been really
enjoyed the delicate flavor of the wine
digestion digestion Lloyd often suffers
from digestion problems hmm
relieved relieved Omar took some
medicine to relieve his Medic so we're
talking about Miguel my god have you
ever been to lie um yeah of course yeah
I've been to lie before and have you
tried Miguel because this is a really
popular in a lie so that's where you get
it isn't I've been there but I don't
remember trying it no you remember
seeing all these like little food
vendors and then they sell the sausages
and then there will be like oh these are
sausages with the Mayo gal flavor maybe
because I'm a vegetarian
I don't maybe it's a seasoning a lot of
the time maybe that's why ok because if
they're using it as a seasoning it might
be for spicing a meat yes because I
heard it has a bit of a pepper taste you
add it what does it taste like well see
the thing is I don't really have a
sensitive taste but whatever I eat I
just feel like okay that's the semi and
you were to ask me in detail how does it
taste like just check-in journey yeah ok
well it's also used kind of like
medicine too right that's right I heard
that the essential oil it kind of has
like citrus smell to it and if you have
a card or something will problem with
your skin you can rub it on there and it
also helps with your digestion too I
think it's just kind of like ginger
because they say it also tastes a little
bit like ginger that's right
so next time you should definitely try
I'm sure I can get it outside of will I
too right I guess so actually I'm not
sure I'm sure you can I'm gonna get
anything online these days I guess so
yeah I guess you're right okay so let's
learn more about Macau Macau good for
the body good for the earth the district
of Li is blessed with rich soil that
makes it possible for many plants to
thrive there
one such plant is Macau or mountain
pepper capable of growing in areas from
100 to 1,500 metres above sea level this
native shrub is prized for its unique
qualities and favorable effects on human
and environmental health
today's lesson is called Maga good for
the body good for the earth part 1 hello
everyone my name is Jeff and I'm Mike
and yes we're talking about the Macau
which is not in any way even though it
sounds similar related to Macau and I
thought you were talking about Macau you
can go gamble there right
I thought they spelled the place wrong
and when I first read it but no this is
completely different this is not the
gambling place that that city near Hong
Kong with the casinos and hotels no no
no this is not a place it's a thing and
in fact it's a food and in fact it's
from here in Taiwan yeah the district of
wulai all you have to do to get some
Maga is go to ulla you don't have to get
on a plane and fly to Hong Kong or Macau
just go to who lie anyways the district
of ooh lie is blessed with rich soil
that makes it possible for many plants
to thrive there yes there's rich soil so
plants grow very well there they thrive
there they flourish there and yes one
such plant is Mogao or Mountain pepper
all right so now we have a bit of a
better idea what it is obviously it
grows on
it's a peppers it's a little spicy a
vegetable of some kind and yeah this is
a very hearty thing to grow it seems to
be really doing well in July and here we
kind of find out why capable of growing
in areas from 100 to 1500 meters above
sea level this native shrub is prized
for its unique qualities and favorable
effects on human and environmental
health
Wow so it grows in lots of areas right
down near the water near the the sea
level 100 meters right up to like way up
the side of a hill or a mountain 1,500
meters it does well in all of those
areas it's a shrub like a bush big
bigger than a plant smaller than a tree
but with woody branches kind of like a
tree but much smaller and it's very very
unusual special and really kind of cool
yep I couldn't have possibly said it any
better myself anyways before we take a
break here let's talk about the word
unique it's an adjective if something is
unique it's one of a kind okay there's
nothing else like it anywhere that being
said when you hear this word usually
people use it interchangeably with the
word special it does mean one-of-a-kind
but you can also use the word unique to
talk about something that's special
maybe unusual in a good way maybe
something that's original you can use
you can use this word unique to describe
those sorts of things
for example the unique design of the
church makes it a popular spot for
tourists it doesn't look like other
churches so yet tourists like to take in
that particular church you're talking
about that church so looks like a big
shoe I didn't know there was such a
structure but I want that sounds quite
unique very unique alright folks with
that it's time for us to take a break
but when we come back we'll be talking
about a church that looks like a shoe
hello Jamie
tomorrow will be a time when Juan's
India was a true geology me konnichiwa
Marco sounds uncle Marco hard on the
comes around he Nicosia Isha ma da MH
u8w
how my cultures ano ich in here yo f1
team doesn't sue you torsion Tina now my
gosh hi Joshua
hi cash can dodge ago when John Bell TSO
a some Ziemba almond England pin Sola
NACA you macau almond almond YouTube
homological casino - see - cha - 18 to
see a s I and O casino hanko akashi
deshou all i tree your favorite ooh-rah
AHA no joke a tournament Joe Johnson
John Hersey joy Junction Marco
kyocho mention who Joe tanto en
Shangguan Munna you tattooed her she
Hyuna chain consequence in yo-yo shoot
outro shoot imagine I can't and unique
unique shishio - tada - show each other
Oh make a young one of a kind
take a foolish idea that we were the
jinn Yoda
bojong Danza thrive thrive Tapio Jung
Hyung Joong washing self enroll now Yoga
is a chance in the don't schedule
flourish f ll u R is H flourished higher
capilla de otro Junction Jung Ching
Chang Feng Yong hak tell like I went on
the shrub shrub tapioca mu cang oh my
gosh oh my gosh a John srimad Sangha
jewel now she owned a hearty lysine
janta h ard white heart iike manju
srimad shang delusion night hand see
Rocco and John
Macau
good for the body good for the earth the
name Agha
comes from the Atty 'l who for centuries
have been gathering the plants fruit and
using it as both a seasoning and a
medicine with a complex flavor that
combines hints of ginger lemongrass and
pepper the fruit may be consumed either
fresh steeped in hot water to make tea
or dried as the spice in cooking in fact
miguel appears in a wide variety of
traditional a tile and other Aboriginal
dishes from
filling soups made with wild game to
more delicate fare such as steamed fish
[Music]
we're going to almond Macau and we're
going to gamble right wrong today we're
talking about Macao mountain pepper now
the name Macau comes from the entire
people who for centuries have been
gathering the plants fruit and using it
as both a seasoning and a medicine mmm
interesting so native people this native
group the ITL one of the I believe 13
recognized native groups in Taiwan
they've been using this stuff for a long
time both for its healthy benefits and
also just for its delicious flavor in
their food let's find out about that
delicious flavor cuz it really does
sound quite wonderful with a complex
flavor complex meaning kind of
complicated you'll see why we use a word
like complex or complicated with a
complex flavor that combines hints of
ginger lemongrass and pepper
hmmm the fruit may be consumed either
fresh steeped in hot water to make tea
or dried as a spice in cooking that
would be the Mount and pepper part
that's this place the II use in
cooking's that great to flavor your food
so it can be used in lots of ways you
can use it fresh like eat it in a salad
you can use it to make tea I guess that
might be a dried version to or really
dry it and probably crush it to a powder
like a spice like you put in your soups
and other foods to give them more
interesting flavors so you can eat it
you can take it into your body you can
consume it in lots of different ways
depending on what you want to consume
when we talk about food we're talking
about eating the food okay so you
consume food to give your body energy so
you can do stuff during the day consume
can be used in other ways it basically
means to use up something you know cars
consume of gas to drive or businesses
might consume wood and in order to make
furniture or something like that so
there's lots of different ways we can
use it but Jen
when we're talking about food the body
science we consume food now you wouldn't
say hey do you want to come and consume
lunch with us no you would ask people to
come and eat lunch with you as I said
it's more of a scientific type of word
for example according to some experts
you should consume 2 cups of fruit per
day you could say eat but you know yeah
here they're using the word consume
because you don't necessarily have to
eat it ok you could eat it but you could
also drink it ok so you're putting it in
your body you're ingesting it so we're
using this more general word consume now
more on Maga in fact Macau in a wide
variety of traditional attire and other
Aboriginal dishes from filling soups
made with wildgame to more delicate fare
such as steamed fish yes steamed fish
you steamed a fish that flesh will be
very very delicate it will fall off the
bone it might even fall off your fork or
it might fall out of your grasp as far
as your chopsticks are concerned so
that's what it means to have delicate
fare if something is delicate it can be
easily broken like the flesh of a
steamed fish now on the other hand let's
say you have wild game like wild boar or
wild deer or something like that that
meat might be somewhat tougher and
harder to break it's not going to be
delicate by the way the word delicate is
an adjective and like I said before
we're talking about something that's
delicate talking about something that is
easily broken ok
for example Ben really enjoyed the
delicate flavor of the wine yes Ben
enjoyed that wine but he probably
wouldn't be able to taste that if he ate
a food let's say that hey stronger
flavor he wouldn't be able to sense that
delicate flavor anymore ok so we might
also say light it's a light flavor it's
not a strong or powerful flavor it's
would be easily broken by another flame
right ok so it's it's a light flavor
it's not too strong as well that's the
idea there interesting all right let's
take a break and then we'll be back with
more about the
Miguel but not Macau no mokou tickets is
really retaliatory pants were and show
teachers don't do the cool I taught
you well they'll hang out you know how
to get till oh my god hi yo Joe
foods out of sheer way FeO Eden jung-min
moans how how huge all the way down the
machine change in Telugu clean I like
how they really mean pouch our rural
Shabak washes say thank you my bangs
chun-li our hats as a lowly down Joe
Norma's and I can't dance it consume
consume Pasha don't seduce young young
pushes shower how touches upon the young
fella call you down zone when Salman
down show true now about show true
turndown service equina say it'll be joe
johnson kosher will to enjoy so a young
daughter Hannah mashaallahu kana I own
that ingest wickets it ing est singer
taking like that I should she she showed
the easy how they my window how young da
ginger you should jump lemongrass
passion amongst all the must citrus pair
should country Roger country show that
you co entirety - oh my god Roseanne
Baker's sugar younger Trenton chaotzu
Lally
it is hit high and room in da Li dong
Jong hak each other we will tongue we
made you cage as I don't be touching
than the taste so that young rich later
how no one kind of dance it delicate
delicate takahashi no Ching than me
waiter occasional shinchi de number went
on the wild game some cowboy years young
yoshiya wild game that's event in hazard
there was a year wait yet seen kasha
precocial means it controversial sure
the wild boar wild board this is a year
jewel she's on the BOA our board just
yet Jul de ESA's Oaxaca and John Macau
good for the body good for the earth
Macau is also valued as a medicine due
to its healing and comforting properties
essential oil made from a GAO has a
refreshing citrus smell and often
features in personal care and beauty
products
applied on the body it can aid digestion
relieve skin reactions and reduce muscle
pain okay more on Macau Macau everyone
is delicious okay it's got a very
complicated complex flavor but there's
more it can also be used as a medicine
yeah Maga is also valued as a medicine
due to its healing and comforting
properties so this kind of sounds like
Macau is Taiwan's answer to garlic
yeah people use garlic as a seasoning on
food it makes other foods taste even
better but it's also very good for you
sometimes people do use garlic as a
special herb with medicinal purposes
yeah that's right it's got a lot of
vitamins in it but the good thing about
Macau is it smells better than garlic
you don't like the smell
oh I like the smell of garlic but you
wouldn't have garlic smelling perfume
nothing like that Melling smoked a soap
for your hands that wouldn't really work
so well but with Macau that is a
possibility we read essential oil made
from Macau has a refreshing citrus smell
and often features in personal care and
beauty products yeah a nice citrus smell
it's probably better than essence of
garlic so yes I imagine Macau is
probably a better additive when beauty
products and stuff like that are
concerned
colognes perfumes creams the list goes
on and on
Macau is probably better for those
things than garlic is anyways though
Macau remember can be used as a medicine
yeah applied on the body it can aid
digestion relieve skin reactions and
also reduce muscle pain okay folks it's
official Macau can do it all it can even
help with digestion that's what they say
a digestion when we use this word it's a
noun and it talks about how our bodies
process food our digestion system would
be everything from you know how the food
gets down into our stomachs certainly
the stomach the
the intestines where the food gets
squeezed through before it all comes out
the other end
that's digestion so if you have a
stomach problem if you had some spicy
food and you don't feel well a little
bit later oh I'm having some digestion
problems you know my stomach hurts or
some something I ate is not making me
feel very good for example Lloyd Oh
Lloyd often suffers from digestion
problems you shouldn't have spicy hot
pot every day Lloyd how many times have
I told you yeah that might give you a
lot dude sir it might give you some
digestion issues anyways before we take
a break let's go ahead and talk about
the verb relieve here let's say that you
are in pain oh I've got a headache okay
you might want to take a medication to
relieve your pain okay if you relieve
something in this particular situation
you take that thing you take it away
before you had pain now you feel better
that's what it means to relieve pain in
this particular situation for example
Omar took some medicine to relieve his
headache he took a Tylenol or an
ibuprofen and now he feels better the
pain has gone away his headache has been
relieved alright folks with that today's
lesson is now in the books but don't go
away we're back with more next time
Macario night so lowly Caetano Yahoo
even hey Leo you each if we're 13 young
makoto-san a junior Dodger hmm changing
patient's own country's young way now to
erection sound okay pound Rishabha why
hope he would certify he'll change in t
Rotom tom animal and jungle property
tickets that the imposition on Petes
hands larry saw how she touched her she
the man essential oil
tap out shooting yo woman say Oh like I
never danced it digestion digestion
Tasha Shah Jahan amigo a shellfish she
talked not had a she ownership Atsui
iom catch an IV e pension digestive
digestive - owatta home k own digestive
system
la-da-da bushido digestive
how know my closet she dances she uh
intestine tickets Jung Chung Chung way
the negatron hasha teens or int EST i
and ii shower got that bad chong usual
large intestine shout down to the small
intestine holiday i can't relieve relief
don't see our chin chin Tsushima
want hug now in total no jokin will now
yo like Jim want um Toma Josh allows
young dumb medications exist and Edic a
tion medication to 300 nanometers
Shangguan the decision medicinal and EDI
CI and al medicinal shishio yah yah yah
yah Xiao de han allows LT de tylenol
ibuprofen so now that silly those it's
Tony AHA us at home so Yahoo ha ha no me
it sounds like they're challenging bills
ok Masha well
[Music]
so John house in handy hi and she'll
come to one side and tell judge how far
jeong daeun yo silica bigger should be
blessed with something there ago should
make it possible to josh angry and she
don't sit this angers a hint of
something this singer should either A or
B well missile and be blessed with
something don'ts a blessed tile truthful
about yo the east you KP out that game
he goes on should he go more and Modi
how do the shoot through the Shangguan
the dong woman Shan Shan who you'll
be blessed with something like that yo
Shinto Taoism how the shoe Christian
yoshiyama they fool you Shiva sound sure
the area is blessed with good climate
and rich soil say they treat 13 to whole
yo-yo your energy whole ETF a war to run
how did Elijah she make it possible to
Jagan seen don't sit now man yo make
shots possible Joe Pesci motion wake
unum cuz shut down showed Saoirse
potentially just too challenging don't
to the Shona
well me on she shot it like that he
showed to the wait
now how about change and the shots put
into it out three way Joey ginger make
it possible to challenge II don't see
Hannah pudding sashimi hi kitchen for
somebody who sure for something Nevada
Shimura
ocean motion Gautam yeah Chang
the Internet has made it possible for us
to communicate with people from around
the world
wahoo Schulman gogans should I go to
goat home not to show true it's good to
communicate with people from around the
world happen and she down shots Leon
payee thought you ago when there is a
hint of something hint Saddam in saliva
- ouchie way down is olive oil a hint of
something like that
EEP Indian shimma shimma shimma Chang
he found a hint of coriander in the
soup has Italian fashion Yoshi eschew
the chance I want assault horizontally
now king of upon Kaiba
come on Lulu ha ha ha until I said she
either A or B either a or Venus it'll
push a Joe should be a ho be the cheeto
Iike the maybe that's it in your eternal
visual you can have either the ice cream
or the cake for dessert the occasion
been cheating she tangled on Kenya
since ano Hong Kong called Aoyama push
it into archery you know you're either
or the urgent eat how it sounds you and
Julian to me we started it all
bye-bye I'm sure I am Holly something
feels weird in here
hmm what I did you know died she was
learning hi pop you look like you don't
feel well are you okay I'm not sure I
ate spicy hot pot last night
and now something's not right with my
tummy much better
do not let touch with bad time okay much
better
yeah good everything's right now
everything's right okay so something's
not right something's not right with
hygiene breeding districting is that
right yeah or you could say something
seems off
okay seem just cancel your EBN think we
do a cheek wash sequence
things seems off or you can say
something strange who dis change isn't
that strange
why did you change your hair something
seems off you're off or you forgot to
take a shower I see okay anyway anyway
something still seems off right we
should forgot to say something Oh Cara I
do something was off right strange
something's not right
something's not right something seems
off something seems off something
strange something strange
[Music]