[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody i'm shane
today we're looking at part two of a
walk on the high line
new york city's highest park
and the vocabulary words are multiple
multiple
joanna made multiple copies of the
report
district district toronto's
entertainment district
has some of the city's best restaurants
historic historic a statue marks the
location where a historic event took
place many years ago ideal ideal
we found an ideal spot to have a picnic
landmark landmark big ben is one of
london's
most famous landmarks so we're still
talking about
you know the high line and how it was
transformed into a beautiful park
yeah and it's a great way to go and
explore
new york city that's right because you
can kind of go up
and above and then walk around and see
lots of really
cool things kind of like a bird's eye
view
so you can see like the meat packing
district which is
quite famous what else can you see i
think there's also like art and
fashion and business centers and you can
also see the river too
right oh there's like chelsea market ah
the birthplace of oreo cookies
that's a really famous thing and then by
the end you can get to
uh mercado like the little spain it's
like a spanish area where you can get
some really cool spanish food
really yummy stuff to eat wow so it
sounds like a really cool way
to explore right and there's the beauty
around you and you get to see all of the
city it was such a wonderful
idea of how they transformed the high
line to now the beautiful park
yeah i really love when they do that
kind of like a kind of a renaissance
of an area when it starts to lose its
original
function or purpose and then they
repurpose it into something beautiful
and natural i think that's really cool
i know okay well you guys learn more
about this beautiful park
enjoy
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
so what's the best way to spend a day in
new york city's highest park
the high line has multiple entrances but
many people begin at the park's southern
end the trail here winds its way through
the meatpacking district
a historic meat processing area that's
now an art
fashion and business center and
eventually takes you to a lovely river
scene
today's lesson is called a walk on the
high line
new york city's highest
park part two hello everyone my name
is jeff and i'm mike and yes we're
learning about
new york city's highest and probably
most unusual park
this was originally an elevated railway
that carried trains and goods right
through the middle of
manhattan through the middle of new york
city but
since 2009 the city has been turning it
into a park
yes a park that is above the streets and
there
people could today can walk for a mile
and a half
see art exhibits eat delicious food at
food stands
and of course see a lot of beautiful
gardens and trees and stuff like that
yeah
in a park above the city streets so we
begin today's article by a question with
a question it says so
what's the best way to spend a day in
new york city's highest park if you're
like me
and you've never been to the high line
what would be some good advice for how
to enjoy it
if you're going there for the first time
well i've got an answer
all right i got an answer there for you
mike the high line
has multiple entrances there are many
different ways you can get in there
but many people begin at the parks
southern end not another not the
northern
and we want to go to the southern end
interesting all right so you can enter
it from many different places
of course these are probably the old
train stations along the old railway
that way that's why we see that
adjective multiple
entrances an entrance is a way in right
the opposite would be an
exit a way out multiple just means
many more than one we could say the high
line has
many entrances all right we're just
using this word multiple
but it basically means the same as many
or a lot
for a lot more than one for example
joanna
made multiple copies of the report she
didn't just write one and keep it safe
no she made lots of copies or many
copies so that she would have
more okay now the trail here from the
southern end
the southern the southern end yeah the
southern and that the northern
the southern end the trail here winds
its way
through the meat packing district
a historic meat processing area that's
now an
art fashion and business center and
eventually takes you to a lovely
river scene so when we're talking about
a district we're talking about
a neighborhood or a part of a city
that's got its own
defining characteristic hey what do they
do in that part of the city
meat packing it's the meat packing
district for example
toronto's entertainment district
has some of the city's best restaurants
also there's entertainment oh okay so we
might have a financial district with all
the
offices of banks and stuff like that an
entertainer a
shopping district with many malls and
stores things like that so
yeah it's a little bit of a different
part of a major
city and we also talked about this being
a historic
area or district of new york something
that's historic
this adjective just means it's important
to history
all right so it's old obviously but it's
not something that
just was a a common thing in the past or
we don't know who owned it or who lived
there or something no
we do know because there's someone
important or some important events
or something like that happen to it
historians will study it
if it's something historic we might find
it in a museum
or something like that it's important to
history for example
a statue marks the location where a
historic
event took place many years ago
someone was born there or some important
treaty was signed or
a famous battle took place or something
like that
something that was important to history
let's take a break and then we'll be
back
with our tour of the high line from the
southern end
not the northern the southern southern
end hello
hi
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
further on you'll find chelsea market
the birthplace of the oreo cookie
and an ideal spot to stop for lunch
after that
the tracks run past areas thick with
plants where you may see local birds
you'll also spot one of the most famous
landmarks in the city
the empire state building as well as art
pieces that vary throughout the year
okay so we've we've started at the
southern end there we've moved
along the meat packing district there
we've got a lovely view of the river
and you know what further on you'll find
chelsea market the birthplace
of the oreo cookie and
an ideal spot to stop for lunch though
you won't have to sit there and eat like
a bag full of oreos or
anything like that there are nice
restaurants where you can eat
things other than oreo cookies yes
a lunch of oreo cookies probably would
not be
ideal anyways if something is ideal
though
it's pretty good it's not perfect but
it's
close it's not perfect it's not perfect
it's not exactly right but it's really
close it's super awesome it's great for
example
we have found an ideal spot to have
a picnic this is a super great place to
have a picnic
is it the best place ever no but boy
is it close it's almost heaven all right
so as we're walking along the high line
from the south we might notice a slight
change maybe the
southern end has more of those art
exhibits or food
stands but then as we continue on it
says after that
the tracks run past areas thick with
plants where you may see local birds so
it sounds like it gets a
little bit more wild as we move away
from the chelsea market and meat packing
district areas a few few bigger plants
and trees maybe we
hear more birds and also if we look
through those trees
we will see a very famous new york city
site
it says you'll also spot one of the most
famous landmarks in the city the
empire state building as well as art
pieces that vary
throughout the year wow very cool so we
have nature around us
if we look between the buildings we'll
see that famous landmark the empire
state building you know the one that
king kong was hanging off of in those
old movies originally the tallest
building
in new york city and of course more art
pieces or art exhibits what is a
landmark
well this word means basically a famous
site
something that you would look at maybe
in a postcard or
if you go to a a country or a city
you'll definitely want to see that
it kind of marks that place if you see
it you
think of this place the eiffel tower is
the landmark of paris taipei 101
for taipei big ben that big clock tower
in london
that is definitely a landmark and also
the subject of our sentence
big ben is one of london's most famous
landmarks not all landmarks are made by
people we can have natural ones too
large mountains or
things like that but basically a very
famous place
that is very very connected to a certain
place and
tourists will definitely want to check
it out there you have it all right folks
let's go ahead and take a short break
but
when we come back we'll have more
we are planning a trip to osaka
where the music festival will be held
foreign
[Music]
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
by the time you reach the northern end
of the park you'll likely have an
appetite again
but luckily you'll be right by the
mercado little spain
grab a few spanish treats to snack on
before checking out the modern buildings
in hudson yards
or climb back up into the green
wonderland above and explore the high
line again
feel the pulse of new york as you walk
along this once vital transportation
artery
okay so remember we're at the park there
high line park and we started at the
southern end
that's where you start your trip there
now by the time you reach the northern
end of the park
you'll likely have an appetite again
but luckily you'll be right by the
mercado little spain
so mercado means market
market little spain so you'll be able to
grab a few spanish
snacks there ah interesting yeah it says
grab a few
spanish treats to snack on before
checking out the modern buildings in
hudson
yards so the food that you're grabbing
there these treats that you'll snack on
you're
probably walking and eating as you
continue along the high line
you get up to the hudson yards so you
can stop there or
it says climb back up into the green
wonderland above
and explore the high line again so
obviously the spanish market
it's down on the ground level right you
have to get back down to street level
buy your snack you can stop there and
take the subway back to your hotel or
get back
up on the high line and enjoy this green
wonderland above this park that's right
there above
the city and it's a great place to feel
the energy or
pulse feel the pulse feel the pulse of
new york as you walk along this
once vital transportation
artery yeah at one point it was
important
for transportation it was a dream line
now
it's important culturally though
very important anyways folks that's it
for
our article and now it's time for us to
ask and then answer the one
question mike can you think
of any public parks or spaces
in other countries that are similar
to the high line oh gosh well the high
line reminds me of a place i don't
know the name of it reminds me of that
old river
that goes through seoul south korea i
never went there when i went to korea it
was the middle of winter
but during the summer time there's this
old river i don't know the name
but it used to be very polluted and
dirty and nobody
went there but since you know about 10
years ago or 15 years ago
like the high line the city's brought it
back to life now it's a tourist
attraction
people go there and sit by the water in
the summer it's clean and wonderful so
it's kind of like that it's a wonderful
time or a wonderful story i should say
of a city taking something that was
really kind of forgotten
and you know kind of dirty and and not a
nice thing and turned it into a
wonderful
thing for tourists and locals sounds
good to me all right folks with that
it's time for us to take a break and to
say
bye bye take care
melissa took a hot bath before she went
to bed
melissa said
melissa took a hot bath before going to
bed
howdy sangha jongin hey you don't should
check out
shiddang
let's check out the new department store
you can
enjoy
[Music]
it's cold here in alaska thank goodness
i have my igloo to keep me warm igloos
are
made of snow so they don't look like
they can keep people warm
but they actually do a great job
a well-made igloo can increase the
inside temperature
40 degrees above the outside temperature
the walls of the igloo block out the
wind
freezing winds can make the air feel
much colder
the inuit invented igloos hundreds of
years ago
most people believe that inuit lived in
igloos
all the time actually igloos were used
mainly by hunters hunters stated igloos
while they hunted for seals to build an
igloo
you need the right kind of snow the soft
powdery kind isn't ideal it can't be
packed tightly enough
to build an igloo now it looks like the
snow conditions
are pretty good if you want i could show
you how to build
your own igloo here is more
information frozen
the lake here in winter is always frozen
dome the building is famous for its
special
dome shape
the cake's shape is of a heart
build my grandfather wants to build
a house made from wood
building the post office is next to a
tall building
roof the roof of the cute little house
is red
hole there is a hole in the wall
next to the door
block they used blocks of stone
to build a strong wall
temperature temperatures suddenly
dropped
last week
tunnel the train went through many
tunnels
thanks for joining us today i hope you
learned a lot
we'll catch you later