[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome back
everybody this is shane
today we're looking at part two of
putting pen to paper
the history of ballpoint pens and the
vocabulary words are
crew crew the captain of the ship asked
the crew
to do their best responsible responsible
the teacher discovered that dennis was
responsible for the broken window
household household diane made a list of
all the household chores
that need to be done contribute
contribute
a heart problem contributed to the
singer's death
essential essential heat electricity and
hot water
are considered essential services so
we're still talking about
ballpoint pens right right so i guess
this guy bureau made a lot of
money from this invention right at first
basically um it was just in argentina
that's right and he was able to sell
some of it like a really big contract
was to the uk i think the royal navy
that's right or air force right and that
was a big thing but he's not really the
one who spread the ballpoint pen all
over the world
it was actually an american businessman
right
go america milton reynolds i remember
his name is
right but i think one thing about the
ballpoint pen is that
it's kind of responsible for the curse
of writing
going out of fashion what do you mean
because when you write with a fountain
pen it's very easy to connect the
letters
together but with the ballpoint pen it's
not
quite as easy and so i think people
started to print and use like block
letters
more instead of cursive writing yeah
what a pity because i
love cursive writing it is really pretty
but yes but
i like nowadays i don't really see
anybody writing
in cursive writing yeah i wonder if
they're still teaching it in school
in like you know english-speaking
countries if it's important anymore but
i learned it and you learned it
yeah and i love it even until today i
still do it okay
well hopefully you learned a little bit
about the ballpoint pen
and learned a little bit about how sad
we are that handwriting or cursive
writing is out of fashion
okay enjoy today's lesson enjoy
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
biro began selling his pen in argentina
where he and his brother had fled to
during world war ii his biggest customer
was the uk's
royal air force which ordered 30 000
pens to allow its crews
to write more easily while in the air
unfortunately
bureau wasn't able to spread his
invention around the world
instead american businessman milton
reynolds was the man
responsible for that after seeing the
pens in argentina
he changed the design just enough to
sell them as his own
though expensive the pens were a big hit
with american customers in the 1940s
[Music]
today's lesson is called putting pen to
paper the history
of ballpoint pens part two
hello everyone my name is jeff my name's
mike ballpoint pens they're everywhere
you probably have one around you right
now
yesterday we learned about laszlo bureau
not a great scientist but a hungarian
journalist
who used old-fashioned fountain pens
leaked ink everywhere
got on his hands and all over the place
he thought there's got to be a better
way he saw some kids
rolling marbles through water he thought
if i could roll
ink across the page in the same way that
would make a good pen
he came up with the bulb that's what he
did well he and his brother and his
brother
they developed an ink but yes the ball
the marble rolling through the puddle
and making a line it gave me inspiration
for the ballpoint pen
and hungary it has been
invented yes and there's more to the
story
biro began selling his pen in
argentina where he and his
brother had fled to during
world war ii i'm sure there's a story
behind that
but let's go ahead and move on now his
biggest customer was the uk's
royal air force which ordered 30
000 pens to allow its crews to write
more easily while in the air
fascinating so there you go the royal
air force that's you know the the
the guys who fly warplanes around during
world war
ii the british royal air force or the uk
they ordered a bunch of these pens for
their crews
because those planes used to fly real
high it was cold up there
the old ink would just freeze inside the
pens
and the flight crews didn't want frozen
ink
in their pens what is a crew a crew is
basically a
team of workers working together
probably closely
for some special job we can talk about
the crew of a ship
the sailors and the officers the people
who run the ship
work the ship drive the ship fix the
ship that's the crew we could have a
film crew the people who do the lights
and the camera and the sound guy and the
makeup people
those are the film crew so they're all
working on a specific job
they all have different jobs but they
work as a
team for example the captain of the ship
asked the crew
to do their best do your best men and
they said yes sir
and they went off and did their best so
there you go so the air force
orders all these pins now
unfortunately beeru
wasn't able to spread his invention
around the world i just realized
something you know what british people
call ballpoint pens
what they call them biros spelt that way
interesting yeah that's why because the
royal air force ordered
them but still what's the story here
why was he not able to spread his
invention
throughout the world well the american
here's the story instead
it says that american businessman
milton reynolds was the man responsible
for that that's why americans don't call
them biros because of milton reynolds
milton reynolds what did he do what was
he responsible for
i bet he stole the idea he did he was
responsible for it
he did it he was behind
this by the way yes if you are
responsible
for something you
had a hand in that or in bringing
that thing about you did it you
caused it you were behind no
we're not talking about being
responsible people
oh you can trust me i'm responsible
no here we're kind of pointing a finger
as far as
guilt is concerned anyways for example
the teacher discovered that dennis
was responsible for the broken window
they don't call him dennis the menace
for nothing
anyways after seeing the pens in
argentina
he changed the design just enough
to sell him as his own oh so he stole
the
iphone and called it an e-phone and
changed the screen a little bit and made
a lot of money
that kind of idea oh that's terrible
well though expensive
the pens were a big hit with american
customers
in the 1940s let's take a break and then
we'll be back with more about
the ballpoint pen or the biro hello
again
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
eventually mass production made plastic
ballpoint pens more affordable
and soon they were a household staple
although ballpoint pens were convenient
they changed the way that people write
because of the way the ink flows it
doesn't feel natural to join letters
together
in addition ballpoint pens can be less
comfortable to write with
because more pressure must be applied
when writing with them
some say these factors contributed to
the decline of cursive writing
[Music]
okay we're talking about ball point
pens now right before the break it said
that
in america there ballpoint pens were
kind of popular but they were also
kind of expensive but eventually
mass production made plastic
ballpoint pens more affordable
and soon they were a household
staple translation eventually
there were factories people learned how
to make
these pens by the boatload
out of plastic they became cheap and
then they were
everywhere they became household staples
absolutely a household is basically your
home
and the things and often the people
inside it all right so that is your
household
you have things in your household people
live in your household
furniture machines food you pay taxes on
your household and all sorts of stuff so
we're not just talking about the
building
we're talking about the place you live
if it's an apartment if it's a house
doesn't matter and the things and
activities and people
that are all involved in it that is your
household for example
diane made a list of all the household
chores
that need to be done cleaning washing
paying the bills
cooking all of these things might be
household
chores so a household staple is
something every home will have
every home will have ballpoint pens not
just rich people or whatever because
they're so
cheap and easy to get although ballpoint
pens were convenient
they change the way that people write
very interesting so they were very
useful cheap
people used them so much that it
actually changed the way human beings
write their words why is that because of
the way the ink flows
it doesn't feel natural to join letters
together that was the old style of
writing
right cursive writing yeah you would
join all your letters together
in a flowing kind of way yeah and
in addition ballpoint pens can be
less comfortable to write with
because more pressure must be applied
when writing with them so push down here
are some
drawbacks okay now some say
these factors contributed
to the decline of cursive writing
i learned to write cursive i don't
write in cursive i would say that
texting probably is going to
lead to the decline of cursive writing
but that's a different topic for a
different
day here we have the verb contribute if
something
contributes to something in this case
it leads to that thing or it has a hand
in that thing so some people think the
ballpoint pen
it's everywhere people use them all
over the place and because of certain
drawbacks to the
ballpoint pen i should say that maybe
people
don't write in cursive as much as they
used to
they write those block letters where all
the letters are separate
that's what i do anyways for example a
hard
problem contributed to the
singer's death not a ballpoint pen
no it was a heart problem he was smoking
too much and just
had a heart attack anyways folks with
that it's time for us to take a break
but don't
go away we'll be back soon
it doesn't feel natural to maintain
physical
distance from our loved ones
on
putting pen to paper the history of
ballpoint pens
ballpoint pens have become an essential
tool in our everyday lives
who would have thought that this amazing
invention was inspired
by something as simple as children
playing with marbles
okay folks let's start wrapping things
up
ball point pens have become an
essential tool in our everyday
lives we can't do without them
if we didn't have ballpoint pens we'd
have to write with pencils or
markers or feather quills
quills or fountain pens or
crayons right oh gosh the list goes on
and on yeah
absolutely that's why ballpoint pens are
essential they're
necessary if you want to write easily
and you don't want to spend a lot of
money or make a lot of
mess the ballpoint pen is what you need
and if something is essential
this adjective just says it's necessary
it's
needed you can't really do this thing
without it
or if you tried it would be a lot more
difficult
for example if you want to travel to
another country
a passport is essential you can't get
into a foreign country
without a passport unless you're the
queen of england or something like that
now if something is essential it just
means we need it it's
very very important or even absolutely
needed in our lives for example heat
electricity
and hot water are considered essential
services if you move into a new home or
build a new building you have to attach
it to the part the pipes and all that
stuff from the city
that bring in water and electricity
otherwise you might as well just live in
a tent in the forest
because you won't have any of that stuff
but for most buildings
it's absolutely essential and who
would have thought that this amazing
invention was
inspired by something as simple as
children playing with
marbles there you go amazing absolutely
all right that's it with our article and
now it's time to
ask and then answer the question
mike do you prefer to write with a pen
or a pencil and why
i like writing with a pen
better because i don't think i have a
pencil at home
you do not own a pencil i don't know
that maybe i have one of those clicky
pencils but then they break or you
you run out of the the the lead the
pens are much more convenient and plus
you can't erase them
and they're neater
mike doesn't own a pen why would i have
a pencil
a pencil why would i have a pencil gosh
all right folks with that today's lesson
is now in the books and it's
time to say bye bye take care
[Music]
well
australia has some interesting and
unique landscapes
bungal bungal range is a collection of
rock formations in honolulu
national park in western australia it's
a beautiful place with colorful layers
of orange
and black rocks the sandstone and other
rocks formed over 350 million years ago
scientists think that a meteorite hit
the area a long time ago
that might be one of the reasons it
looks so unique
wind in the tsunami desert and rainfall
created these patterns on the rocks too
weathering made deep canyons and some
great
rock climbing spots the bungal bungal
range
wasn't discovered by the outside world
until 1982
but aboriginal people have been living
in the area for around
20 000 years because it's located in
such a remote place
not many tourists make it to see the
bungal bungal range
in person follow a guide to take you to
the best rock formations
in australia here is more
information algae
seaweed is a type of algae
deposit the river deposits
small rocks and dirt at its mouth
dome there is a large dome on top of the
building
a road the ocean eroded
the cliffs gorge
taroko gorge is a famous gorge in taiwan
sandstone sandstone is made when sand
is pressed down for many years
seabed the seabed is
the bottom of the ocean stack
brian ate a stack of pancakes for
breakfast
weather wind and rain over
millions of years weathered away the
mountains
whirlpool that boat was caught
in a big whirlpool
thank you for joining us for today's
lesson we'll see you next time
[Music]