[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen welcome
everybody i am shane
today we're looking at part one of a
walk on the high line
new york city's highest park and the
vocabulary words are
transport transport the company is
responsible for the transport of
building materials
from one place to another goods good
the goods in this store are extremely
expensive oh no abandoned
abandoned because of the typhoon many
people were forced
to abandon their homes exhibit exhibit
the museum has dozens of new exhibits
dense dense the treasure hunters cut
their way through the dense jungle
so we're talking about new york new york
a walk on the
high line yeah so i think a long long
time ago in the 1900s
new york it used to be like a really
dangerous place right in the early 1900s
right
that's right when they had to transport
like goods like
food and stuff through the city there
were a lot of accidents because there
were like carriages there's no cars yet
right
carriages and people and i guess there
were a lot of accidents so they needed
to think of a way
to get a train in through the city and
can
transport these goods safely that's
right so i think it was in the 1930s
that's when they built the high line
which is the elevated
railway so it's above everybody so it
doesn't
cause any problems so i think that
really helped you know new york with
their accidents
and um but as trucks became more popular
i think people started
abandoning the high line right so
basically they start figuring out other
ways of getting
goods through the city and of course
everything expanded and
modernized so they stopped using that
train line
so what do they use it for now but what
a pity though so i think you know back
in 2009 and new yorkers they're thinking
oh we gotta
turn into something else maybe a nice
park
nice park yeah that's a really
interesting idea
okay let's learn more about that and
we'll learn all about this park next
time all right enjoy enjoy
[Music]
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
the streets of new york city in the
early 1900s were a dirty and dangerous
place
steam-powered trains delivered food
alongside pedestrians and carriages
leading to many deadly accidents by the
1930s it was clear that something new
had to be done
enter the high line this elevated
railway solved a major problem for the
city
but over time it has changed to serve
the city in a much different way
hello everyone today's lesson is called
a walk on the high line
new york city's highest
park part one
hello everyone my name is jeff and my
name is mike
high park well yeah absolutely this
is not the kind of adjective we
often see when talking about a park we
might say the biggest park or the
greenest park or the oldest park or
something like
the most beautiful or the most beautiful
park but parks are generally made of
grass and trees
and gardens and lakes you know a good
park has
those things and these are things that
we find on the ground
grass trees gardens we don't find them
up in the air which is where we would
find something
we describe as being high so this is a
park
that is above the ground it is up in the
air it is over your head
this is kind of an unusual park i would
say
anyways it's located in new york city a
city with great parks
with great parks like central park but
we won't be talking about that
today anyways let's talk about new york
city a little bit
the streets of new york city
in the early 1900s were a
dirty and dangerous place
oh boy were they ever get this
steam powered trains
delivered food alongside
pedestrians and carriages
leading to many deadly
accident so we're not talking
oh here's a nice street and a curbing
and some sidewalks oh people were
walking and people were driving in cars
and they were separated
oh everybody was safe and nobody was
dying no no no we had
people in trains and carriages and there
were
no markings on the roads it was a mess
a deadly mess that's right deadly and
dirty because of course alongside those
steam-powered trains with their
smoke and steam you'd have horses and
carriages with all the horse poop on the
ground
it was not the place you wanted to be
walking around
in your brand new shoes that's for sure
so
by the 1930s we read it was clear
that something new had to be done so
cars came in but the
trains were still there the roads were
not well organized
accidents happened people got hurt and
killed
so by the 1930s a few years later it was
clear that something new had to be done
this is something that everyone looked
around and said this is
crazy we have to do something to fix
these deadly dirty streets in new york
so what did they decide to do what did
they
decide to do that's what we're gonna
find out
next let's go ahead and move on
enter the high line
the high line high
line yes this elevated
railway solved a major problem for the
city
but over time it has changed
to serve the city in a much different
way so
before you had the train at the same
level as pedestrian on the ground
on the ground man big mistake
oh people were dying left and right
that's that's where the high line comes
in you take that train there
and you elevate it oh this is like you
can make it higher like the brown line
of the mrt
in taipei that goes down fushing road
right it's a train that runs above the
city left the street level
so the train stays out of people's way
that's why we call it
an elevated railway that is something
that is
higher well we'll find out more about
the high line and its
new form its new life in the city of new
york
after this break
up
um
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
cutting through new york's downtown area
the high line allowed for the transport
of goods to where they were needed
as trucks became more popular for making
deliveries
the high line was slowly abandoned
nature took its course
and while some sections of track were
torn down others gradually became home
to a wide variety of plants and animals
by 2009 new yorkers had realized the
value of this unique area
and the highline's new life as a public
park began
[Music]
okay cutting through new york's downtown
area
the high line allowed for the transport
of goods
to where they were needed so the trains
weren't running along the ground there
knocking pedestrians to the left and
right and killing people and stuff like
that
no no no this was now an elevated
train and it was high
off the ground it was now a high
line yes this elevation allowed for the
transport or movement
of goods to where they were needed and
here yes we do have the word
transport it's a noun transport is
movement you might have heard the word
transfer trade
transfer transportation excuse me
transportation is the movement of
one thing or some things i should say
from one
place to another transport is just
movement for example the company is
responsible for the
transport of building materials from one
place
to another they move building materials
from one place to another and here we're
talking about
the transport or the transportation of
goods that's right goods are things that
are sold
basically of course things that are made
in a factory
from pens and pencils to shoes
televisions and cars these are goods
they make them in the factory and then
they sell them in stores of all sorts of
types
but also we might talk about things that
come out of a farm
apples or grain or rice or things like
that
those could be goods as well so it could
be things that you find in your local
store
or things that big companies will buy in
large amounts like some company buys
millions of potatoes to make french
fries out of or something like that but
these are just things that are
sold in small sizes and large sizes
all over the place for example the goods
in this store
are extremely expensive maybe it's a
jewelry store
selling goods made of gold and silver
and stuff like that
all right let's get back to our our look
at the high line so
originally of course it was for the
transport of goods it says as
trucks became more popular for making
deliveries
the high line was slowly abandoned ah so
as
cars developed and small cars became
bigger trucks trucks became more useful
than trains they
can take large amounts in the big truck
but they can take it down
streets they can bring it right to your
door so moving things in
huge amounts like on a train was not so
useful
so this big train line through the city
was slowly
abandoned usually when you use this word
abandon you're saying
that you're going to leave something
somewhere and you're not going to come
back
and get it but here the idea is if
something
is abandoned it's no longer used or it's
being used
less and less and less for example
because of the typhoon many people were
forced
to abandon their homes they had to
leave their homes and they probably
weren't going to go back or they
wouldn't be able to go back now
nature it says took its course and
while some sections of track were torn
down
others gradually became home to a wide
variety of
plants and animals
starting to sound like the high line
is becoming a park well
slowly yes absolutely when nature takes
its course
that means nature does what it naturally
does if you abandon a home
after a year or two you'll find plants
growing in the corners and within five
years you might have birds
living inside the house because there
are no people there this is kind of
what happened with the high line plants
bushes flowers
birds move in squirrels are turning it
into their little home
it became a park it became kind of a
park nature
took it over again or came back and so
it says by 2009
so 40 50 67 years after the high line
was
slowly abandoned or just kind of left
alone by 2009 new yorkers had
realized the value of this unique area
what a cool place it's like a park
over our heads and the highline's new
life as a par public park
began i guess they could have torn it
down and turned it back into a road
there but
that costs a lot of money and you know
they don't need another road in new york
city but
a new park an interesting park a park
that has already begun
thanks to mother nature hmm there's an
interesting idea
there you go let's turn it let's turn it
into a public park
leave the high line alone all right
folks with that
it's time for us to take a break but
don't go away
we'll be back after this
channel
i think you should just relax and let
nature
take its course
they tore down the old house and built a
new one
australia is home to some of the most
dangerous animals in the world
a variety of
show there are a large variety of
vegetarian options
on the menu
how cool
a walk on the high line new york city's
highest park
currently the high line is almost a mile
and a half long
and features art exhibits food and gift
stands
performances and dense gardens that are
still growing
visitors can take in its natural beauty
while being surrounded by city sites and
views of the hudson river
[Music]
okay the high line there in new york
city
it's now a public park we've got a
section there they didn't tear it down
and now it is home to plants and animals
it's quite
the sight to see currently the high line
is
almost a mile and a half long
and features art exhibits
food and gift stands performances
and dense gardens that are
still growing yeah covet 19 didn't stop
those
gardens from go from growing there you
go as you walk along the high line
this park above the streets of new york
you'll see art
exhibits food and gift stands
performances lots of good stuff what is
an exhibit
an exhibit is basically a show that is
being put on for people to
see we're not talking about a
performance like dancers or
musicians we're talking about art
probably paintings sculptures
things like that especially if it's
there temporarily for just
a short time at the local museum they
might have an exhibit of picasso
paintings
there for a couple of months and anyone
who wants to see something cool and
interesting will go to the exhibit for
example the museum has
dozens of new exhibits picasso paintings
for example
for example anyways we also have this
word
dense to talk about let's say you have
an amount of something
okay if you were to somehow compress
that amount of something into a smaller
space
you would say that you now have a denser
material okay let's say you have
something that's light and fluffy
that's not dense something that is heavy
and small at the same time that would be
very dense so material like a metal like
gold let's say would be very dense
whereas
oh a pillow let's say you rest your head
on that's nice and soft
i wouldn't call that dense at all
for example the treasure hunters cut
their way
through the dense jungle there were
leaves and vines everywhere oh it's very
hard to
cut through they were just oh gosh just
plants everywhere was so dense in that
jungle there anyways visitors there if
you go to the high line
can take in its natural beauty while
being
surrounded by city sites and views
of the hudson river hmm on one of the
rivers that goes around the island of
manhattan so there you go the natural
beauty of the high line
stretches in front of you and off to one
side you can maybe
look out through the buildings or right
there you'll see the beautiful hudson
river
in the middle of new york city one of
the biggest cities
in the world the high line sounds like a
great place to visit
and we're glad to get the chance to
check it out with you guys but that's it
for today
so we'll see you all very very soon
until then
bye bye
um
[Music]
aloha let me tell you a bit
about hula it's an important custom in
hawaii
it used to be a dance for social events
people performed it for enjoyment too
the songs or chants that go with hula
tell stories of native island people's
history
if i had to describe hula in one word
i would say that it's smooth
both the body movements and the chance
flow like water
many people don't realize that hula is
made up
of only six traditional moves
female hula dancers used to wear short
skirts
men wore clothes that covered only their
middle
when westerners arrived in hawaii in the
early 19th century
they wanted hula dancers to cover their
bodies
so both men and women hula dancers
began wearing longer skirts hula
is protected by the hawaiian goddess
laka
people believe lakka causes the dancers
movements
as they dance now would you like to
learn
how to hula here is more
information instrument
jason can play many instruments
island the okinawa islands are in
southwestern japan
volcano mount fuji is the most famous
volcano
in japan waste
henry wears a black belt around his
waist every day
hip mrs smith fell
and broke her hip last week
ankle remember to stretch your ankles
before running
bracelet mandy's husband gave her a
beautiful bracelet
necklace hannah is wearing an expensive
necklace
chief that strong man is the chief
of this tribe dancer
all the dancers on the street are
wearing traditional costumes
wasn't that a super interesting lesson
i know i thought so we'll see you again
next time