[Music]
so
hi everyone this is karen hey everybody
i'm shane today we're looking at part
one
of surprising geography facts and the
vocabulary words are
recall recall from what i recall
colleen's dad
is a doctor rainfall rainfall
the area has an average rainfall of
around 30 centimeters per year
yearly yearly the town's summer festival
is held
once yearly primarily primarily
engine trouble was primarily responsible
for the plane crash
vast vest the library has a vast
selection of books to choose from so
we're talking about some
surprising geography facts yeah i think
this is kind of like
trivia right you're kind of learning
some interesting facts that maybe are
not that
useful in everyday life but they are
interesting and then they are about a
world so i think it's worth knowing
right and some are quite surprising so
the first one to
talk about is antarctica being
a desert and it is
it is the largest desert right yes not
only that's
the largest one but that seems really
strange because
when you think of a desert you don't
think of a place that's made of water
but actually the definition of a desert
it's
actually an area that receives less than
250 millimeters of rainfall
annually so yeah and they only have like
i think around 170 millimeters
of rainfall per year wow so
yeah it's in fact a desert i know
antarctica and then over in russia
they have 11 different time zones in one
country
because it is so big right
so that actually makes sense but it's
quite surprising you can call somebody
in russia at one point and then maybe
it's like the next day on the other part
of russia
usually think it should be the same time
zone in the same country
but even in canada is different time
zones too in america but we only have
three how many do you have i don't
remember i have to check
it's not 11. it's not 11. definitely
okay let's learn some more interesting
and surprising geography geography learn
geography facts
enjoy
surprising geography facts most of us
can recall some basic geography
knowledge
the highest mountain the deepest ocean
the biggest continent
etc but for some unexpected facts about
our planet
you'll have to read on
today's lesson is called surprising
geography facts part one
hello everyone my name is jeff and
i'm mike and the world is a fascinating
place lots of interesting places lots of
interesting facts
so we're going to be looking at some
surprising
facts about the world or geography facts
in our two days of
articles so what do you say let's get
going let's get going now most of us
can recall some basic
geography knowledge like
the highest mountain mount everest the
deepest ocean
the pacific ocean the biggest continent
asia etc okay most of us can we call
these things yeah sure i remember those
from books i read as a kid from
geography class at school
when you recall something you remember
that thing that's
basically all it means you have that
information in your
mental hard drive and you have the
ability to
pull it out so you can recall your your
best friend's name
in kindergarten or the name of your
first pet or your your
dad's birthday or something like that
you can remember those things it's
information
that's there in your mind and you know
it's easy to pull it up when you need it
from what i recall
colleen's dad is a doctor
i remember meeting him one day and his
name's dr smith and he was telling us
about
working at the hospital it was five
years ago but yeah i recall that
i remember that i'm not bad anyways but
for
some unexpected facts about our planet
you'll have to read on
after a break we'll see you after the
break
hello
take out
geography facts antarctica is actually
the world's largest desert
you might think of sand and camels when
you hear the word desert
but a desert is officially defined as an
area that receives
under 250 millimeters of rainfall yearly
although antarctica is a continent
composed primarily of water
this water is locked in ice so with its
annual rainfall
at around only 170 millimeters
antarctica
easily falls within the definition of a
desert
okay fun geography facts and surprising
and surprising surprises first of all
the biggest desert in the world is in
africa it's called the sahara desert
right
yeah wrong antarctica
is actually the world's largest
desert yes you don't have to
have you don't have to have sand and
heat
okay and dryness to be
a desert the sahara desert is sandy and
dry and hot
and it's a really big desert but
antarctica
is also a desert and it's bigger than
the sahara
interesting but when you go to the zoo
they won't put the penguins with the
camels
because they're both desert animals that
would be weird that would not that would
not work out but it's true we don't look
at
we don't call it a desert because of all
the sand and all the hot sun
we call it a desert why because there's
no rain
well you might think of sand and camels
when you hear the word
desert most people do but a desert is
officially defined
as an area that receives under 250
millimeters of
rainfall yearly it's not about the
temperature it's not about the hot sun
and the hot sand
it's about rainfall and there's less
rainfall
in antarctica the south pole every year
than there is in the sahara what about
all the snow
and the ice and the blizzards and huh
it's been there forever it just never
goes away it's so cold
that's amazing anyways when we're
talking about rainfall we're talking
about
the amount of rain that falls in a
certain
area over some period of time okay
when i was growing up we actually had a
gauge outside of our house
okay and when it rained okay that would
fill up and it would tell us
how much it had rained during that
particular storm
if there was a lot of rain maybe one or
two
inches of rain fell over that entire
area that would that would have been a
lot of rainfall a lot of water
fell from the sky for example the area
has an average rainfall of around
30 centimeters per year oh okay
now this of course is a word we wouldn't
use in our daily lives when talking
about the weather
but on a weather report in a science
book
then they would use it but we wouldn't
say take your umbrella there will be a
lot of rainfall today
you wouldn't use it in that sort of
normal daily way
all right we also had this adverb yearly
when we talk about something that is
yearly or happens yearly or
occurs yearly we means it happens each
year
or in a year all right so we're just
talking about a year as a period of time
we're using that to measure things so
we're not saying in a decade or in a
century and a hundred years or in a day
or a week
in a year yearly for example the town's
summer festival is held
once yearly so once a year they have a
festival
okay now although antarctica
is a continent composed primarily of
water
something we would not associate with
deserts usually
this water is locked in ice
there you go here we have the adverb
primarily
primarily means for the most part so
yes this is a continent that is mostly
water it's composed or made up of water
for the most part or mostly
but the water is in the form of ice or
is locked in ice
so it's not
really water in the sense that
we think of water rainfall it's in
solid form it's not in the form of rain
it's composed primarily of water in ice
form and again primarily means mostly or
for the most part for example engine
trouble
was primarily responsible for the plane
crash
yeah the engine broke down and the plane
fell out of the sky
okay the pilots might have made a few
mistakes but they didn't have a lot of
time to fix things so if the engines
hadn't failed there wouldn't have been a
problem so let's look
at antarctica's rainfall remember less
than
250 millimeters yearly makes you
a desert so with its antarctica's
annual rainfall at around only 100
millimeters a little more than half that
number
antarctica easily falls within the
definition
of a desert so i guess it would be safe
to guess that
the sahara desert there in northern
africa might get 180 or
200 millimeters of rain more than
antarctica
there you go fascinating fun fact number
one
down but hey there are more to come
after a break
desert
tina thinks of her grandmother every
time she hears the song
tina mate
thinks of the job as the opportunity of
a lifetime
mat
henry tried to think of a way to solve
dylan never thinks of anyone but himself
surprising geography facts russia covers
11 time zones
this is because of how vast the world's
largest country is
also notable is that russia is the only
country that borders both finland
in northern europe and north korea in
east asia
russia also controls an island called
big diomede
it sits less than four kilometers from
its sister island
little diomede owned by the united
states
although these two islands are
geographically close they sit on either
side of the international date line
so they have a 21-hour time difference
okay geography fun fact
number two and this is going to be
surprising now we all know that russia
is
big real big it's a big country biggest
country in the world
it's by far the biggest country in the
world but get this
russia covers
11 time zones
wow 11. but that's like half the world
that's like half the world 24 time zones
24 hours a day in the united states
there's like three or four
time zones at most and that's not
including
alaska throw that out of there right
russia
11 time zones wow canada's the second
biggest country i think it's like
six and a half time zones or something
like that so russia
is really big and it's really big in an
east-west
way as we can see because it stretches
basically around
half the world half the world would be
12 time zones like from here to new york
city
that's 12 time zones so russia's almost
the same size stretching around the top
of the world
it's very big this is because of of
course
how vast the world's largest country
is yeah there are many words many
adjectives you can use to describe
russia
and vast is certainly a very good one
because vast just means
huge really really really big
especially in kind of a geography kind
of way
the way something just covers a huge
area of land
as you stand on a mountain top and look
out over a
jungle or a forest and you it goes until
you can't even
see anymore that is a vast forest so
every time i'm in tokyo if you go up to
the top of a tall building
especially at night you just see lights
until you can't see any further because
tokyo is a
vast city it's really huge it covers a
massive area of only one time zone
though only one time zone tokyo that's a
very good point well
yeah probably for example the library
has a
vast selection of books to choose from
anyways also notable is that russia
is the only country that borders both
finland in northern europe and
north korea in east asia
sure it's fast it's vast it's it that it
definitely is that
that's right and russia and time zones
that's right and russia not only covers
most of the continent of
asia it also has a few islands out there
in the pacific ocean or maybe the bering
sea
it says russia also controls an
island called big diomede it
that island big diomede sits less than
four
kilometers from its sister island little
diomede
owned by the united states so this is up
in that northern part of the pacific
near
alaska and you know siberia or
wherever that is in in russia that very
far eastern part of russia
and actually they control two islands
that are very close to each other which
isn't a surprise because
they almost touch up there in the north
but here's the really interesting part
here's the really interesting point
although these two islands are
geographically close four kilometers
they
sit on either side of the international
date line so they have a 21
hour time difference if it's wednesday
on little diomede it's
tuesday on big diomede or the other way
around because of the
international date line wow about that
that's cool
all right folks today's lesson is now in
the books but hey we're going to come
back next time with some more
fun facts on geography
quote
welcome to yellowstone national park
i will be your guide you may not realize
it
but yellowstone is huge
it covers almost 9 000 square kilometers
of land
before it became a national park few
people
knew about this part of america
officials went there to find out more
and they brought an artist with them the
artist made paintings of the area
when the u.s government saw the
paintings they were impressed by the
area's beauty
in 1872 president ulysses
s grant officially made yellowstone the
world's
first national park at first
yellowstone was also called wonderland
this name came from the popular book
alice's
adventures in wonderland still
wonderland didn't receive many visitors
because it was very far out west
a year after it opened the northern
pacific railway was completed
as a result more people began visiting
the park
now millions of visitors come to
yellowstone every year
here is more information
volcano it's not safe to live near
an active volcano
erupt the volcano near rome
erupted yesterday
reptile crocodiles are reptiles
hot spring tendy went to a hot spring
with her family
last weekend waterfall
my friends and i are going swimming
under a waterfall tomorrow
hunt henry's father taught him to hunt
when he was a teenager
auction this beautiful house went to
auction recently
lodge the lodge is famous for its
quiet and peaceful surroundings
campfire a campfire can keep us warm
while we are camping
feed cindy loves her pony and
feeds it every morning
thanks for joining us today i hope you
learned a lot
we'll catch you later
[Music]