[Music]
hi everyone this is karen everybody i'm
shame are you playing game yeah okay
today we're looking at part two of the
life of a pro gamer and the vocabulary
words are prevent prevent washing your
hands often can prevent the spread of
many diseases physical physical
although joe suffered no physical harm
in the accident the mental effects will
last a long time
frequent frequent periods of extreme
heat have become more frequent in recent
years retired retired alice wants to
move to the countryside after she
retires mmm-hmm advertising advertising
the company has increased its spending
on advertising over the past few months
well we're still talking about the
interesting life not a pro-gamer and we
don't know too much about right and we
learned that actually it takes a lot of
practice and i think even if you're not
a pro gamer and you spend a lot of time
using your hand and sitting in a chair
you it's easy to get a sore back or sore
hands and fingers and that is why these
pro gamers they would have to take these
breaks where there was stand up and do
some stretches and do some exercise
that's almost like being an athlete
before you perform or before you do some
type of sports you need to stretch your
muscles to make sure you don't hurt your
self during good position right you're
good okay and also your eyes will get
really really tired from staring at the
screen all the time unnoticed even using
my smartphone
yes my hands will start to get tired
from holding the phone and typhoons and
just keep you know looking at my phone
swiping my phone so i can imagine being
on a playing a video game for 15 hours a
day that's why these short breaks are so
important to these pro gamers and the
lifespan of their career is actually not
that long by the time people are
graduating college you know 22 23 this
game
are already retiring from their pro
career so what would they do afterwards
make youtube videos there's a lot of
videos where people like to see a
walkthrough or a review of a video game
and they can make advertising money from
that type of thing yeah right well maybe
do some coach coaching you write
interesting so if you're really
interested you have to be serious it's
not all fun and games and you have to be
very dedicated that's right okay right
for more about pro gamers the life of a
pro gamer
even though pro gamers spend most of
their time sitting down they still need
training to prevent physical injuries
they have to stretch between matches to
prevent injury to their wrists arms or
shoulders they also need to take
frequent breaks from looking at screens
to prevent eye strain additionally while
gamers are known for all-night sessions
it's important for them to get enough
sleep maintaining a healthy schedule
makes a gamer more disciplined which
translates into better performance in
the game as well
welcome everyone today's lesson is
called the life of a pro gamer part 2
hello everyone my name is Jeff and I'm
Mike yeah we're learning what it would
be like to be a professional video or
computer game player yeah you've seen
these people on TV you might have
watched a show about them or maybe you
enjoy watching them play online on
Twitch or something like that but what's
it really like well yesterday we learned
that it's actually really hard you might
be playing video games 50 60 70 hours a
day 15 hours uh sorry a week 15 hours a
day little time for a personal life or
even sleeping and things like that but
big prizes big salaries million-dollar
cash prizes if you win tournaments the
attraction is obvious and you're doing
something you love too but when you're
doing this you're also sitting down a
lot of times is true and they do say
that sitting down okay is extremely bad
for you okay so if you're a pro gamer
you're gonna be spending a lot of your
time sitting down so you're gonna have
to do something to counteract the
effects of sitting down all the time
yeah even though pro gamers spend most
of their time sitting down they still
lead a training I should say to prevent
physical injuries so the training will
be physical and the whole idea is that
they don't hurt their bodies that they
don't get physical injuries yeah now of
course all athletes do a lot to prevent
injuries it will definitely not be good
for the athlete because if you prevent
something this verb means you stop
something from happening by taking
action before it happens you make sure
it doesn't happen by being smart and
preparing yourself by doing something in
advance alright so a lot of people
around the wintertime might wear masks
to prevent themselves from catching a
cold or passing on a cold if they have
one another way to prevent sickness is
to wash your hands okay if you want to
prevent yourself from falling asleep
moon maybe drink a cup of coffee or
something to help your self wake up a
little bit we wear helmets when we ride
motorcycles and seatbelts and cars
to prevent being badly hurt should if
there is an accident or should there be
an accident so all of these things are
done to prevent something usually
something bad you wouldn't really want
to prevent someone from giving you a
birthday present because that's a good
thing yeah but you wouldn't want to
prevent someone from kicking you by
moving away from them because that's a
bad thing for exemple washing your hands
often can prevent the spread of many
diseases
yeah that's why doctors tell us to do it
birthday presents good kicks bad day
kicks bad got it I don't I don't want
anyone to hurt me with happy birthday
I don't want anyone to kick me because
that might hurt my body it might injure
me physically physically is the adverb
physical is the adjective okay yet
through physical training to prevent
physical injuries ie you have to
exercise your body so as to not hurt
your body yes the adjective physical
means of the body or relating to the
body and not the mind okay the word for
the mind would be mental the word for
the body is physical for example
although Joe suffered no physical harm
in the accident the mental effects will
last a long time so he survived but he
might just have experienced some trauma
so in his mind he might be hurt but his
body is fine anyways as far as these
pro-gamers are concerned they have to
stretch between matches to prevent
injury to their wrists arms or shoulders
they have to stretch stretch stretch all
the time so that they don't get hurt
playing a video game I know it sounds
funny but it can happen but if you've
ever sat at a desk for 15 hours yeah you
will notice your shoulders and other
parts your neck maybe will start to hurt
and of course their eyes because that's
what's doing a lot of the hard work
their eyes getting all that information
from the screen they also need to take
frequent breaks from looking at screens
to prevent eye strain to prevent
injuring their eyes by using the
for too long things like that that orals
outs and glasses and maybe even other
more serious eye problems so frequent
breaks are the key to that what is
frequent this adjective means something
that happens quite often that happens
quite regularly it's not once every
month it's not once every year it's
maybe once a day twice a day or three
times a day or something like that if
you drink a lot of water you'll take
frequent trips to the bathroom because
you have to he've had a lot to drink all
right so it's something that happens a
lot if you're waiting for a bus well if
it's early in the morning you hope
there's a frequent bus you hope that bus
comes along every five minutes and not
every 25 minutes that would not be
frequent for example periods of extreme
heat have become more frequent in recent
years they happen more and more
in recent years and with less time
between them a lot more of them more
often than before
yeah interesting anyways additionally
while gamers are known for all-night
sessions they play all night long
sometimes it's important for them to get
enough sleep you have to sleep yeah
maintaining a healthy schedule makes a
gamer more disciplined which translates
into better performance in the game as
well so oh I need to practice all put in
an all-night session well that might
work for a while but after a while not
having sleep that's bad for you so go
ahead be more disciplined get that sleep
and you will perform better in the game
as a result alright folks with that it's
time for us to take a break but don't go
away we'll be back after this hello
honey
de hecho en toda tree agency 2008 song
dosage endian she can do research on
current and do decision making canal cha
cha cha cha cha cha go toyou kana
hanazawa taboos gentle soldier hysteria
shouldnít la pimienta Shanghai by P
conjugates show so to ham sauce and
boolong in sham sahaja yoga counter act
take a dong COK Pilate shouting honking
horn citizenship in zou zou ante
or a CT counteract how they can transit
prevent prevent dodging suture we found
physical physical transition T the road
Heda had a food situation ly mentioned
physically physically shanti shanti nan
Xiang nan dans le dirty - Oh Jo Jo Jo
Mayo showed up erosion tensions a singie
in Shanghai which hunch I need oxygen to
Shailaja a young girl trauma tickets tra
um a trauma attribution Cindy qianxiang
ha no mocha venti dirty - Oh geodon you
want ambitious a possession light oceans
and own opinion show wanna show P was a
gym bang show Xiang Yu Xiao Chun Tong
shows she people can annul opinions in
front home no she went away
Oh Shi Tong Xiao kou Zi do to you and
Elijah who the Chum - she means show me
all day yo Chang Hungarian Empire John
Hammond Cunha children say Yoshi
jean-pierre single ha ha Michelle I
can't dance frequent
frequent has a sensation Jin Chun ping
Fonda number Chun dances I strain I
strength has Eng San Tong Xiao mo yung
me go to in simplest on phantom a
phantom P large okay young I stream via
that higher session session hibachi
French again challenge home Shimoga hold
on the eat 2010 joking session Jericho
enjoy the life of a pro gamer most pro
gamers are young and they often retire
from the sport around the same time
other people their age are graduating
from college so what can a professional
gamer expect to do for a living once
it's game over for them many become
professional streamers using their fame
to make money from advertising
others become coaches for younger
players or get involved with game
development
pro-gamers most pro gamers are
young and they often retire from the
sport around the same time other people
their age are graduating from college so
there you go usually people who
graduated around 22 years of age this is
when most pro gamers retire how about
that by the way if you retire you leave
a career or a job or the workforce when
you're old or when you've made enough
money that you don't need to work
anymore and for pro gamers 22 apparently
is an old age so they retire now for
tennis players people think oh once you
reach the age of 35 that's all but for
the rest of us usually people retire
when they reach the age of 65 or 70 that
would be old enough that you can leave
the workplace for example Alice wants to
move to the countryside after she
retires yeah I'm done working I want to
move the countryside and take it easy
alright so there you go a very short
career 20 to 23 or certainly your early
20s your hands start to slow down your
eyes and your reaction time starts to
slow down like happens to almost every
athlete at some point in their career so
what can a professional gamer expect to
do for a living
once it's game over for them by here by
game over we mean it's time for them to
retire the life of a professional gamer
is no longer available so what do you do
you're you're quite young you're a video
game expert but you can't compete with
the really young kids well many become
professional streamers using their fame
to make money from advertising this is
that twitch thing we talked about which
a lot of you might know you can go on
there play games have people watch you
chat with you if you're really good
they'll learn from you and learn your
secrets and tips and also you can make
money from advertising in this way
basically make yourself a famous gamer
who people want to see play games and
stuff like that there's money to be made
there what is advertising advertising is
basically companies telling you about
their products because they hope that
the products will attract you and you
will buy them it can be a poster on a
side of a bus a sign by the road and ad
on the television or radio something
that pops up after your last YouTube
video to tell you about some new thing
basically that's what it is because
companies want your attention because
they want your money for example the
company has increased its spending on
advertising over the past few months
that's why you see a lot of their ads we
would say around town or on the Internet
right so some players do that and others
become coaches for younger players hey
or get involved with game development so
they can help players become pro gamers
and they can help game makers make
better games as well alright folks with
that it's time for us to you take a
break but don't go away
when we come back we'll be wrapping up
our article on pro gaming tofurna to do
and adoha inching down Tony and see
their entire IP the show how much Apple
daughter song teens England only 20 2008
pigeon dollars sure sir essential
phonemic a shot young people shall not
cease with ammunition show cuz I was
young in situatio it hides all about
venture - charlie
say nyah ha not real when I am played
George from we don't run yet reporter
young Hanuman sheets Hong Kong called me
like truncheon
now Yoda not show any intentions of the
child in Rajasthan yoshikawa Honda how
when jungle streamer streamer has urgent
report Oh naturally how they dance
retire retire
tapia sheet ratio 2014 home incheon jang
hijae from something the majority she
dances young cow workforce workforce
passage allowed only law dong jung-ho
citizenship enzo wo RK f o RC e
workforce sidebands advertising
advertising happy ashok Wonka Wonka
Asian means not sure important had a
Shangguan
and advertise advertised don't see a way
some light so clog options right now
that's the way Josh I am ent enjoy tada
means advertisement advertisement dad
Wonka ha Chang Shan Shan Shan where ad
means to add gesso Falco and John the
life of a pro gamer professional video
game playing might sound like a dream
job at first but due to the punishing
practice schedule and the short shelf
life of a career in gaming it isn't all
fun and games in fact becoming a pro
gamer takes hard work and perseverance
two qualities that will help you find
success no matter what career path you
choose ok let's start to wrap things up
professional video game plane pro gaming
might sound like a dream job at first at
the beginning but once you delve into
the subject a little bit more you
realize that hmm is this really a dream
job or is it a little bit tougher than
that yeah absolutely playing games for
money you might sound like with eating
french fries for money that's great I
love french fries I'll do that yeah
think about it this is gonna be your
whole life so it says but so it might
sound like a dream job but due to the
punishing practice schedule and the
short shelf life of a career in gaming
it isn't all fun and games you'll have
to work really hard and your whole
career could be over before you're even
married by the early 20s so think about
it pretty carefully because it is a lot
harder than you would imagine
yep in fact becoming a pro gamer takes
hard work and perseverance two qualities
that will help you find success no
matter what career path you choose a
good point that being said you also have
to be young for the most part you don't
have to be young for other jobs and pro
gaming youth is extremely important
interesting alright folks that's
it for our article but we're not quite
done we still have the one question to
ask and then answer Mike after reading
this article do you think that being a
pro gamer sounds like a good career
choice for you why or why not
well I've watched a few shows about the
life of a pro gamer in the pro gaming
world and after watching those and
reading this I don't think I would want
to be a pro gamer because and this is
very simple I can't think of a game that
I would want to play for 60 hours a week
there's lots of games I love and I might
play it for 60 hours for one week but
then I get bored of it you know what I
mean I just wanna land cover your entire
life no not all the time every day all
day long I just can't think of a game
that I would want to play and no pong or
Tetris yeah no probably definitely not
those ones and I don't think if you you
you couldn't really just switch games
and be good at anyone so you'd have to
focus I just can't think of that great
game that I'd love to play forever me
neither
anyways folks with that our lesson on
pro gaming is now on the books and it's
time for us to say bye bye
hello Giuliana Kawashima - champion show
diggity Emma saying how things actually
among Hong Kong's Oh cousin Annie are
called without hunting so her lair in
the region empire he'll hunt when the
junior non-official change without a
doubt took account of people to
challenge a house or in your knee action
when training on tapestry coolant how
you children easy children show me then
chances it children went to that Tony no
no see no Jimmy open bar waiting on
Cueto one how come on Joe a
Capuchin dances also perseverance
perseverance Joe Pesci lee jin-young
Papa the manly watch out for that CIT da
Liang from cooler Yoshinori Muto yeah
pong pong catches on so don't throw joy
oh has a it don't instant you
will see the Shih Tzu
hiyo Tetris Tetris does it allows the
fun quiet hello me a chance - Jonesy
Punjab is okay I'm Michelle
[Music]
sahaja honey
hyecho condo alpha diamond see now just
how alpha junket your Sangha digger
should spend you take the young puppy
job theater shelf-life this anger should
fun and games
Oh miss Eliza spend and take the young
Bobby job spent on tik tok ABA Hafiz
sanction professor Jankovic see me coach
in Hanoi young FOP Otomo Oh Mason like I
can spend catch a piace
quaff a chance of SEO search engine for
the future chance of fortunately for
routinely challenging attrition should
somebody
joshan span cha cha cha ching ching
ching ching me Phaeton's ing producer
somebody spent cha cha cha ching ching
ching ching latecha on yeah means
baroque Tim spent $100 on watery tickets
every week Tim mega since he qualified
and I might let hope Henry spent 3 hours
washing his car yesterday
Henry toda Hollis anguish after she had
to pencil teniendo own choice
Angela see how they can take pay young
right so half a Austria chances
Havasu Gianotti meat and not chunky no
chasing something take cash and sitting
watching the weather should it take to
Jane Watson it's a couple things
Xiang Yu Yu Hakusho good work takes time
how the talking just really end up that
kind of a trip it takes a lot of time
and effort to master a foreign language
now ting Tong hua Guo Yan Cheu half a
dose sitting dancing me how did Elijah
see shelf life
shelf life such a champion Sansa shall
show the city leadership all transition
yo shout she said hey I can ypu show
whining what is a chunk understood yeah
sound celebrity marriages tend to
have a short shelf life mainland the
Wang Wang Wang wait saputo notation
halal means inhomogeneity 20 suet
caboose angry
since sequence a whole a she fun and
games fun and games Tasha 2-shot
singsong voice I love the ho don't be a
fool ding my Joshua fujiyoshi on show
potential no Towanda sonship VR
technology is more than just fun and
games we are SHINee Cinco de puta Hawaii
shamash okay Beyonce cha cha cha RA cha
cha cha cha cha hwa-jung halite oh don't
touch against yeah was it easier for me
and Kim says oh why cause of Shushan in
today crossover what Suzanne young we
are wondering about the phone call
centers outside and CEO taboo to talk
about Halloween sounds gentlemen to me
Santa jingle I'm Holly and Shane Jacoby
yeah we're small anyway it would just be
a oh that's a good name would you be
I'll put it under when you certainty and
the truth yeah so I sit alone in Al Gore
what are the comers
sorry jintan do what I say
[Music]
do you want to hang out tonight I know
of a great new restaurant I'm sorry but
I already have a date tonight so how was
your date
that's great do you want to hang out
tonight
mmm hang out hang my laundry MA
was it but certainly I don't see okay so
hangout time and I see just me about
Suzie Wong Wong whoo - see ya bye et toi
density you putting on those messaging
on inside je te Tohu come on your case
or hanging out yeah okay what you want
to go chill tonight
okay so do you want to go to look at the
Joneses sake ja no Shafi
yeah hey cuz I can't race you boy hand
hedge in fact just chill it's chill just
so y'all relax it's just you didn't love
her the gun juice I mean it's all gonzo
I think uh Rafi found some of the Ganges
indicates you just see why me and
caffeic H Hill yeah okay or you could
just say do you want to do something
tonight
oh hey do you wanna talk about easy
boys so we're switching ass but we will
never translate the point is you won't
say do you want to go out
window-shopping dog Wan Jia Tommy so
just a window shopping because you're a
woman
wait Johnson's right downtown well just
so do you want to go out and do
something do you want to hang out die
now we're gonna go take a walk sure yeah
take a walk mah boi because everybody
needs in - I wouldn't huh
yeah but no one more it density no son
he was all just it what's in this she'll
take a walk let's go take a walk oh yeah
you're dumb I can take a walk is it I
got don't get in the single
the boy young witnesses you want to take
a look all right all right so if you
want to hang out with us and learn
English then come over
do you want to hang out tonight
do you want to hang out tonight do you
want to go chill tonight do you want to
go chill tonight do you want to do
something tonight do you want to do
something tonight
[Music]